<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ECD 4ECD (Electrical+Comms+Data) RSS Feed</title>
    <description>http://ecdonline.com.au&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    <ttl>5</ttl>    
    <link>http://ecdonline.com.au</link>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4ECD_3 Maintaining sparkie safety in a changing electrical landscape</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Maintaining sparkie safety in a changing electrical landscape" class="lazyload img-thumbnail img-right" data-original="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/78451/pool_and_spa_master/..jpg" title="Maintaining sparkie safety in a changing electrical landscape" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/78451/pool_and_spa_master/..jpg" style="display: block;"&gt;


&lt;p&gt;“Any electrician will know that they need to constantly be aware of common problems that may hinder their safety, such as water, confined spaces and damaged cables,” said Lucy Finlay, Standardisation and Regulation Manager, Pacific at Clipsal by Schneider Electric. “To ensure workplace safety, electricians need to go beyond this to not only protect themselves, but also those who may conduct work after them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, Finlay discusses the most important aspects of safety for electricians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Keep up with regulations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure they are aware of necessary safety regulations and industry standards, electricians must first make sure they are licensed to trade. Most importantly, they need to keep updated with the latest changes, no matter how busy they are on the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Australian Building Codes Board announced changes to the &lt;a href="https://ncc.abcb.gov.au/" target="_blank"&gt;National Construction Code&lt;/a&gt; (NCC) across volumes one to three, directly impacting electricians and builders. While some changes came into effect on 1 May 2023, all new regulations will be effective from 1 October 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These imminent updates to the NCC will also alter training requirements for electricians, as well as improving their safety on the job. Despite a significant amount of reskilling for sparkies, this also provides the opportunity to upgrade their businesses, increasing revenue in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Use certified products, not untested or uncertain suppliers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When installing products like DC isolators, it is important to use certified products. This is critical when it comes to jobs that require a return to site to provide regular maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A faulty or non-certified product can pose serious harm after installation. It’s therefore imperative that an electrician’s chosen wholesaler can supply the relevant documentation to mitigate any present or future risk. It is also essential to make sure all installation work has been done correctly, tested and documented in accordance with local requirements. Recent changes to AS/NZS 3000:2018 require a minimum of a Type A RCD for the protection of most final subcircuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Recognising the impact of smart homes when it comes to electrical safety&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home automation is revolutionising Australian homes, helping consumers create greener properties. Products like &lt;a href="https://www.clipsal.com/products/wiser-smart-home-solutions" target="_blank"&gt;Clipsal Wiser Smart Home&lt;/a&gt; provide electricians with scalable home automation products to offer to homeowners, which will ultimately help them meet all their sustainability needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many of these smart products are safer for electricians due to low voltage exposure, many green additions such as EV chargers require different measures when it comes to safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;EV uptake and the infrastructure supporting the EV revolution&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, consumers across the world and in Australia have continued to invest in EVs and the infrastructure needed to charge their vehicles. With new building codes across residential and commercial buildings seeing EVs being prioritised, electricians need to be aware of the changes to codes for their own safety and that of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, some buildings will need dedicated distribution boards for every 24 parking spaces. While newly constructed buildings don’t need to have EV chargers installed initially, infrastructure such as charging control systems will need to be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear that the need for increased safety awareness has never been higher due to the rise of green energy and smart products. New products, regulations and standards are constantly being released into the Australian market to ensure the safety of those in the electrical field, and it is essential that sparkies keep up to date to make sure they stay safe and prosper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on safety in the workplace, visit &lt;a href="https://www.clipsal.com/safety" target="_blank"&gt;clipsal.com/safety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/530516/web_image_article/Lucy-Finlay-headshot.jpg" style="display: block; height: 290px; margin: auto; width: 218px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Lucy Finlay, Standardisation and Regulation Manager, Pacific at Clipsal by Schneider Electric.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Top image credit: iStock.com/zstockphotos&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/article/maintaining-sparkie-safety-in-a-changing-electrical-landscape-609002700</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/article/maintaining-sparkie-safety-in-a-changing-electrical-landscape-609002700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4NOJA Power VISI-SWITCH down pole operator accessory</title>
      <description>
&lt;style&gt;.ecd_div{color:green !important}
#ecd_div p {padding-bottom: 5px !important}
&lt;/style&gt; 
	  &lt;div class=&quot;ecd_div&quot; id=&quot;ecd_div&quot;  style=&quot;text-align=none&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;LEFT Algin NOJA Power has released a down pole operator accessory for its solid dielectric insulated load break switch, known as the NOJA Power VISI-SWITCH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A down pole operator accessory is a mechanism that brings the actuation lever of the pole-top switchgear to a point further down the power pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows utilities to reduce the distance that operators need to reach with hot sticks to actuate the NOJA Power VISI-SWITCH into closed and open positions. It also allows utilities that elect to install the NOJA Power VISI-SWITCH above the overhead lines to bring the actuation point below the powerlines, removing the need for operators to fit a hot stick between the lines to reach the switchgear operating lever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The down pole operator accessory is available as a standalone accessory for existing NOJA Power VISI-SWITCH operators or as a supply option when purchasing a NOJA Power VISI-SWITCH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/product/noja-power-visi-switch-down-pole-operator-accessory-527109694</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/product/noja-power-visi-switch-down-pole-operator-accessory-527109694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4R U OK? encourages tradies to support each other</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   With R U OK?Day coming up on Thursday, 14 September, the suicide prevention charity has dedicated special resources to encourage meaningful conversations across tradies’ communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The R U OK? Tradies Tools to Talk resources are designed to help family, friends and workmates spot the signs that their friend or relative may be struggling. They provide practical tools and tips to start an R U OK? conversation and help a loved one or workmate find support if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Tradies Tools to Talk resources are free and available at: &lt;a href="https://www.ruok.org.au/tradies" target="_blank"&gt;ruok.org.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tradies face a range of challenges across their working lives — from job uncertainty to financial pressures, intense physical demands and workplace culture issues,” said R U OK? Community Ambassador Andre Sakr, 44, a construction project manager in Sydney who lives with anxiety and depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In an industry where stigma is high, these pressures can build up and impact mental and emotional wellbeing for tradies if they don’t feel they can talk to others about their struggles.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sakr emphasised how important it was to have an authentic conversation with someone close to you, who takes the time to take notice and really listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think being genuine is one of the most important things you can do when you’re talking to someone,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is a lot of stigma around talking about mental health, especially in the workforce, meaning a lot of people will not really feel comfortable coming forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is why it is so important to be genuine in your approach with that real desire to help. This allows people to open up more and it does knock down that wall.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R U OK? CEO Katherine Newton also emphasised the importance of genuineness, trust, and “let[ting] the person know you’re sticking around for whatever comes next”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We know the positive impact an R U OK? conversation can have when people know and trust each other. This usually means that trust has been built over time, they’re familiar with each other’s routines and behaviours, and they likely know what’s going on in each other’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This trust, along with consideration of the ‘where’ and ‘when’ a conversation will take place contributes to making an R U OK? conversation truly meaningful,” Newton said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For free resources to help you know when and how to ask ‘Are you OK?’ in your workplace, school and community, every day of the year, visit: &lt;a href="https://www.ruok.org.au/join-r-u-ok-day?utm_source=MED&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Day&amp;amp;utm_id=EV" target="_blank"&gt;ruok.org.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support at any time of day or night, Lifeline provides free and confidential crisis support. Call 13 11 14, text 0477 13 11 14 or chat online at: &lt;a href="https://www.lifeline.org.au/crisis-chat/" target="_blank"&gt;lifeline.org.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MATES in Construction offers free 24/7 support by telephone for Australian construction workers. Call 1300 642 111.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mensline offers free 24/7 support by telephone and online for men with emotional health and relationship concerns. Call 1300 78 99 78 or chat online at: &lt;a href="https://mensline.org.au/" target="_blank"&gt;mensline.org.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13YARN is a free 24/7 service offering crisis support for Aboriginal &amp;amp; Torres Strait Islander people. Call 13YARN (13 92 76).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image caption: R U OK? Community Ambassador Andre Sakr.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/r-u-ok-encourages-tradies-to-support-each-other-1434791397</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/r-u-ok-encourages-tradies-to-support-each-other-1434791397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Electricians charged after potentially fatal oversight</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   Two electrical workers and one company have been charged in Western Australia after the occupants of three Pilbara homes were left exposed to potentially fatal hazards for weeks — a result of the electricians failing to install essential safety devices while upgrading switchboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Perth Magistrates Court, Karratha electrical contractor Minbaringu Services Pty Ltd and electrical workers Zane Russell and Trent Tatham all pleaded guilty to breaching WA’s electricity licensing regulations following prosecution by the state’s safety regulator, &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.wa.gov.au/building-and-energy" target="_blank"&gt;Building and Energy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russell and Tatham were employed by Minbaringu in late 2021 when they upgraded switchboards at properties used by mining workers in Tom Price and Wickham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrical workers and designated electrical inspectors from the electricity network operator Rio Tinto later found a key safety component, the multiple earthed neutral (MEN) connection, had not been installed in the switchboards at three properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a MEN, protective devices such as circuit breakers and fuses may not operate if an electrical fault occurs, which can cause metal objects to become live with lethal voltage levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tom Price home was occupied and hazardous for two months between Minbaringu’s switchboard work and the discovery and rectification of the missing MEN. The same risk was present for a month at the Wickham properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minbaringu had submitted official notices of completion for all three properties, which incorrectly certified that the electrical installing work had been checked and tested for safety and compliance. The MEN error would have easily been detected if the company’s electricians had carried out the compulsory checks and tests, including reviewing photographs attached to the notice that clearly showed the fault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magistrate Thomas Hall said there was “risk of death or permanent injury” from the “very serious” offences, which were made more significant by the work being incorrectly signed off as compliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Hall noted all parties had pleaded guilty at the earliest opportunity and the company had shown genuine remorse and insight. Minbaringu’s post-incident investigation was thorough and it had rectified its practices and cooperated fully with Building and Energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Western Australia’s Director of Energy Safety, Saj Abdoolakhan, said the case should remind electricians why checks and tests of their work are mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is simply no excuse for cutting corners with any area of electrical work when people’s lives can be at risk,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrical contractors must also drive a culture of compliance among their employees to ensure proper processes are followed at every job, Abdoolakhan said. “In this case, the contractor also obviously failed to adequately review photographs of its electricians’ work before signing the notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Had these defects not been discovered by the designated electrical inspectors they could have led to serious injuries or death,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/artisteer&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/electricians-charged-after-potentially-fatal-oversight-1147795118</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/electricians-charged-after-potentially-fatal-oversight-1147795118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4AEMC recommends mass rollout of smart meters</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   In a move welcomed by &lt;a href="https://www.energynetworks.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Energy Networks Australia&lt;/a&gt;, the Australian Energy Market Commission (&lt;a href="https://www.aemc.gov.au/" target="_blank"&gt;AEMC&lt;/a&gt;) has made a final recommendation in its metering review for the accelerated rollout of smart meters across Australian homes and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the AEMC’s suite of reforms, energy customers would receive a smart meter by 2030, along with better information, protections and data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The independent review determined that speeding up the rollout of smart meters to 100% of households by 2030 would provide net benefits to the value of $507 million for national electricity market regions, including NSW, Qld, the ACT and SA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AEMC Chair Anna Collyer cautioned that the current pathways for replacing smart meters have led to positive experiences for many, but not all customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Going from an old accumulation meter to a smart meter can be like going from a landline to a smart phone, and people deserve transparency and timely information about how they can make the device best work for them,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the AEMC’s proposal, a coordinated rollout would be led by energy networks developing a legacy meter retirement plan, with retailers overseeing upgrades to smart meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the final recommendations, retailers would be obliged to provide customer-friendly information prior to meter installations, as well as adequate notice regarding any tariff changes and access to real-time data free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recommendations also include the development of a communications strategy for the rollout to inform and assist consumers with their choices, and support for vulnerable customers with premises requiring remediation before a smart meter can be installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Smart meters are key to ensuring we are building a grid that will see us move into a net zero future,” said Energy Networks Australia CEO Dom van den Berg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We can’t run a 21st-century grid with 19th-century meter technology. Making sure every home and business has a smart meter will enable that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Van den Berg said that while not every customer could take advantage of the cheap power that rooftop solar or batteries can offer, smart meters would allow them to still save on their power bills by taking advantage of flexible pricing options such as the ‘solar soaker’ tariff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Smart meters also assist networks to identify, locate and fix faults and outages faster and make connection processes far simpler, which delivers better customer service,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AEMC said its final recommendations took in feedback from extensive consultation with stakeholders. The organisation will now work with energy advocacy bodies on next steps in the rule change process. Energy Networks Australia said it looked forward to continuing to collaborate with the AEMC, consumers and stakeholders on progressing these vital reforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit the &lt;a href="https://www.aemc.gov.au/market-reviews-advice/review-regulatory-framework-metering-services" target="_blank"&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/AvailableLight&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/aemc-recommends-mass-rollout-of-smart-meters-364819266</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/aemc-recommends-mass-rollout-of-smart-meters-364819266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Innodisk IAGCO carbon monoxide sensor module</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   Whether in homes, offices or public spaces, the demand for precise air monitoring tools is increasing. To cater to this need, Backplane Systems Technology now supplies Innodisk’s IAGCO, a digital carbon monoxide sensor module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designed for indoor air quality monitoring, IAGCO serves security monitoring needs and seamlessly integrates into wireless sensor networks. Its primary role is the meticulous detection of carbon monoxide concentrations around its installation point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sensor’s rapid response and recovery time provides users with prompt information about any dangerous carbon monoxide concentrations. It has wide operating ranges capable of accommodating varied temperature, humidity and voltage conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IAGCO’s on-chip data processing capability eliminates the need for external libraries, simplifying operations while not unduly straining the main control unit (MCU). Applications include smart home systems, HVAC and home appliances, as well the burgeoning realm of IoT devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/product/innodisk-iagco-carbon-monoxide-sensor-module-1466445719</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/product/innodisk-iagco-carbon-monoxide-sensor-module-1466445719</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Smart fire safety for a remote power station</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   A photovoltaic power station located in a mountainous region of Yunnan Province, China, used to depend on local villagers to act as fire ‘informants’ — a common practice in the past, especially in remote areas. Unsurprisingly, this system had its drawbacks, with slow flow of information, delayed instructions and manual positioning of the fire location drastically extending the response time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the 700+ mu* photovoltaic power station has implemented an intelligent fire prevention and control solution from &lt;a href="https://www.dahuasecurity.com/au/" target="_blank"&gt;Dahua Technology&lt;/a&gt; to safeguard its vast facilities. The solution significantly increased the accuracy of fire alarms by more than 10 times and the efficiency of fire alarm response by 30%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;24/7 remote fire safety inspection and monitoring&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dahua has integrated its technology with the inspection mode of the power station to create a robust system that monitors the fire situation in the power plant and its surrounding areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dual-lens cameras installed at high points were configured with cruising paths, enabling them to conduct uninterrupted online inspections of the power plant and display the images through the system. A plant inspection that previously took one month can now be completed in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the inspection process, algorithms are used to determine whether there is smoke or fire in each area. When a fire is detected, the system will locate the fire source within a range of 3–5 kilometres and find the fire location within 30–50 metres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;30% improvement in fire response efficiency&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to eliminating the need for further inspections, improving the efficiency of the overall handling process is another key advantage of this solution. Through converged communication technology, the tedious reporting and communication process of the past has been transformed into efficient information exchange between multiple terminal devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on onsite audio and video data, multiple parties can easily communicate and discuss plans and strategies. At the same time, fire alarm information and the fire location determined by the platform will be sent to relevant personnel in real time, allowing them to accurately and quickly reach the corresponding location to distinguish the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire safety is crucial for photovoltaic power stations. Dahua’s intelligent solution not only helps protect the power plants and their staff, but also facilitates the stable delivery of environmentally friendly electricity to thousands of households.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*1 mu corresponds to 1/15 of a hectare or about 666.67 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image courtesy of Business Wire.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/case-study/smart-fire-safety-for-a-remote-power-station-1603026926</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/case-study/smart-fire-safety-for-a-remote-power-station-1603026926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4New frontiers in clean energy</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   Given the pressing need for Australia to find alternatives to fossil fuels, and the rapidity of our energy transition, the world of future energy is a heady one, full of wild-sounding ideas, innovation and experimentation, with an array of disparate tech and brands for consumers and industry to sort through. As a forum for these ideas and products, the renewable energy expo &lt;a href="https://www.energynext.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Energy Next&lt;/a&gt; can feel like stepping into the near future, even though many of the ideas being presented are currently being trialled or put into practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited on the second day of the event, when I encountered talks exploring the benefits of microgrids, virtual power plants, ‘Superhybrids’ and hydrogen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pushing the envelope with VPPs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more and more businesses and homeowners adopting solar batteries, virtual power plants (VPPs) are becoming a hot topic. To form a virtual power plant, you need a collection of solar PV and solar battery owners who agree to form a network, coordinated by underlying software, that provides excess power to the grid at times of need. In addition to the benefit of grid stabilisation, this allows participants in the VPP to potentially earn some money from the solar they produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his talk on VPP Innovation for grid providers and customers, Alex Georgiou charted the history of &lt;a href="https://shinehub.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;ShineHub&lt;/a&gt;, the Australian solar tech company he co-founded with solar engineer Jin Kim. Beginning as a solar retail company that centralised all aspects of solar installation for the customer in the one online hub, ShineHub has since grown various sibling companies under the banner of GTL Group — one of these (released in 2020) is an independent VPP, meaning that users do not have to partner with an electricity retailer in order to be part of the virtual power plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When GTL introduced its cloud-based VPP in 2019 — the first in Australia, according to Georgiou — customers had to pay for hardware and there were relatively few takers. This changed when the company shifted its model so that it would pay its VPP customers 45c for every kWh the VPP drew from their household battery and fed into the grid (this has lately risen to 55c/kWh). This profit incentive resulted in a huge adoption rate, Georgiou said, with up to 95% of the company’s customers coming onboard at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its inception, ShineHub has gone on to become a major player in battery storage deployment (especially residential), installing 40 MWh of batteries and helping to prevent another South Australian blackout, according to Georgiou.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ShineHub’s comprehensive approach stems from a desire to make things easier for companies who are trying to get into batteries from scratch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We built these software systems for the integration between products, systems and grid, to be able to really easily facilitate the positive adoption of these batteries,” Georgiou said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;EVs: giant, mobile batteries&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles present another opportunity for helping to stabilise the grid and participate in the energy market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the same way that batteries can be used for virtual power plants in the home, car batteries can be used for virtual power plants wherever they’re located,” Georgiou said. A major challenge for making EVs part of a VPP, however, is that there are huge penalties from VPP markets if back-up power is not available for the grid when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Georgiou was confident these problems can be ironed out. He envisaged a situation where someone drives their EV to the mall, plugs it in, leaves it to recharge and makes their money off the virtual power plant while shopping. It’s a solution “that’s not that far away”, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Microgrids to the rescue?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jey Shivakumar, Principal Engineer, Energy Transformation Services at the engineering firm Cossill &amp;amp; Webley, spoke about decarbonisation in a Western Australian context, where the state’s major utility Synergy has been given a large sum of money to close down coal-generated energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting the utilities handle Australia’s energy transition on their own is not the best option, according to Shivakumar, especially not in a large state like WA that is not fully interconnected. With 4000 km of transmission network still needed, challenges for utility-scale solar PV, wind and hydro include the need for large-scale transmission line upgrades as well as access to easements and sizeable tracts of land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While one solution is to let individuals arrange their own solar installations, probably with distributed energy resources (DER) like solar PV and batteries, this is not the most reliable system given a plethora of different brands and infrastructures, Shivakumar said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could microgrids help to fill the gap? Microgrids are small enough not to be burdened by the problems faced by large energy providers, yet big enough to be able to take advantage of energy sharing. At the moment, however, there is a fair bit of uncertainty around how microgrids are run (Shivakumar described it as a “Wild West mentality”), including the grey area of how much a utility needs to be involved, as well as making sure customers are protected downstream. There is a need for more regulation, governance and protection of customers. Into the future, though, Shivakumar believes the knowledge gained from microgrids can be passed on to utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;‘Superhybrids’: pulling everything together&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture the energy transition and you probably see solar and wind farms; photovoltaic panels on roofs; batteries; and, taking on an increasingly prominent role, hydrogen. But what if multiple energy sources could be pulled together in the one power plant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the Superhybrid, a solution developed by carbon-free energy company &lt;a href="https://sunshinehydro.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Sunshine Hydro&lt;/a&gt; and introduced at Energy Next by the company’s Executive Chairman Michael Myer in his talk, ‘Superhybrids’ Role in Australia as a Green Superpower’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Superhybrid can be thought of as an ecosystem, Myer said, combining traditional pumped hydro with wind, solar, hydrogen electrolysis, liquefaction and fuel cells, with the aim of producing 24/7 carbon-free energy. (A Superhybrid is capable of producing the same almost-100% carbon-free energy as a nuclear power station, but more cost-effectively, according to Sunshine Hydro.) It provides ‘deep’ energy storage: more than 15 hours. Crucially, the ecosystem is coordinated and optimised by the company’s AESOP software, developed over the past seven years. While a Superhybrid is thought of as a single piece of infrastructure, parts of it can be divided between different companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunshine Hydro currently has several Superhybrid projects planned in Australia, including the &lt;a href="https://www.flavian.sunshinehydro.com/" target="_blank"&gt;$2bn Djandori gung-i hydropower project&lt;/a&gt; near Miriam Vale within the Central Queensland Renewable Energy Zone, for which development applications are being prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Other areas of interest&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other presentations at Energy Next looked at the potential role of hydrogen, which has considerable funding behind it at the moment (including the federal government’s $2 billion Hydrogen Headstart initiative for green hydrogen projects). Solar technology featured heavily, as might be expected, and there was plenty of focus on EVs (charging infrastructure, as well as electric vehicles’ role as energy storage systems).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy data — and systems for capturing it, such as GTL’s VPP and Sunshine Hydro’s AESOP software — was a key theme throughout the conference. In her talk on a real-time marketplace for energy data, Grace Young, Chief Innovation Officer at &lt;a href="https://wattwatchers.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Wattwatchers Digital Energy&lt;/a&gt;, examined the multiple issues that need to be balanced when collecting, aggregating and sharing energy data from homes and businesses in real time, including security and privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, if there was one major takeaway from Energy Next, it was the necessity of having good underlying software to log and coordinate the movement of renewable energy as it makes its way flexibly from solar panel, battery, EV, wind farm or pumped hydro and into a rapidly changing grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Energy Next took place on 18–19 July 2023 at ICC, Sydney.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/vm&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/article/new-frontiers-in-clean-energy-240490358</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/article/new-frontiers-in-clean-energy-240490358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4How reliable will eastern Aust energy be over the next 10 years?</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   The recently released &lt;a href="https://aemo.com.au/-/media/files/electricity/nem/planning_and_forecasting/nem_esoo/2023/2023-electricity-statement-of-opportunities.pdf?la=en&amp;amp;hash=D8CC2D9AC8D9F353194C9DD117095FB4" target="_blank"&gt;2023 Electricity Statement of Opportunities (ESOO) report&lt;/a&gt; from the Australian Energy Market Operator (AEMO) has highlighted the need for urgent investment in renewable energy projects as coal and gas are increasingly phased out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ESOO report assesses the reliability of electricity over the upcoming decade for each state in the National Electricity Market (NEM) and signals what development is needed to cover predicted supply gaps. It is produced using insights from developer and market participant surveys, transmission information and extended analysis of energy limitations, like the potential impact of drought conditions, as well as coal and gas supply shortfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This year’s report highlights the pace of Australia’s energy transition and the urgency needed to deliver new investment to ensure reliable, affordable and cleaner energy for consumers,” said AEMO CEO Daniel Westerman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Over the 10-year outlook, we continue to forecast reliability gaps, which are mostly due to the expectation that 62% of today’s coal fleet will retire by 2033.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To ensure Australian consumers continue to have access to reliable electricity supplies, it’s critical that planned investments in transmission, generation and storage projects are urgently delivered,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Emerging reliability gaps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AEMO predicts that over the next 10 years, electricity consumption and peak demand will grow due partly to population growth and economic activity, but also due to electrification (fuel switching) across all sectors of the economy, including transportation and residential heating and cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reliability risks are forecast to exceed the relevant reliability standard in Victoria from this summer; New South Wales from 2025–26; South Australia this summer and then again from 2028–29; and Queensland from 2029–30. These risks are calculated based on existing, committed&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; and anticipated projects&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; as per the ESOO’s ‘central scenario’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reliability gaps identified through the central scenario form an important part of the electricity planning process, as they provide the signal, and in some cases the obligation, for electricity retailers to contract sufficient capacity to provide for a reliable power system.&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Westerman pointed out that while the central scenario showed increased reliability risk, it did not reflect the reliability &lt;em&gt;potential&lt;/em&gt; from the 248 gigawatt (GW) pipeline of proposed generation and storage projects, actionable transmission projects and government energy programs underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Federal and state government initiatives, including transmission projects identified in the Integrated System Plan, and mechanisms delivering firming capacity, such as the Commonwealth’s Capacity Investment Scheme, can address many of the identified risks over most of the 10-year horizon, if delivered to schedule,” Westerman said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is also the opportunity for consumers’ rooftop solar, batteries and electric vehicles to actively participate in the power system, which would further reduce reliability risks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to last summer, around 3.4 GW of new generation and storage capacity is expected to be available this summer, which is forecast to be hotter than in previous years, meaning electricity demand may be higher than observed in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re expecting an elevated level of risk compared to recent years, mostly due to hotter and drier conditions, and coal-fired generation reliability is at historic lows,” Westerman said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The entire industry is focused on managing the risks in the summer ahead, particularly during high-demand periods coupled with generation outages and low renewable output, but some risk will remain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the longer term, AEMO will continue to collaborate with industry and governments to deliver energy projects to maintain reliable and affordable electricity for all consumers,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Energy analysts respond&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several energy analysts have weighed in on the 2023 ESOO report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Buckley, Director of independent public interest think tank &lt;a href="https://climateenergyfinance.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Climate Energy Finance&lt;/a&gt;, said it was notable that AEMO explicitly confirmed that risks to supply can be adequately addressed by state and federal government renewable energy transition initiatives currently underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These include enhancing orchestration of virtual power plants (VPPs) and distributed energy resources (DER) such as rooftop solar to help shore up supply and firming; major transmission infrastructure; pumped hydro storage (PHS); and battery energy storage systems (BESS) — assuming these can be delivered on schedule.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Stephanie Bashir, Founder and CEO of &lt;a href="https://nexaadvisory.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Nexa Advisory&lt;/a&gt;, stressed that the pipeline projects AEMO designed to address reliability gaps were at risk of not being finished on time without significant action from industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The industry, from investors to developers and providers, are ready and willing to do this. We have been saying, for years, governments and other decision-makers need to focus the effort on prioritising and accelerating connections of the renewable power projects in the ISP [&lt;a href="https://aemo.com.au/en/energy-systems/electricity/national-electricity-market-nem/nem-forecasting-and-planning/integrated-system-plan-isp" target="_blank"&gt;Integrated System Plan&lt;/a&gt;] and building the transmission infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I cannot emphasise enough that we cannot rely on coal power to address reliability issues when [it is] part of the problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://flowpower.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Flow Power&lt;/a&gt; CEO Matthew van der Linden said that there were “very real, practical solutions staring policymakers in the face”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Demand response, or using energy at off-peak times, is an incredibly simple yet untapped opportunity. In Victoria alone, if just 5% of businesses powered down at the right times, the reliability gap for this summer would disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Likewise, for individuals: with the right education and incentives, households could play an active role in taking pressure off the grid and helping to correct the market. It’s high time governments got serious about demand response with funding and education. Programs like the Building Integrated Demand Response in South Australia show that government programs can support businesses to embrace automation and reduce their impact on the grid,” van der Linden said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tristan Edis, Director, Analysis and Advisory, &lt;a href="http://greenmarkets.com.au/about-us/our-team/" target="_blank"&gt;Green Energy Markets&lt;/a&gt;, said, “While we certainly need to get our skates on building new power plants, the amount of unserved energy after Eraring exits is surprisingly small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If readers manage to make it to page 74 of the report they’ll find the amount of new capacity needed to meet the reliability standard can be easily constructed within the time frames required.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;1. Committed projects meet all five of AEMO’s commitment criteria (land, contracts, planning, finance and construction) but have not yet met the requirements of their first commissioning hold point.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2. Anticipated projects have made progress towards at least three of AEMO’s commitment criteria and have provided AEMO confirmation or update of project status in the last six months.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;3. The ESOO Central scenario applies for the purposes of the Retailer Reliability Obligation.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Joniquelife&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/article/how-reliable-will-eastern-aust-energy-be-over-the-next-10-years--1525424925</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/article/how-reliable-will-eastern-aust-energy-be-over-the-next-10-years--1525424925</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4MEA calls for wide adoption of home battery storage</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   &lt;a href="https://masterelectricians.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Master Electricians Australia&lt;/a&gt; (MEA) is strongly recommending the adoption of home battery storage as an immediate solution for Australia’s at-risk energy grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MEA CEO Malcolm Richards said governments needed to stop prolonging the pain of the clean energy transition by hanging onto the hope that billion-dollar infrastructure projects such as Snowy 2.0 and the Marinus link would eventually provide a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The solution is an absolute no-brainer. The best way to prevent successive summers of blackout pain is to leverage the investments so many of us have already made in the clean energy transition by encouraging home energy storage,” Richards said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This would be a game changer that is well within our immediate reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Investing in home energy storage takes away the need to build more transmission lines, but governments need to be working together to drive this in the right direction — not catching up when it’s all too late.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richards said a major obstacle to effective use of solar and energy storage is that current tariff structures do not sufficiently reward homeowners for the amount of power they offset from their solar panels into the grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Excess energy produced during the day from these solar panels is wasted, rather being stored at the source of its generation and load shifted to times of peak demand in the evening,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a grid that often can’t cope with the excess load from solar panels, it was far more logical to invest in battery storage for homes and businesses that are, in many cases, producing more energy than they consume, Richards said. This stored power could then be distributed to the grid when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richards said the latest report by the Australian Energy Market Operator (&lt;a href="https://aemo.com.au/en" target="_blank"&gt;AEMO&lt;/a&gt;) of an impending summer of blackouts as the grid struggled to cope with El Nino weather forecasts showed the urgency of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MEA suggested the following measures would support the grid as coal-fired power stations continue to be decommissioned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Introducing metering reforms that speed up the rollout of smart meters into every Australian home and business.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Providing rebates to incentivise home battery storage to soak up the feed-in from large-scale home solar systems across the country during the middle of the day and returning it to the grid.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Legislating a preference for bidirectional-enabled EVs to further support load shifting, turning EVs from a potential drain on the grid to being part of the solution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Urgently reforming consumer electricity tariffs to take advantage of home batteries and bidirectional EVs.&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Marc_Osborne&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/mea-calls-for-wide-adoption-of-home-battery-storage-564529274</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/mea-calls-for-wide-adoption-of-home-battery-storage-564529274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Q&amp;amp;A with Jey Shivakumar: How microgrids can serve residential and industrial sites</title>
      <description>&lt;h4&gt;Witchcliffe Ecovillage&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Witchcliffe Ecovillage is a picturesque sustainable community of 11 residential clusters each containing 20–25 homes. The community produces and harvests its own energy, water and fresh food produce onsite.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/527704/web_image_article/110_20221012_ECOVILLAGE_Jodie___Aarons_Home.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image courtesy of Witchcliffe Ecovillage.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Could you describe the Witchcliffe Ecovillage site and what was involved in designing suitable energy infrastructure for it?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This development is located 8 km south of Margaret River, in sub-regional WA. The electrical network within the area is constrained with long feeders that are a mixture of pole-top and underground cables. Any system designed to interface with this type of network would need to consider reduced network reliability (dropouts) and limited hosting capacity for large-scale embedded generation systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Are you able to go into some of the manufacturers that were used and the reasons for using them?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suppliers for the core embedded generation systems were Solarwatt (panels), Fronius (Inverters) and Tesla (Battery System). All these products were chosen by the developer since all of these suppliers were willing to engage early, assist with early procurement and offer bulk purchasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to achieve as much consistency in the installed systems as possible to limit compatibility issues and have strategic spares available for potential replacements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/527706/web_image_article/125_20221012_ECOVILLAGE_Jodie___Aarons_Home.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image courtesy of Witchcliffe Ecovillage.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;How many people worked on the installation, approximately?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project management, design and installation teams comprised over 25 people with various skill and experience levels coming together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Did you encounter any challenges?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge was the process of obtaining all the relevant approvals. As the project was pushing the envelope in terms of sustainability goals, approval authorities did not have processes to handle what we had proposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fair amount of time was spent consulting and engaging with all approval bodies to assist them in understanding our objectives, which eventually resulted in very positive discussions and opportunities to upgrade processes for future developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Could you talk about the advantages of energy sharing that were provided by this particular microgrid model?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As each cluster is, in effect, a private network microgrid, it has a single CT (current transformer) metered point of connection with a retailer and private metering within. All excess solar PV generation is shared among the residents within the cluster. Excess energy is then stored in the battery to be shared during the evenings, with any surplus above that to be exported to the grid and greater network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private metering within the site allows for any excess energy generated by individual residents to be shared among each other without having to go through a retailer. This also opens the door to allow variable pricing of energy for energy trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Peel Business Park&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peel Business Park, part of the WA Government’s multimillion-dollar Transform Peel project, is an industrial estate 70 km south of Perth designed for a multitude of uses, including manufacturing and fabrication; transport and logistics; wholesale storage; warehousing; and agri-innovation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/527630/web_image_article/Peel_Business_Park_Microgrid.jpg" style="display: block; height: 265px; margin: auto; width: 400px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Peel Business Park Microgrid. Image courtesy of DevelopmentWA.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;How did this large-scale project, which I understand is the first of its kind in WA, differ from Witchcliffe Ecovillage?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Witchcliffe is comprised of small private strata clusters with small distributed microgrids, each with a network/utility connection per cluster. Peel Business Park, on the other hand, is a large-scale single microgrid with a private network operator having a distribution network licence that owns and operates the network. The private networks within Witchcliffe are owned and operated by each individual strata cluster through the strata body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Did this model break new ground? If so, what was particularly innovative?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most groundbreaking element of this estate was the engagement of a private network operator instead of the standard state utility to service the lots with power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Why was the decision made to use a microgrid?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real push was to achieve an industrial estate that moves towards net zero, provides a reduced energy price for future tenants within the development and reduces the costs associated with network upgrades to service the site with power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Do you think this set-up will become more widespread on similar industrial estates?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that as time goes on and connecting to standard utility networks becomes more complicated, private operators will take over. Private network operators with smaller, more manageable networks will roll out and tie in with the greater grids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will allow private network operators to embed more sustainable systems/controls within these networks and, at the point of connection, provide network utilities grid services to assist with network stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/526150/web_image_article/Jey-Shivakumar.jpg" style="display: block; height: 335px; margin: auto; width: 250px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Top image caption: Northern view of a Witchcliffe Ecovillage home. Image courtesy of Witchcliffe Ecovillage.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/article/q-amp-a-with-jey-shivakumar-how-microgrids-can-serve-residential-and-industrial-sites-1266825682</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/article/q-amp-a-with-jey-shivakumar-how-microgrids-can-serve-residential-and-industrial-sites-1266825682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4WA looks to future with new electricity framework</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   WA Energy Minister Bill Johnston has introduced a new bill to the parliament that aims to prepare the electricity sector for rapid changes resulting from the state’s energy transition. The primary legislation governing WA’s electricity sector is nearly 20 years old and no longer represents the way an increasing number of Western Australians produce, store and consume electricity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed with industry and consumer representatives, the Electricity Industry Amendment (Distributed Energy Resources) Bill 2023 amends the &lt;em&gt;Electricity Industry Act 2004&lt;/em&gt; to provide clarity and remove duplication by consolidating the rules and codes into one document — the Electricity System and Market Rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its amendments include support for the uptake of new technologies — such as rooftop solar and battery storage — to facilitate the Cook government’s commitment to net zero by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bill also introduces a State Electricity Objective, which “… will empower decision-makers to consider the energy trilemma — sustainability, reliability and affordability — ensuring that decisions are made for the long-term interest of all Western Australians”, Johnston said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The amendments will futureproof the existing governance framework, by providing provisions to better manage and incorporate rooftop solar, battery storage and electric vehicles,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit: &lt;a href="https://www.wa.gov.au/government/document-collections/energy-and-governance-legislation-reform" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.wa.gov.au/government/document-collections/energy-and-governance-legislation-reform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/SolStock&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/wa-looks-to-future-with-new-electricity-framework-856832404</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/wa-looks-to-future-with-new-electricity-framework-856832404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4$45K fine for unlicensed apprentice</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   An investigation by Queensland’s &lt;a href="https://www.electricalsafety.qld.gov.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Electrical Safety Office&lt;/a&gt; (ESO) has led to an unlicensed electrical apprentice being fined $45,000 in the Richlands Magistrates Court for performing non-compliant and unsafe electrical work in South East Queensland between November and December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The defendant pleaded guilty to six charges including failing to comply with electrical safety duties, installing unsafe electrical wiring and not holding the appropriate electrical licences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ESO’s investigation was prompted by a complaint about the defendant’s AirTasker profile ‘Brendon G’, which stated he was a licensed electrical contractor who could install ceiling fans, lights and external air con power switches as well as replace power points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, the defendant was a fourth-year apprentice and did not hold an electrical work licence nor an electrical contractor licence. He performed electrical work for 27 customers including installing ceiling fans, power points, lights and cooktops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The investigation identified unsafe electrical work and wiring rules contraventions at five locations, four of which exposed homeowners to serious electrical risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrical Safety Office Executive Director Donna Heelan said the safety regulator made no apologies for pursuing rogue operators who fail to comply with electrical safety and licensing legislation to ensure that Queenslanders are safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In sentencing, Magistrate Shearer stated the legislative scheme was designed to prevent unlicensed people from doing such work and that the penalties imposed have to be a real deterrent. The defendant was fined $45,000 with no conviction recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/wattanaphob&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/-45k-fine-for-unlicensed-apprentice-43137052</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/-45k-fine-for-unlicensed-apprentice-43137052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Trial to increase powerline safety begins in NSW</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   NSW distribution network service provider (DNSP) &lt;a href="https://www.ausgrid.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Ausgrid&lt;/a&gt; is trialling a new type of powerline technology with the aim of increasing safety and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lightweight covered conductor was supplied by Swedish specialist cable producer &lt;a href="https://amokabel.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Amokabel&lt;/a&gt; with support from &lt;a href="https://www.groundlineengineering.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Groundline Engineering&lt;/a&gt;, and has been installed on an 11 kilovolt (kV) line in the Sydney suburb of St Ives. This is the first deployment of lightweight covered conductor in New South Wales, Ausgrid said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ausgrid is leading the way on improving network resilience and reliability for power consumers in New South Wales, providing an example for other DNSPs,” said Steve Rutland, Managing Director of Amokabel Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Covered conductor offers a range of benefits in terms of resilience, reliability and safety, making it a clear choice for widespread deployment — especially with the effects of climate change having an increasing effect on our networks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology consists of conductive wire surrounded by an insulating jacket made of advanced lightweight insulation materials that improves reliability and adds minimal weight. This means that it can be restrung on existing poles to save the DNSP — and therefore the consumer — the cost of replacing infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/530189/web_image_article/Ausgrid_sent_field_crews_for_familirisation_with_the_technology.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Ausgrid sent field crews for familiarisation with the technology. Image: Supplied&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ausgrid’s goal for the trial is to compare this new technology with its existing methods. Lightweight covered conductor is more resilient than bare wire and significantly easier to install than older covered conductor technologies. It is highly resistant to dropped tree branches, a common cause of outages. The technology is also safer for people and wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an additional benefit, lightweight covered conductor can help to reduce the risk of bushfire by 98.8% compared with bare wire, according to Amokabel. This is because, unlike bare wire, an overhead line using covered conductor doesn’t produce sparks when it contacts dry foliage or other objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the 11 kV trial line is successful, Ausgrid will consider deploying a higher-rated version of the covered conductor for 33 kV lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob Bradley, Senior Engineer, Transmission Engineering at Ausgrid, reported that the first installation of the new CCSX covered conductor system went quickly and smoothly, with positive feedback from field crews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We really appreciated Groundline/Amokabel’s assistance with field crew training and also practical support and guidance during the installation works,” Bradley said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Top image caption: Installation underway in the Sydney suburb of St Ives. Image: Supplied&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/trial-to-increase-powerline-safety-begins-in-nsw-446379620</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/trial-to-increase-powerline-safety-begins-in-nsw-446379620</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Powering a lead and silver mine in Western Australia</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Abra Base Metals Mine&lt;/strong&gt; is a new high-grade lead-silver mine currently being constructed between Meekatharra and Newman in Western Australia (approximately 1,000 km northeast of Perth).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the remote nature of the mine, ensuring reliable energy to power the site was critical. Galena Mining wanted to incorporate a power station that would help lower the mine’s operating costs and reduce its carbon footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hybrid thermal and renewable power station is owned and operated by &lt;strong&gt;Pacific Energy&lt;/strong&gt;, an industry leader providing remote, off-grid energy in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hybrid power station is a 21 MW fully integrated system combining a 6 MWac solar farm, 2 MW Battery Energy Storage System (BESS) with a 10 MW high-efficiency/low emissions gas generation plant and 1,100 kl LNG storage and regas facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pacific Energy’s subsidiary, &lt;strong&gt;Hybrid Systems Australia&lt;/strong&gt;, designed, constructed and commissioned the solar farm and BESS solution, which incorporates the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;15,024 mono facial 460W panels with a NEXTracker single-axis tracking system&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;2 x 4.6 MW (4,565 kVA) FIMER PVS980-58 Central Inverters&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;2 MWh Battery Energy Storage System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;a href="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/523022/web_image_article/FIMER-HybridSystems-ABRAMine.jpg" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/523022/web_image_article/FIMER-HybridSystems-ABRAMine.jpg" style="display: block; height: 266px; margin: auto; width: 400px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In mid-2021, FIMER was engaged by Hybrid Systems to provide an 8.8M VA solution to meet the site’s energy requirements. FIMER provided several solutions, but the PVS980 4.6 MW solution was selected for its cost-effectiveness and performance capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We were extremely impressed with the capability and responsiveness of FIMER’s local and global product team throughout the project, specifically the product selection process and the commissioning of the products. Their level of communication provided us with comfort that our requirements had been met and we could meet our project milestones,” said Daniel Jackson, Hybrid Systems General Manager Operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FIMER’s PVS980 solution has a large install base worldwide, with many located in harsh environments. The Abra Base Metals Mine is in the Australian desert, where summer temperatures can reach 45–50 degrees Celsius. The performance of the PVS980 inverter when derating at high temperatures was an essential requirement. FIMER’s proven technology allowed the teams to plan for and ensure the size of the inverter could still provide sufficient generation when derated at temperatures above 35 and 50 degrees Celsius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Venning, FIMER Australia’s Country Manager, highlighted this, saying, “FIMER’s PVS980 inverters have proprietary technology using self-contained two-phase thermo-syphon heat exchangers, which are totally passive and provide high performance with a low-pressure drop, with an efficiency equivalent to liquid cooling and with the simplicity of an air-cooled system. This enables the inverters to be installed in high temperatures while still providing reliable performance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PVS980-58 5MVA is also extremely durable and is equipped with extensive electrical and mechanical protection to provide a long and reliable service life of at least 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FIMER’s PVS980 was delivered in January 2022 in time for the solar farm’s construction. During this time, FIMER provided technical training to Hybrid Systems and Pacific Energy engineers to commission and maintain the PVS980 units. One of FIMER’s technicians visited the site in early November to commission the two central inverters and certify their staff to become authorised technicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solar farm will meet nearly 30% of the mine site’s power needs. The solar generation and battery energy storage solution has an expected annual output of over 16,602 MWh and will reduce CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions by approximately 11,800 tonnes per annum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;*******************************&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style="text-align:center"&gt;Product spotlight: FIMER PVS980-58 5 MVA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;a href="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/523023/web_image_article/PVS980-58-5MVA.jpg" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/524723/web_image_article/PVS980-58-5MVA.jpg" style="display: block; height: 228px; margin: auto; width: 400px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next generation, high power, central inverter from the PVS980 family raises the performance, cost efficiency and ease of installation to new levels. The inverters are aimed at system integrators and end users who require high-performance solar inverters for large, solar power plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PVS980 central inverters are now available from 909 kVA up to 5000 kVA, and are optimised for multi-megawatt power plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like other FIMER central inverters, the PVS980-58 has been developed on the basis of decades of experience in the industry and a proven technology platform. Unrivalled expertise from the world’s market and technology leader in frequency converters is the hallmark of this solar inverter series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FIMER’s compact skid houses all the electrical equipment that is needed to rapidly connect a solar power plant to a medium-voltage (MV) electricity grid, or to a high-voltage point of connection through HV step-up grid facilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;*******************************&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/sponsored/powering-a-lead-and-silver-mine-in-western-australia-96762888</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/sponsored/powering-a-lead-and-silver-mine-in-western-australia-96762888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Embrace the New Energy Landscape for improved efficiency and sustainability.</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   Gone are the days when the electrical system of a commercial building was simply required to operate the lights and provide access to power. Now, in modern buildings, the electrical power system is complex, often incorporating features such as local energy generation, electric vehicle charging, energy storage, and connection to the grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coupled with the desire of tenants and building owners to improve their sustainability and energy efficiency, a digital transformation of electrical energy and power management is critical to the delivery of a holistic approach to power optimisation. In short, a smart power distribution system is needed. This is the New Energy Landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;EcoStruxure and the New Energy Landscape&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, only around 10% of electrical distribution equipment is connected to software&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. To truly optimise and improve the energy system of a commercial building, it is critical to collect energy and power metering data from strategic locations throughout each building’s electrical distribution system — from the service entrance to the final distribution circuits. After all, you can’t manage what you don’t measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several ways to implement a metering system, but a good rule of thumb is: the more meters a building has and the more advanced those meters are, the more insight and potential savings can be found. Integrated and connected products, such as intelligent sensors, metering, protection, control, and communication devices, distributed across one or more facilities and seamlessly networked together, can help enable this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the data has been collected, an overarching solution can be used to analyse critical data and discover meaningful insights, enabling actions based on real-time information and business logic. EcoStruxure platform is Schneider Electric’s plug-and-play, open, and interoperable IoT-enabled system architecture. It is the foundational technology backbone that connects everything from the shop floor to the top floor to collect and analyse critical data and discover meaningful insights and enable actions based on real-time information and business logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Connecting with energy management software&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schneider Electric’s EcoStruxure Power Monitoring Expert software provides access to real-time data and can send alerts from connected meters, circuit breakers, and other devices so you can keep an eye on the system and ensure it is operating efficiently. The software’s advanced dashboards, energy visualisation, and analysis tools seamlessly integrate so you can easily interpret the findings and make informed decisions. You can also run energy modelling and forecasting to uncover abnormal or wasteful energy usage, allocate costs to evaluate operations and use baseline comparisons to validate savings from upgrades or other initiatives. It can also aggregate collected data across multiple processes or facilities and generate compliance reports that meet ever-changing energy efficiency standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those wanting to proactively manage power management and power distribution systems, EcoStruxure Power Advisor offers remote access, support and on-site maintenance. The software provides data analysis for energy performance reporting, sub-billing, and energy and emissions audits — all crucial components in many modern buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software can also provide Green Building Certification support by indicating how an EcoStruxure solution can help achieve points toward NABERS certification or other popular rating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those buildings where net-zero performance or even net-positive energy usage is the goal, Schneider Electric’s EcoStruxure Microgrid Advisor offers dynamic control of on-site energy resources and loads. For example, the building may have its own energy source such as solar panels or wind turbines, as well as energy storage and a connection to the grid. In these instances, you might need software that can offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tariff management — using on-site renewable energy at the most advantageous time, based on variable tariff rates (i.e., self-consuming or selling renewable electricity to the grid when grid prices are high, and consuming or storing grid energy when prices are low).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Carbon footprint reduction — maximising the self-consumption of on-site renewable energy production to reduce equivalent emissions.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Peak shaving — consuming renewable energy to avoid demand penalties due to grid energy consumption exceeding a certain level for a given hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schneider Electric’s EcoStruxure Microgrid Advisor can automatically switch between energy sources, as and when different events are triggered. The software seamlessly connects to the energy resources to automatically forecast and optimise how and when to consume, produce, and store energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Achieving sustainability, net-zero and energy efficiency&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help your customers achieve their sustainability and energy efficiency goals, you need to offer a smart power distribution system, integrating energy management software that accurately tracks and analyses their electrical energy usage. By monitoring and managing their assets, you can also help your customers to extend the life of their products and systems, while making their operations safe, efficient and resilient every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schneider Electric’s EcoStruxure architecture is a comprehensive solution that helps turn your customer’s climate ambition into action. With the support of experts at Schneider Electric, and through our EcoXpert program, you can audit, design, manage, and maintain energy-efficient commercial buildings, with a customised, cost-effective, turnkey solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand more about how Schneider Electric can help you take advantage of the New Energy Landscape, &lt;a href="https://www.se.com/au/en/work/solutions/sustainability/" target="_blank"&gt;download our e-guide&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1 &lt;/sup&gt;Global estimates from Schneider Electric Field Services organization in 2020.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/sponsored/embrace-the-new-energy-landscape-for-improved-efficiency-and-sustainability--399917004</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/sponsored/embrace-the-new-energy-landscape-for-improved-efficiency-and-sustainability--399917004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4BERNSTEIN Three-Stage Enabling Foot Switch</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   The BERNSTEIN Three-Stage Enabling Foot Switch is an electromechanical switch designed for staged control operations. Its features include hands-free operation; reduced risk to the operator; easy and controlled positioning; and pedal position feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, a machine will not operate when a safety gate is open, which can make programming and maintenance problematic. With an enabling foot switch, these tasks can be safely performed using the logically designed switching stages as follows: Position 1 = OFF, Position 2 = ON, Position 3 = STOP, or rather will revert to the OFF position when the pedal is fully compressed. Level 3 is of enormous importance for the safety of the operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the enabling foot switches can be equipped with a safety latching mechanism. This ensures that the foot switch engages after reaching Position 3, and also ensures that the machine cannot be started without first being unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enabling foot switches from Bernstein also have the added option of pedal position monitoring. From a control point of view, pedal positions 1 and 3 are completely identical. Bernstein switches have an optional additional PNP signal output which indicates the exact pedal position, making it easy to identify and signal a forced stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, click &lt;a href="https://pacificautomation.com.au/industrial-automation/switching-safety/foot-switches/bernstein-f1-zsd-foot-switch-1039824?utm_source=ECD&amp;amp;utm_medium=Website&amp;amp;utm_campaign=BernsteinHotProduct" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/hot-product/bernstein-three-stage-enabling-foot-switch-977375585</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/hot-product/bernstein-three-stage-enabling-foot-switch-977375585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Photovoltaic (PV) Modules &amp;mdash; The Principle of Photovoltaic Cell Operation</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   Nowadays, it is a common situation for household illumination systems or even electric cars to be supplied with solar energy provided by photovoltaic cells. However, it does not mean that everybody, including PV system users, knows the principle of operation of such systems and recognises the processes transforming solar energy into electric power. In this article, most of such issues are precisely explained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;WHAT IS PHOTOVOLTAICS?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photovoltaics is the technology of converting solar radiation into electric power through the use of photovoltaic panels and DC-to-AC converters&lt;/strong&gt; to supply energy consumers connected to a power network or to store energy in batteries. This is the simplest and most narrow definition, so it is worth adopting a slightly broader perspective and going back to the beginnings of this technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By definition, “photovoltaics” is a science interested in converting solar energy into electric power that has evolved into an important field of technical engineering that is now present in the majority of highly developed countries. In parallel, numerous technologies related to obtaining energy from renewable energy sources have been developed. However, &lt;strong&gt;obtaining energy from the sun radiation is the most important and remains the leading method of providing “free-of-charge” and infinite energy.&lt;/strong&gt; Moreover, note that solar energy could completely replace fossil fuel-based energy sources, which would significantly reduce air pollution levels. However, there is one major drawback to it, namely the demand for a large surface area resulting from a PV panel size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;PHOTOVOLTAIC PANELS — PRINCIPLE OF OPERATION&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The process of converting solar energy into electric power&lt;/strong&gt; taking place in the internal cell layers starts under the reflective layer, where &lt;strong&gt;two silicon plates are located, i.e. the upper one acts as a negative conductor made of silicon with a phosphorus admixture&lt;/strong&gt;. The lower plate acts as a positive conductor and is made of silicon with a boron admixture. When a photon strikes a silicon atom, it knocks the electron out of its place and forces it to move. Since there are a lot of photons and such knocks, the electrons attempt to pair up with the vacant places left by the previously knocked out neighbouring electrons, and, as a result, they begin to circulate between the plates and in this way generate electric charge movement. However, the electric field present at the contact point of the positive and negative layers separates the electron-vacant space pairs, which results in arranging the electron movement and generating voltage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is easy to connect with a local power grid, however, the system must be provided with a frequency converter to transform DC into AC. As mentioned above, silicon is used as a basic material of PV cells, as the photon energy is equivalent to the energy required to move one electron in a silicon atom. Despite the fact that pure silicon is not a perfect conductor, the best solution is obtained when it is mixed with phosphorus and boron. Manufacturers also offer&lt;strong&gt; panels made from other materials, e.g. cadmium combined with tellurium, copper, indium, gallium and selenium.&lt;/strong&gt; However, regardless of the elements used, photovoltaic panels always consist of photovoltaic cells, which are their smallest components and can be connected in series or in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;MAIN PV CELL TYPES&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, there are two basic photovoltaic cell types available on the market. These are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;silicon-based cells (panels) (monocrystalline, polycrystalline and amorphous),&lt;/strong&gt; market share is definitely dominant;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;cells (panels) made of other elements (CdTe and CIGS).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silicon-based panels are most common due to their simple design and high efficiency, i.e. 17–23% for &lt;a href="https://www.tme.com/au/en/katalog/photovoltaic-modules_113581/?params=139:1774886_material:monocrystalline-silicon&amp;amp;utm_source=https://www.ecdonline.com.au/&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2023-08-17_ecdonline_(og)_AU" target="_blank"&gt;monocrystalline panels&lt;/a&gt; and approx. 14–18% for polycrystalline panels. Monocrystalline panels are characterised by the highest efficiency, but they are also most expensive. They are made of circular silicon plates that are trimmed to a square shape with chamfered corners. &lt;a href="https://www.tme.com/au/en/katalog/photovoltaic-modules_113581/?params=139:1617643_material:polycrystalline-silicon&amp;amp;utm_source=https://www.ecdonline.com.au/&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2023-08-17_ecdonline_(og)_AU" target="_blank"&gt;Polycrystalline panels&lt;/a&gt; (efficiency: 14–18%) are made from multicrystalline silicon, in the form of a compressed block with a non-uniform surface, cut into thin square bluish plates. Matt amorphous panels are made of very cheap non-crystallised silicon, which results in their lower efficiency (8–10%), but also the lowest price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other group of PV cells includes products made from elements other than silicon. This group includes &lt;strong&gt;CdTe and CIGS cells&lt;/strong&gt; with a negligible photovoltaic layer thickness and lower efficiency as compared to silicon-based panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CdTe panels comprise a single cell, with a thickness of a few microns, made of cadmium telluride, and their efficiency is slightly higher (10–12%) in comparison with CIGS panels (12–14%), whose design is based on four elements, i.e. copper, indium, gallium and selenium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;FACTORS INFLUENCING PV PANEL EFFICIENCY&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although PV cell manufacturers usually do not disclose any proprietary manufacturing process details for reasons of commercial confidentiality, it can be assumed that &lt;strong&gt;the quality of these cells is determined by the cutting conditions of the crystals and quartz blocks, as well as the monocrystalline crystal culture conditions. &lt;/strong&gt;Other factors affecting quality include conditions in which the panels are polished, as well as cleanliness, ventilation and temperature of the rooms where the key processes are run. However, it is easiest to compare the efficiency and performance of identical panels supplied by different manufacturers, as they largely depend on the manufacturing process quality and materials used in production. To obtain objective results, tests must be conducted under identical real-world conditions which are constantly influenced by diverse factors common to all the panels (cells) affected by a test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, regardless of whether a comparative test is conducted or real-life PV system operation is analysed, &lt;strong&gt;there is always the same group of factors influencing the end results:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;roof surface area;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;roof inclination in relation to sunlight;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;season of the year, i.e. sun radiation intensity;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;sunlight absorption time in hours; and&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;operating temperature of the cells.&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter is quite problematic, as the efficiency of cells decreases when they reach their temperature limit, which happens during very hot and sunny days. This is therefore a paradox situation, as these are the days with the most solar radiation intensity. The other factors mentioned above, including the lack of shade in panel operating locations, also directly affect the amount of electric power obtained. Seasons of the year are also important, as in spring and summer the number of sunny days is greater, and the intensity of the sunlight is at its highest, which, together with the right angle of cell inclination, gives much better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;PV CELLS IN THE TME PRODUCT CATALOGUE&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The range of PV cells offered by TME includes products provided by three manufacturers: &lt;a href="https://www.tme.com/au/en/katalog/photovoltaic-modules_113581/?params=2:131_manufacturer:panasonic&amp;amp;utm_source=https://www.ecdonline.com.au/&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2023-08-17_ecdonline_(og)_AU" target="_blank"&gt;Panasonic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.tme.com/au/en/katalog/photovoltaic-modules_113581/?params=2:1346_manufacturer:green-power&amp;amp;utm_source=https://www.ecdonline.com.au/&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2023-08-17_ecdonline_(og)_AU" target="_blank"&gt;Green Power&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.tme.com/au/en/katalog/photovoltaic-modules_113581/?params=2:897_manufacturer:cellevia-power&amp;amp;utm_source=https://www.ecdonline.com.au/&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2023-08-17_ecdonline_(og)_AU" target="_blank"&gt;Cellevia Power&lt;/a&gt;. The products offered by the first one are mini-amorphous cells for internal use (clocks, minor electronic equipment), and the range provided by the other two manufacturers includes larger mono- and polycrystalline cells for outdoor applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, click &lt;a href="https://www.tme.com/au/en/katalog/?utm_source=https://www.ecdonline.com.au/&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2023-08-17_ecdonline_(e)_AU" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/sponsored/photovoltaic-pv-modules-the-principle-of-photovoltaic-cell-operation-60315861</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/sponsored/photovoltaic-pv-modules-the-principle-of-photovoltaic-cell-operation-60315861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4Rio Tinto decarbonises with solar energy storage — a case study</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   
	&lt;span style="background-color: initial;"&gt;Rio Tinto had site access gates that required power to operate. At the time, the only option was to dig long trenches to run power lines, which brought cost and complexity. Due to the remoteness of the site location, the solution also needed to include remote monitoring to alert to smoke, intruders, theft and tampering, as well as provide shade and weather protection.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Learn about how Rio Tinto leveraged a modular, maintenance-free, easy-to-install, standalone solar system to solve their problem. Discover how to utilise free solar power to reap the benefits of no ongoing electricity bills.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 11:15:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/white-paper/rio-tinto-decarbonises-with-solar-energy-storage-a-case-study-773239925</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/white-paper/rio-tinto-decarbonises-with-solar-energy-storage-a-case-study-773239925</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECD 4NSW Govt urged to retain EV rebate</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:none !important ;color:purple !important; " class="green"&gt;   The Motor Traders’ Association of NSW (&lt;a href="https://www.mtansw.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;MTA NSW&lt;/a&gt;) is urging the NSW Government to retain its EV rebate scheme in order to help support industry transition, facilitate consumer adoption and contribute to a more sustainable automotive future for New South Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1 September 2021, the NSW Government &lt;a href="https://www.nsw.gov.au/driving-boating-and-transport/ev-rebates" target="_blank"&gt;has offered $3000 rebates&lt;/a&gt; on purchases on the first 25,000 new battery electric and hydrogen fuel cell vehicles with a dutiable value of less than $68,750.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MTA NSW warned that any proposal to remove the EV rebate would be premature given the scheme is nascent and hasn’t had the chance to play out fully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The mixed messaging resulting from any proposed changes to the current EV rebate scheme could have far-reaching implications for the community, market dynamics and the automotive industry at large,” said Collin Jennings, Head of Government Relations and Advocacy at MTA NSW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of electric passenger vehicles sold year-to-date in July 2023 rose from 2324 to 5544, underscoring the increasing popularity of EVs, according to the latest figures from the Federal Chamber of Automotive Industries’ &lt;a href="https://www.fcai.com.au/sales/get-vfacts" target="_blank"&gt;VFACTS&lt;/a&gt; report. Moreover, electric SUVs experienced a significant leap, growing from 1084 YTD in July 2022 to 10,932 YTD in July 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The rebate scheme, while relatively new, has already demonstrated its positive impact on the sales of electric vehicles in both NSW and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As the original engine manufacturers (OEMs) and importers work hard to reduce the costs of electric vehicles, the existing rebate will serve as an important mechanism to bring forth the next wave of adoption and propel electric vehicles into the mainstream,” Jennings said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MTA NSW is advocating for the state government to make EVs more affordable to a wider range of people, especially as cheaper electric vehicle models make their way into the market in the short to medium term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industry body emphasised that the policy measures of state and federal governments should be clear and aligned to ensure a successful electric vehicle transition. Mixed messages would create confusion among stakeholders and undermine the collective efforts of the auto industry, which has been working hard to meet demands by investing millions of dollars in training and equipment, the organisation said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/chameleonseye&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com.au" target="_blank"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;button type="button"&gt;Click Me!&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023</pubDate>
      <link>http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/nsw-govt-urged-to-retain-ev-rebate-1677812244</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">http://ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/nsw-govt-urged-to-retain-ev-rebate-1677812244</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
