<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ECD (Electrical+Comms+Data) RSS Feed</title>
    <description>In this issue: ECD (Electrical+Comms+Data)</description>
    <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au</link>
    <item>
      <title>HVAC under strain as El Ni&amp;ntilde;o bites</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the Bureau of Meteorology &lt;a href="https://media.bom.gov.au/releases/1183/the-bureau-declares-el-nino-and-positive-indian-ocean-dipole-events/" target="_blank"&gt;declaring an El Niño event&lt;/a&gt; for this summer, bringing with it warmer and drier conditions and an increased likelihood of heatwaves, HVAC systems in Australia’s million-plus commercial buildings will need to work harder than ever, producing higher energy bills and greater emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Given that all Australian state capitals already have many days exceeding 35–40 degrees, the Australian Standard* for offices and factories of 21–24°C is going to be under some large pressure,” said Michael Fisher, Managing Director of &lt;a href="https://www.boonedam.com/en-au" target="_blank"&gt;Boon Edam Australia&lt;/a&gt;, part of a global group specialising in architectural revolving doors and security entrances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Given that commercial buildings are responsible for about 24% of Australia’s total energy consumption, the pressure is going to be on to maximise efficiencies while minimising emissions from hard-working air-conditioning plant,” Fisher said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Keeping commercial energy bills down&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building owners and managers particularly prone to higher energy bills, closer emission scrutiny and duty-of-care issues this summer include those in charge of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;data centres and financial computing centres, which already draw large amounts of energy overall and face calls to reduce emissions;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;public and private office buildings;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;health centres, which have a particular responsibility to maintain even temperatures for their patients;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;hotels and retail centres concerned about guest and customer comfort (Australia has more than 1600 shopping centres of more than 1000 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, and about 6000 hotels and similar establishments);&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;industrial workplaces, which have a duty of care for worker conditions, and also to maintain hygienic temperatures around delicate processes and perishable goods;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Australia’s 10,000 primary, secondary, TAFE and university colleges, which accommodate more than 5.6 million students and academic staff (including more than 4 million primary and secondary students and about 1.5 million at higher education facilities).&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Many of our stock of a million-plus non-residential buildings are upgrading their HVAC systems to the best modern standards, while architects, builders and managers generally are paying far greater attention to producing ‘tight’ buildings that don’t leak expensively conditioned air and place greater load on plant,” Fisher said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Many also are highly aware of the amount of HVAC air that is dumped out onto the footpath every time a sliding or conventional door is used — which is nearly all the time in busy government and private buildings, particularly service and transport centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t pretend for a moment that revolving doors are a total answer to energy sustainability objectives — that is a multifaceted issue — but we do believe that some buildings have a sustainability blind spot when it comes to the obvious benefits of revolving door entrances, with their ‘always open, always closed’ functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One of the difficulties in the past has been actually measuring the doors’ impact on sustainability, and obtaining practical ROI information as the cost of energy continually goes up and the ROI continually tracks down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Measuring energy savings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boon Edam — which operates in 27 countries globally — has set out to provide architects, builders and managers with a reliable estimation tool to quantify the gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company partnered with &lt;a href="https://www.tudelft.nl/en/" target="_blank"&gt;Delft University of Technology&lt;/a&gt; (TU Delft) to develop a scientifically validated software that is now available in Australia, New Zealand and Papua New Guinea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The software’s science-based approach gives specifiers the chance to demonstrate to their clients what many of them have known for years: revolving doors offer permanent gains in energy efficiency across the spectrum of commercial building types, both existing structures and new buildings seeking NABERS or National Electricity Market (NEM) measurable sustainability credentials,” Fisher said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software was first used to test Sydney, Melbourne and Brisbane building models. It showed that the payback period for installing a revolving door, instead of a less energy-efficient sliding door, is shrinking rapidly as energy prices accelerate quickly. Calculated on this year’s prevailing energy prices (which are due to rise again early in 2024), Melbourne has the quickest payback time of four years, followed by Brisbane at 4.9 years and Sydney at 5.7 years and shrinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The energy calculation software quantifies the benefits of revolving doors compared to sliding doors when considering energy savings and prevention of draught. Users are provided with a format into which to enter specific data for their facility, which is then processed by the new Boon Edam propriety software. The software calculates and reports on data including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;energy savings in kWh per month throughout the year when a revolving door is installed instead of a sliding door;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;payback time of a revolving door compared to an automatic sliding door;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;the area of the floor behind both door types, where according to &lt;a href="https://www.din.de/en/about-standards/din-standards" target="_blank"&gt;DIN standards&lt;/a&gt;, serious discomfort from draught can be expected.&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fisher said that for building specifiers seeking to achieve green performance ratings, it can no longer be a question of ‘What is the cheapest door upfront?’, but rather ‘How can we create a sustainable, secure and comfortable environment that meets national and global standards of sustainability and returns benefits starting immediately and extending over decades?’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*AS1837- 1976 Code of Practice.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/ DNY59&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/article/hvac-under-strain-as-el-ni-o-bites-656284894</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/article/hvac-under-strain-as-el-ni-o-bites-656284894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supermarket, warehouse and airport recruited for grid stabilisation project</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.agl.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;AGL&lt;/a&gt; has received $864,000 in funding from the Australian Renewable Energy Agency (&lt;a href="https://arena.gov.au/" target="_blank"&gt;ARENA&lt;/a&gt;) to develop and trial a price intensity forecasting tool that will support demand flexibility in the commercial and industrial sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARENA’s report, &lt;a href="https://arena.gov.au/knowledge-bank/the-role-of-flexible-demand-in-australias-energy-future/" target="_blank"&gt;The Role of Flexible Demand in Australia’s Energy Future&lt;/a&gt;, identified potential sources of demand flexibility that included new retail and commercial products such as energy-as-a-service, dynamic tariffs and demand-based market hedges, as well as electrification and control of commercial and industrial loads such as heat pumps, electric furnaces and thermal storage for cold stores and commercial property. AGL’s two-year project will put these sources of demand flexibility to the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $1.78 million project will initially recruit four Melbourne-based customer sites and utilise their price intensity forecasts to manage energy loads, freeing up around 25 MW of combined flexible load which can be used to ease pressure on the energy grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melbourne Airport, a warehouse and logistics company, a tier 1 supermarket chain and a water utility company are the sites selected for the project, representing key addressable industries of cold stores, supermarkets, water treatment and airport market segments. Together, these sites offer up a potential of 385 MW in load management across the National Electricity Market (NEM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unlocking flexible demand at commercial and industrial sites can free up electricity capacity at times of high demand and consume electricity when renewable electricity is abundant. This will help us create a truly smart, adaptable and efficient energy grid,” said ARENA CEO Darren Miller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Through AGL’s trial, the development of the price intensity forecasting tool will help to reduce barriers for industry to take up renewable energy, shifting usage to times which can lower power bills and reduce strain on the grid. We look forward to seeing the end results of the project which will assist other sectors in their own energy transition.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AGL’s tool will work by developing a pre-dispatch forecast of solar and wind generation, and thermal generator availability to produce 30-minute interval price forecasts for the next seven days. The customer sites’ process management system will plan the operation of their energy usage based on the forecast by moving load in or out of the 30-minute blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Flexible demand projects like this enable AGL to develop our technological expertise in harnessing renewable energy while also exploring novel ways to reduce customer costs,” said AGL Chief Customer Officer Jo Egan. “We look forward to sharing the knowledge of the trial with ARENA and our participating partners to optimise the transition to renewable energy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project will begin with development of the software and hardware in early 2024, with findings to be shared mid-2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Tempura&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/supermarket-warehouse-and-airport-recruited-for-grid-stabilisation-project-98380913</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/supermarket-warehouse-and-airport-recruited-for-grid-stabilisation-project-98380913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Govt to fund 32 GW of renewable energy</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a move welcomed by climate advocacy groups, the federal government has announced a significant expansion of its existing Capacity Investment Scheme (CIS) and the National Energy Transformation Partnership (NETP), in conjunction with the states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This expansion will take the CIS from its current pilot stage to a total of 32 GW nationally, comprising 9 GW of dispatchable capacity and 23 GW of variable capacity. This is equivalent to about half the current National Electricity Market (NEM) with its nearly 11 million customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through boosting available power in the energy grid, the investment aims to deliver a long-term, reliable, affordable and low-emissions energy system as Australia’s grid makes the shift to more renewables. This follows 24 coal plants with a total capacity of 26.7 GW having announced their closure dates during the term of the previous government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This plan for renewable energy is a game changer,” said &lt;a href="https://www.solutionsforaustralia.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Solutions for Climate Australia&lt;/a&gt; Director Dr Barry Traill. “It shows that the Albanese government is taking its commitment to replace unreliable coal and gas with renewable energy seriously.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.climatecouncil.org.au/about/" target="_blank"&gt;Climate Council&lt;/a&gt; said the investment would double the amount of renewable energy in Australia’s grid, and that the extra renewable power is equivalent to more than 10 times the capacity of the ailing Eraring coal-fired power station, Australia’s largest power station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This investment can unlock the additional energy capacity needed to ensure that coal-fired clunkers like Eraring close on schedule. The NSW Government and others right around the country should grab it with both hands,” said Dr Jennifer Rayner, Head of Advocacy at the Climate Council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first CIS pilot auction has taken place in New South Wales, with the successful projects to deliver more than 1 GW of dispatchable power across the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;States will be asked to work with the Commonwealth to ensure renewables are rolled out and reliability is enhanced through objective benchmarks, an orderly transition and potential strategic reserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around half of the capacity offered under the expanded CIS (18 of 32 GW) will be subject to NETP agreements. Capacity may be re-allocated from any jurisdictions that don’t make agreements to those that do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barriers to renewable investment, such as workforce and supply chain constraints, will also be taken into consideration, the government said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Agreements between the federal and state governments under the National Energy Transformation Partnership will be a great way to ensure all governments are pulling in the same direction: adding cheaper, cleaner and more reliable solar and wind energy as quickly as possible,” Rayner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Thurtell&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/govt-to-fund-32-gw-of-renewable-energy-74491722</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/govt-to-fund-32-gw-of-renewable-energy-74491722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record number of apprentices to tackle energy transition</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a bid to ready its workforce for Australia’s energy transition, &lt;a href="https://ampcontrolgroup.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Ampcontrol&lt;/a&gt; has taken on what it describes as a record number of 55 new apprentices, who will start work in 2024 across NSW, Qld and WA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company offers multiple career pathways across its Australian operations, including its Apprentice and Graduate Program, encouraging students to pursue careers in science, technology, engineering and mathematics (STEM) fields. In 2024, it will expand its established career pathway programs to include cadetships and school-based apprenticeships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 55 apprentices starting in 2024, 38 are starting in NSW, nine in Queensland and eight in WA. The types of apprentices employed are electrical, fabrication, mechanical fitting and machining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ampcontrol said its apprentice and graduate programs give students the opportunity to experience multiple aspects of a business, allowing them to participate in innovative projects that test their problem-solving skills early on in their careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been involved in standalone power systems integrated with hydrogen technology and large-scale renewable projects,” said Alex Stamenkovski, Ampcontrol Graduate Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At Ampcontrol, we work at the forefront of the electrification of Australian mining, which will only grow as mines move away from diesel. The graduate program has provided me with valuable opportunities to apply my skills in renewable energy in a rewarding and meaningful way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leigh Stefanszyn, Executive General Manager – People and Engagement, acknowledged the need for more tradespeople to be trained to respond to industry needs for Australia to head into a clean energy environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is estimated over the next seven years, we will be upwards of 44,000 tradespeople short to help us on the clean energy path that we’re currently on,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Coming into Ampcontrol Career Pathway Programs now is vitally important to prepare those skills for the next five to seven years and beyond.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image caption: Ampcontrol CEO Rod Henderson (L) and Apprentice Trainee Coordinator Andrew van Der Stelt with 2024 apprentices. Image courtesy of Ampcontrol.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/record-number-of-apprentices-to-tackle-energy-transition-1219593400</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/record-number-of-apprentices-to-tackle-energy-transition-1219593400</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NT to receive $80 million data centre</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Development has begun on the $80 million D1 Darwin data centre facility, which is scheduled for completion and launch in June 2024. Built by technology company &lt;a href="https://www.nextdc.com/" target="_blank"&gt;NEXTDC&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with &lt;a href="https://www.kapitolgroup.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Kapitol Group&lt;/a&gt;, D1 Darwin should create more than 200 jobs in the region for the duration of construction and into the daily operation of the facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As our flagship data centre in NT, D1 Darwin forms part of NEXTDC’s strategy to leverage the next frontier of edge computing and for the region, it is a big step towards national digital equity,” said NEXTDC CEO Craig Scroggie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Its proximity to Darwin’s CBD and direct access to the major submarine cable infrastructure means legacy industries such as mining and resources alongside the emerging defence sector can have real-time responsiveness to operational and mission-critical needs, fully capturing the value of emerging technologies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEXTDC is partnering with the Northern Territory Government to accelerate the region’s economic development through investment in technological infrastructure and advancements. With its projected capacity of 8 MW, D1 Darwin will contribute to the NT’s Digital Territory Action Plan by providing crucial infrastructure for the state’s growing digital industry — and, more broadly, contributing to its $40bn 2030 economic outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chief Minister of the Northern Territory Natasha Fyles said that getting the construction of D1 Darwin underway was an exciting step for the future of NT’s digital economy, enabling many organisations in the region to activate their digital transformation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Offering uninterrupted critical connectivity and cloud services to Northern Territory businesses and government will significantly boost the capability of what they are offering to their customers and stakeholders,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Australian fibre and network solutions provider &lt;a href="https://www.vocus.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Vocus&lt;/a&gt; is also partnering with NEXTDC at the D1 facility, integrating its Terabit Territory fibre network within the data centre to connect secure, high-capacity networks to the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“D1 Darwin is a critical infrastructure facility which will play an integral role in Vocus’s network investments — supporting all levels of government as well as enterprise customers in the resources sector,” said Vocus CEO Ellie Sweeney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“D1 Darwin will establish a major data centre in Australia’s north connecting to Vocus’s new Darwin–Jakarta–Singapore Cable submarine system, which lands our secure digital infrastructure in Perth, Port Hedland, Darwin and South-East Asia,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details about D1 Darwin, visit: &lt;a href="https://www.nextdc.com/data-centres/darwin-data-centres" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.nextdc.com/data-centres/darwin-data-centres&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/gorodenkoff&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/news/nt-to-receive-80-million-data-centre-1554942444</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/news/nt-to-receive-80-million-data-centre-1554942444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring AI&amp;#39;s role in net zero</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.siemens.com/au/en.html" target="_blank"&gt;Siemens Australia&lt;/a&gt; is collaborating with &lt;a href="https://www.swinburne.edu.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Swinburne University of Technology&lt;/a&gt; in a cross-country project designed to explore the responsible use of AI in achieving net zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project aims to enable utility providers, regulators, local governments and businesses to incorporate ethical principles into AI governance for a smooth transition to net zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Led by Swinburne and funded by the Australian Department for Foreign Affairs and Trade under the Australia–India Cyber and Critical Technology Partnership (AICCTP), the project is titled ‘Responsible AI for Net Zero — An Australia and India Collaborative Approach towards Practice, Governance and Ethics in Energy Futures’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re at a pivotal moment of time where AI is impacting every aspect of our lives,” said Siemens Australia and New Zealand CEO Peter Halliday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Net zero is a tremendous target and we need to consider how we embrace AI to accelerate the changes needed across industry, infrastructure and energy sectors to meet challenging climate targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Innovation through digitalisation is the key to addressing all these challenges, especially if Australia aims to reduce global emissions beyond the 1% we’re responsible for,” Halliday said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project focuses on three key pillars:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Establishing current ethical principles for AI adoption in the energy sector.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Identifying key ethical issues shaping the use of AI in the development of smart energy systems for achieving net zero.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Recommending comprehensive guidelines for translating ethical principles into AI energy governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Associate Professor Mehdi Seyedmahmoudian, Director of the &lt;a href="https://www.swinburne.edu.au/research/platforms-initiatives/siemens-swinburne-energy-transition-hub/" target="_blank"&gt;Siemens Swinburne Energy Transition Hub&lt;/a&gt;, emphasised that it was paramount to ensure the responsible and ethical use of data while developing the AI-driven tools within advanced energy systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This project showcases how we collaborate with other leading institutions and industries, to ensure we provide smarter and safer energy systems for our communities,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other collaborators on the project include Indian Institute of Technology Palakkad (IIT Palakkad), Indian Institute of Technology Madras (IIT Madras) and Maxbyte Technologies Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“AI is key in delivering net zero by supporting sustainable and green energy systems,” said Professor Prem Prakash Jayaraman, Director of Swinburne’s &lt;a href="https://www.swinburne.edu.au/research/platforms-initiatives/factory-of-the-future/" target="_blank"&gt;Factory of the Future&lt;/a&gt; and Digital Innovation Lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This project is particularly important as it takes a global approach, bringing together industries, government and university to tackle the challenge of using AI responsibly to deliver our net zero commitments.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/PhonlamaiPhoto&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/news/exploring-ai-s-role-in-net-zero-677993217</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/news/exploring-ai-s-role-in-net-zero-677993217</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perth prepares for first electric bus fleet</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Perth will soon launch its first electric bus fleet thanks to the installation of charging infrastructure at a major bus station in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jetcharge.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;JET Charge Pty Ltd&lt;/a&gt; has been awarded a contract to design, supply, install and commission the electric bus charging infrastructure at Elizabeth Quay bus station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $1.65 million contract will see 18 electric bus charging dispensers and the associated charging management system and software installed at the bus station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installed, the charging infrastructure will support the operation of 18 electric Perth CAT buses and will make Elizabeth Quay the first bus station in WA capable of supporting electric buses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on the infrastructure will begin in early 2024, with the first electric Perth CAT bus to begin services by the middle of next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All 18 electric Perth CAT buses will be in operation by mid-2025, with each electric bus able to travel about 330 kilometres on a single charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation of the new electric charging infrastructure is part of a $250 million joint initiative between the Australian and Western Australian Governments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our governments are focused on transitioning our bus fleet to fully electric and this is a really important step in making that a reality,” said Western Australian Transport Minister Rita Saffioti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re investing in new electric buses, but also ensuring we have the infrastructure in place to support those electric buses and delivering the facilities so we can manufacture and build the buses right here in Western Australia.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative ultimately aims to deliver 130 new electric buses, charging infrastructure at key depots and major upgrades to manufacturing facilities to support the production of electric buses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delivery of a new fleet of electric buses comes after a trial of four electric buses began in the Joondalup area in February last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/delectus&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/perth-prepares-for-first-electric-bus-fleet-773368446</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/perth-prepares-for-first-electric-bus-fleet-773368446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are virtual site visits the key to a net zero construction sector?</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Almost all (95%) construction, engineering and property (CEP) business leaders in Australia say that decarbonisation and emissions reduction is central to their organisation’s overall sustainability agenda, compared to just 86% of those from all other sectors, according to research commissioned by aerial technology company &lt;a href="https://www.nearmap.com/au/en?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;amp;utm_campaign=24-Q2-AU-Commercial%20-Sustainability-Campaign-White%20paper-Media%20release&amp;amp;sfc=7019g0000009ut9AAA" target="_blank"&gt;Nearmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The construction industry alone is one of Australia’s largest industries, responsible for approximately &lt;a href="https://www.trade.gov/country-commercial-guides/australia-building-construction" target="_blank"&gt;9% of the country’s GDP&lt;/a&gt;. However, the built environment sector has a disproportionate amount of greenhouse emissions — reportedly being responsible for &lt;a href="https://wwf.org.au/blogs/new-industry-alliance-set-to-transform-embodied-carbon-emissions-in-australian-construction-and-infrastructure-industry/" target="_blank"&gt;one-quarter&lt;/a&gt; of Australia’s emissions. This presents a significant opportunity for the industry to lead in achieving net zero carbon for Australian buildings, and it could be a reality by 2040, &lt;a href="https://newsroom.unsw.edu.au/news/art-architecture-design/net-zero-australias-built-environment-possible-2040" target="_blank"&gt;as laid out in a guide&lt;/a&gt; produced by UNSW Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Nearmap, location intelligence technology tools that enable virtual site visits have the potential to help reduce carbon emissions, eg, cutting just two physical site visits each day that would normally require one hour of travel time can have a significant impact. Nearmap estimates that companies can potentially reduce up to 5280 kg of carbon emissions and save up to AU$34,100 a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company’s research found that while 93% of CEP leaders believe technologies such as aerial imagery and geospatial analytics can help reduce carbon emissions and achieve sustainability goals, the reported usage of technology across the sector is currently only 75%. Barriers to adoption include limited awareness and understanding of available technologies (60%); lack of technology tools and solutions (57%); and financial constraints (56%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technologies deemed most useful by leaders from the CEP sector in helping reduce carbon emissions or achieving sustainability goals were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Environmental impact assessment and monitoring tools (57%).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Geospatial analytics and insights powered by AI (49%).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Advanced measurement and measurement tools (47%).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;High-resolution aerial imagery of areas across Australia (45%).&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is encouraging to see that 93% of CEP business leaders believe technology can help reduce emissions — particularly as there has long been a misconception that deep technical or geospatial knowledge is needed to implement solutions that can help companies meet decarbonisation goals,” said Daniel Paull, Executive Vice President and General Manager, Nearmap Australia and New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The power of making simple changes like switching to virtual site visits should not be underestimated — understanding this will help overcome the barriers to adoption identified by the research and lift usage of technologies that can help contribute to a greener future for all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearmap’s white paper ‘Decarbonising Australia’s Built World with Technology’ can be accessed &lt;a href="https://view.nearmap.com/Commercial-Decarbonisation-WhitePaper.html?utm_campaign=24-Q2-AU-Commercial%20-Sustainability-Campaign-White%20paper-Media%20release&amp;amp;utm_source=PR&amp;amp;utm_medium=Media%20release&amp;amp;utm_content=&amp;amp;sfc=7019g0000009ut9AAA" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/ipopba&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/article/are-virtual-site-visits-the-key-to-a-net-zero-construction-sector--1658187486</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/article/are-virtual-site-visits-the-key-to-a-net-zero-construction-sector--1658187486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$708m upgrade to WA network</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;WA’s Cook government has announced &lt;a href="https://www.westernpower.com.au/resources-education/network-improvements/network-upgrade-projects/decarbonisation-work/" target="_blank"&gt;it will invest $708 million&lt;/a&gt; in upgrading the state’s transmission infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upgrades will enable large-scale renewable energy generation to connect to the grid, for both domestic use and to facilitate new industries like renewable hydrogen. With modelling indicating that a tenfold increase in renewable generation may be needed to meet future low-emissions electricity demand, strengthening the northern transmission network is critical, the government said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This government understands the need for tangible actions and delivery of infrastructure to support decarbonisation of industry in the South West,” said Energy Minister Bill Johnston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By upgrading the northern network, we can increase the output of existing wind generation as well as connect around a gigawatt of new wind and solar generation capacity, which is almost double the amount of large-scale renewables currently connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Working closely with industry and communities, we can ensure our main network delivers a reliable supply of low-emissions electricity to meet our collective decarbonisation goals.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$575 million will go towards increasing the capacity of the network’s northern section, including a new 330 kV double circuit transmission line between Malaga and Pinjar, enabling massive renewable energy generation projects in the Mid-West to connect to the grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A further $133 million will be invested towards planning for new lines, reinforcements and upgrades around key industrial areas including Kwinana and Collie, as well as upgrades between Geraldton and Perth to support development at Oakajee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the largest investment in transmission infrastructure in WA in more than 10 years and is an important step on the transformation of our main electricity grid,” said Premier Roger Cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Growing our electricity network is critical to unlocking our renewable energy potential — to reduce our own emissions, and to help countries across the region reduce theirs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government will establish a new body, PoweringWA, to coordinate the delivery of new electricity infrastructure at the pace needed for decarbonisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located within the Department of Energy, Mines, Industry Regulation and Safety, PoweringWA will coordinate the build of transmission, renewable generation and storage infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be responsible for planning, community consultation, industry liaison and project management, ensuring appropriate consideration is given to environmental, cultural and social issues, while delivering a reliable and low-emissions electricity supply for all users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/georgeclerk&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/-708m-upgrade-to-wa-network-280131511</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/-708m-upgrade-to-wa-network-280131511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netatmo Outdoor Security Camera with Siren</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" src=""&gt; &lt;p&gt;With a powerful 105-decibel alarm, the Netatmo Outdoor Security Camera with Siren can distinguish between a person, animal and vehicle, and can learn to recognise the difference between harmless and suspicious movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera keeps tabs on both welcome and unwelcome visitors, package deliveries and animals coming onto the property, with homeowners receiving real-time notifications via smartphone when an unknown person or vehicle is detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images are accessible 24 hours a day from a smartphone, including night captures thanks to infrared vision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/product/netatmo-outdoor-security-camera-with-siren-1547618854</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/product/netatmo-outdoor-security-camera-with-siren-1547618854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust power grid needed for once-in-a-decade demand</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Australian Energy Market Operator (AEMO) has completed its &lt;a href="https://aemo.com.au/-/media/files/electricity/nem/system-operations/summer-operations/2023-24/2023-24-summer-readiness---overview.pdf?la=en&amp;amp;hash=6690CD3D76CBC8CE1E6731B4EB7FDB3E" target="_blank"&gt;2023–24 Summer Readiness Overview&lt;/a&gt;, outlining expected weather conditions, energy system preparations and contingencies to maintain electricity reliability in Australia’s main power systems this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AEMO works on an ongoing basis with generation and transmission businesses, federal and state governments, and key agencies to manage risks to the National Electricity Market (NEM) that serves the eastern and south-eastern regions of Australia, and the Western Australian South West Interconnected System (SWIS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our extensive planning with industry, governments and network businesses aims to have enough generation and transmission available year-round to meet consumers’ electricity needs,” said AEMO Executive General Manager Operations Michael Gatt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This year’s summer forecast is for hot and dry El Niño conditions, increasing the risk of bushfires and extreme heat, which could see electricity demand reach a 1-in-10-year high across the eastern states and in Western Australia.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August, AEMO identified periods when electricity reliability thresholds were at risk in the &lt;a href="https://aemo.com.au/-/media/files/electricity/nem/planning_and_forecasting/nem_esoo/2023/2023-electricity-statement-of-opportunities.pdf?la=en&amp;amp;hash=D8CC2D9AC8D9F353194C9DD117095FB4" target="_blank"&gt;NEM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://aemo.com.au/-/media/files/electricity/wem/planning_and_forecasting/esoo/2023/2023-wholesale-electricity-market-electricity-statement-of-opportunities-wem-esoo.pdf?la=en&amp;amp;hash=E05FBD7B0EEF023895B6360D590BAE26" target="_blank"&gt;SWIS&lt;/a&gt; this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The entire industry has been focusing and continues to focus on managing possible risks for the summer ahead, particularly during high demand periods,” Gatt said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To mitigate such risks, AEMO is in the process of procuring additional reserves through the Interim Reliability Reserve and Reliability and Emergency Reserve Trader (RERT) mechanisms in the NEM. In Western Australia, it is tendering for reserves through the Supplementary Reserve Capacity mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to last summer in the NEM, an average 1500 MW of scheduled generation and an extra 2000 MW of generation capacity from new wind and solar projects will be available this summer. In the WEM, nearly 50 MW of extra scheduled generation is expected to be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, an expert from RMIT has cautioned that more measures need to be put into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“According to the Australian Energy Market Operator we are in a much better position than last year due to additional wind and solar capacity added to the system,” said Associate Professor Lasantha Meegahapola from the university’s &lt;a href="https://www.rmit.edu.au/about/schools-colleges/engineering/research/research-areas/electrical-and-biomedical-engineering" target="_blank"&gt;Electrical and Biomedical Engineering&lt;/a&gt; department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“However, the amount of energy produced by these renewable power sources is significantly lower compared to traditional generators, since they can only produce power when there’s wind and sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Relying too much on these generation sources is too risky without a large storage capacity built into the network.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While having additional wind and solar power should reduce the risk of blackouts in the coming hot summer, blackout risk cannot be ruled out, Meegahapola said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The operator needs careful planning to optimally utilise the additional wind and solar generators while coordinating with the energy storage systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As we move towards a low-carbon power grid, the network requires more storage capacity to firm the output of the wind and solar energy generators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meegahapola, who conducts research into renewable power generation, power system stability and microgrids, said community or neighbourhood batteries and microgrids should also form part of the mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These solutions would help us construct a more robust power grid that can cope with extreme weather conditions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to its collaboration with industry, governments and network businesses to identify and plan for relevant summer risk scenarios, AEMO said it had undertaken extensive briefings and emergency exercises to test contingency plans and communication processes ahead of summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Wirestock&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/article/robust-power-grid-needed-for-once-in-a-decade-demand-734679148</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/article/robust-power-grid-needed-for-once-in-a-decade-demand-734679148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Views sought on First Nations Clean Energy Strategy</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The federal government has opened consultation on the focus areas for Australia’s First Nations Clean Energy Strategy. Views are invited on how to enable First Nations peoples to lead and benefit from the clean energy transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The First Nations Clean Energy Strategy aims to ensure First Nations peoples can meaningfully participate in and benefit from Australia’s clean energy transformation; access affordable and reliable renewable energy; and lead and be equal partners in the energy transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strategy is being developed with respect for Indigenous Australians’ strong local and cultural knowledge, including management of Country. It will be formulated in partnership with First Nations peoples, organisations and communities across Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government will also hold a series of roundtables with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;representatives from First Nations communities&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Traditional Owners&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;prescribed body corporates&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;land councils&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;industry, government, law and policy experts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;state and territory governments.&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback received through the consultation, roundtables and regional conversations will inform the development of the First Nations Clean Energy Strategy, which will be delivered by mid-2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Thurtell&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/views-sought-on-first-nations-clean-energy-strategy-1054948586</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/views-sought-on-first-nations-clean-energy-strategy-1054948586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jemena takes action on bushfire risk</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Energy company &lt;a href="https://jemena.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Jemena&lt;/a&gt; has partnered with engineering service provider &lt;a href="https://www.zinfra.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Zinfra&lt;/a&gt; on an extensive work program that aims to reduce the risk of powerline-related bushfires in Melbourne’s north-west.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program involved commissioning Rapid Earth Fault Current Limiter (REFCL) technology in areas at increased risk of bushfire in the Jemena electricity network geographic area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REFCLs are a type of electronic equipment designed to detect when one line out of a three-phase powerline has fallen to the ground, and reduce line voltage on the fallen line. The technology simultaneously boosts the voltage on the remaining overhead powerlines in service, ensuring that power can be maintained to homes and businesses while reducing the risk of a fire igniting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The REFCL program was developed and mandated across Victoria as an outcome of the 2009 Black Saturday Bushfire Royal Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jemena Network Investment and Delivery Manager David Speairs said the work program represented a $50 million investment from Jemena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Extensive work was undertaken to ensure that REFCL technology could operate safely on our electricity network. We augmented our Coolaroo Zone Substation to accommodate the REFCL equipment, which included installation of a new control building, as well as moving strategic sections of our overhead powerlines underground to further mitigate bushfire risk.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jemena and Zinfra have worked together on a number of past projects, and maintain a strong relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Zinfra has previously undertaken REFCL works across the AusNet network, proving our capability in delivering a project of this kind,” said Zinfra Program Manager Nic Stringer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Safety — that of our people, the community and the environment — was a focus throughout the REFCL program for both Zinfra and Jemena,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commissioning of the REFCL technology and receiving of the Zone Substation compliance certificate from Energy Safe Victoria was the culmination of two years of planning and work in the field, Speairs said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The completion of the project will ensure communities in north-west Melbourne will have a more secure power supply, and bushfire risks will be greatly reduced,” he concluded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href="https://jemena.com.au/electricity/safety/storms,-bushfires-and-summer-safety" target="_blank"&gt;https://jemena.com.au/electricity/safety/storms,-bushfires-and-summer-safety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Byronsdad&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/jemena-takes-action-on-bushfire-risk-1061352634</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/jemena-takes-action-on-bushfire-risk-1061352634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVs and rooftop solar could boost SA&amp;#39;s future grid</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;While more large-scale generation and transmission is needed to support Australia’s transition to renewables, there is not enough attention being paid to the massive opportunity presented by customer energy resources embedded in the distribution network. This was the view presented by &lt;a href="https://www.sapowernetworks.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;SA Power Networks&lt;/a&gt; CEO Andrew Bills at the recent Future Energy Conference, which took place from 8–9 November at Tonsley Innovation District in South Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bills said that in South Australia there are now more than 37% of customers with solar, forming a total installed capacity of almost 2.2 GW — more than enough to regularly meet the state’s electricity needs in the middle of mild sunny days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“South Australia already is a world leader with 350,000 rooftop solar installations, more than 35,000 batteries and significant potential that will be unleashed by electric vehicles as we electrify transport,” Bills said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bills described electric vehicles as the next big thing to influence energy outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They have batteries 3–10 times the storage capacity of home batteries and are a great opportunity to utilise the state’s abundance of renewable energy,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Emerging technologies like smart two-way chargers for EVs also have real potential to slash energy costs for consumers. We can kill two birds with one stone when it comes to electric vehicles, with cheaper transport and cheaper energy for households.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An average household could halve its total energy spend from about $4500 to about $2400 per annum by switching to an EV, according to Bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the electricity network set to become the primary ‘fuel’ source for transport, Bills said the good news is that there was enough spare capacity in the electricity distribution network to substantially meet demand from EVs and avoid the need for larger-scale network upgrades ultimately paid by consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The network has tremendous spare capacity outside peak times. We can unlock this capacity and create significant value for customers and the community by encouraging ‘flexibility’ in energy use. If we get it right, we can significantly increase network asset utilisation and help lower energy costs for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The solution is a mix of incentivising as much electricity use as possible into daylight hours to take advantage of the state’s abundant, and still-expanding, low-cost rooftop solar energy; utilising smart energy management systems that look for the best outcome for customers and respond to network signals; and ensuring vehicle charging is spread across the day and week,” Bills concluded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/SimonSkafar&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/evs-and-rooftop-solar-could-boost-sa-s-future-grid-1386222754</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/evs-and-rooftop-solar-could-boost-sa-s-future-grid-1386222754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiring error causes electric shocks for homeowner</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;A WA court has heard that a homeowner in Bridgetown in the state’s south-west received multiple electric shocks caused by a dangerous wiring error that a Manjimup electrician failed to detect. The electrician and an apprentice under his supervision had attended the Bridgetown property in February 2022 to replace a private power pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the work, overhead sub-mains cables were connected to the house from a mains connection box on the new pole. The apprentice carried out the wiring work in the mains connection box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later, the property owner contacted Western Power to report receiving electric shocks from the oven and shower. An inspection by Western Power revealed the active and neutral conductors were transposed at the mains connection box, causing earthed metal components in the house to become live with electricity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The supervising electrician was found to have breached WA’s Electricity (Licensing) Regulations 1991 by not visually inspecting the electrical installation work to verify its compliance with wiring rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the supervising electrical worker, he was responsible for inspecting the apprentice’s wiring. A visual check would have clearly identified the transposed active and neutral conductors, the court was told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 26 October 2023 at Manjimup Magistrates Court, Magistrate Michelle Harries ordered the electrician to pay a $5000 fine as well as costs of $537.15. Harries noted the electrician’s early guilty plea, remorse and lack of prior misconduct, but emphasised the seriousness of the offence, which had potentially life-threatening consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WA’s Director of Energy Safety, Saj Abdoolakhan, said that the property owner was extremely lucky to have avoided a serious or even fatal injury, and that a simple visual check would have immediately revealed the wiring error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This case is a clear example of why checks and tests of all electrical installing work are mandatory. There is no place for complacency when the stakes are so high,” Abdoolakhan said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is also a timely reminder to electrical contractors and supervising electrical workers about their responsibilities for apprentices.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the Building and Energy &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.wa.gov.au/taxonomy/term/1" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; for more information on &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.wa.gov.au/energysafety/electric-shocks-and-reporting" target="_blank"&gt;shock and tingles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.wa.gov.au/building-and-energy/private-power-poles-and-lines-are-your-responsibility" target="_blank"&gt;private power poles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.wa.gov.au/building-and-energy/safe-working-guidelines-and-effective-supervision-electrical-apprentices" target="_blank"&gt;electrical apprentices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/ Pollyana Ventura&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/wiring-error-causes-electric-shocks-for-homeowner-957459800</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/wiring-error-causes-electric-shocks-for-homeowner-957459800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nbn increases access to smart city techology</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nbnco.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;NBN Co&lt;/a&gt; will be rolling out its Smart Places technology across Australia, following a series of trials at strategic locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wholesale product enables retail service providers and developers to make use of outdoor smart devices through a miniature, ruggedised, reverse-powered network connection that operates via nbn fibre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart devices powered by outdoor fibre connections include IoT solutions such as smart traffic lights and smart poles; CCTV monitoring of highways, waterways and coastlines; and sustainability solutions in developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7118445259335888896" target="_blank"&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; commissioned by nbn from International Data Corporation (IDC) has shown a shift across industries, which are increasingly adopting outdoor smart devices to drive innovation, sustainability and efficiency. Today’s estimated 71,000 nbn outdoor connections is expected to grow to more than 319,000 by the end of the decade.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a game changer for governments, developers, utilities and transport industries — it gives them the power of fibre just about anywhere,” said Head of nbn New Developments Andrew Walsh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We trialled nbn Smart Places right across the country in dozens of locations and it’s been so successful it’s now available throughout Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The device is only small, but its impact is massive — it can provide the connectivity to monitor and control traffic light signals [and] digital billboards, provide Wi-Fi in public places, and provide real-time high-definition CCTV coverage,” Walsh said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first places to trial the technology was the sustainable residential community Brabham Estate in Perth, Walsh said. Smart communities developer Peet used nbn Smart Places to deliver, via retail providers, high-performance Wi-Fi to the Brabham Estate community park, allowing connectivity, smart benches with phone chargers and a weather station that decides when to mow the lawns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As we see a rapid increase in the planning and development of smart communities, towns, suburbs, precincts and buildings, we know communities and businesses are seeking the best connectivity,” Walsh said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A smart place (or smart cities as they’re often known) integrates technology into the surrounding built or natural environment to increase livability, sustainability and productivity for residents and businesses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;1. IDC Spotlight Paper, commissioned by nbn: ‘Fibre Based Non-Premises Connectivity Allows Success in High Bandwidth IOT Use Cases’.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/AerialPerspective Works&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/news/nbn-increases-access-to-smart-city-techology-34411915</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/news/nbn-increases-access-to-smart-city-techology-34411915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to upgrade your industrial operations for maximum profitability</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;
	&lt;span style="background-color: initial;"&gt;Learn how to maximise your industrial potential leveraging advanced PLCs. Discover how to harness the power of data-driven operations for higher efficiency, quality and market success.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Examine six essential criteria that you need to consider to ensure that you choose the right PLC solution for your upgrade.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:28:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/white-paper/how-to-upgrade-your-industrial-operations-for-maximum-profitability-837462016</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/white-paper/how-to-upgrade-your-industrial-operations-for-maximum-profitability-837462016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EPIC DATA FFC connectors for GOF fibre-optic cables</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Digitalisation in the industry is increasing rapidly. Data volumes are also rising quickly. A futureproof communication infrastructure in factories with glass fibre cables is therefore essential. Recent additions to Treotham’s range include the site-assembly EPIC DATA FFC-LC connector and EPIC DATA FFC-SC connector for GOF fibre-optic cables. These connectors simplify the establishment of a pluggable glass fibre connection and offer a high level of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;181 zettabytes (the number 181 followed by 21 zeros) is the prediction for the amount of digital data generated worldwide by 2025. How can this gigantic amount of data be transferred in a quick and stable manner? The solution is light, namely via fibre-optic, cables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fibre-optic cables transport data at up to 40 Gbps over different wavelengths simultaneously and are resistant to electromagnetic interference. As a result, there is no signal interference and no data loss. Furthermore, considerably longer installation lengths are possible than copper. Glass fibre cables can easily achieve 40 Gbps over 40 km at 1550 nm. This enables synchronised real-time capability and, therefore, efficient production through fast communication, even at very high data transmission rates such as those found in digital twins, robot AI and Industry 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/hot-product/epic-data-ffc-connectors-for-gof-fibre-optic-cables-1130495221</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/hot-product/epic-data-ffc-connectors-for-gof-fibre-optic-cables-1130495221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How decarbonisation is affecting coal power workers</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, approximately one-third of Australia’s coal-fired power stations closed, with more expected in coming years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on individual wage micro-data of workers in the coal-fired power sector, the non-partisan economic research institute &lt;a href="https://e61.in/" target="_blank"&gt;e61&lt;/a&gt; investigated how these workers, and by extension their families, are being impacted by power station closures. It found that former coal-fired power station workers experience a greater drop in wages than other industries following redundancy, earning 69% less compared to 43% less for those in other sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E61 analyst and paper co-author Elyse Dwyer said that while it was common to see wages decrease when a worker is made redundant, the dip seen among ex-coal energy workers is substantially larger than that observed in other industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After four years, coal-fired power plant workers earned around 50% less than their pre-redundancy earnings, compared to 29% for all other workers, with lower-skilled workers seeing the greatest relative decrease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s a variety of factors that may cause this, such as many coal-industry workers being located in regional areas without abundant alternatives for high-wage jobs, but other crucial factors are the age of the workers being made redundant and the potential non-transferability of skills,” Dwyer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Dan Andrews, e61’s Head of Research and Policy Engagement, managing this earnings impact will be an important factor in the success of Australia’s efforts to move away from fossil fuels. “Public support for progress on our climate and net zero goals will require careful management to mitigate some of the impacts faced by these communities,” Andrews said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEO of the e61 Institute Michael Brennan added that the paper’s findings are an important first step in designing policy to support workers and communities affected by the energy transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Understanding the distinct experience of these workers — and getting at the underlying drivers of their larger earnings decline — will help inform policymakers to design and target the right interventions. There could be a need for specifically designed support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This work highlights the value of large-scale microdata in informing our understanding and potential responses to this once-in-a-generation economic transition,” Brennan said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E61’s paper, ‘At the Coalface: What Happens to Workers Displaced by Decarbonisation’, can be downloaded &lt;a href="https://e61.in/at-the-coalface-what-happens-to-workers-displaced-by-decarbonisation/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Tenedos&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/article/how-decarbonisation-is-affecting-coal-power-workers-208529643</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/article/how-decarbonisation-is-affecting-coal-power-workers-208529643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Powerline fatality leads to guilty plea</title>
      &lt;img class="img-responsive" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/80047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;An energy supplier in Queensland has pleaded guilty to a Category 2 offence for failing to ensure an overhead powerline and its supporting structures spanning farmland were safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The supplier was fined $300,000 in a decision handed down in the Rockhampton Magistrates Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site in question was a field where a power pole was kept vertical by a number of stay wires, each of which were separately attached to the ground. There were guards at the bottom of each stay wire obscuring a portion of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During an inspection of the power pole in late September 2020, corrosion was noted and given a Priority 3 rating, meaning it did not require rectification within a particular time frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten months later, employees operating a harvester were working underneath the overhead powerline when the top of the harvester either contacted or came very close to the powerline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One worker was electrocuted and died, and another five received electric shocks and were hospitalised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was found that one of two stay wires had become corroded and as a consequence broke, allowing the power pole to shift and the powerline to drop. When the pole was straightened after the incident, the powerline height over the machinery rose more than three metres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The defendant was charged with a failure to have a system of routine visual inspection of the entire length of the stay wires, including the portions covered by the guards. The energy supplier subsequently amended its inspection process to require routine inspection of stay wires underneath the stay guard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court heard that the defendant failed to ensure its works were electrically safe; its duty was fundamental; and its failure exposed an entire group of workers to serious risk, with a catastrophic outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magistrate recognised that the loss to the deceased’s family must be unbearable, while noting that she was not required to apportion blame. She accepted the defendant is a good corporate citizen and had expressed sincere remorse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She also took into consideration a number of significant mitigating features, including early and ongoing cooperation, and an early plea of guilty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/artisteer&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/powerline-fatality-leads-to-guilty-plea-371872606</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/powerline-fatality-leads-to-guilty-plea-371872606</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
