
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ECD (Electrical+Comms+Data) RSS Feed</title>
    <description>https://ecdonline.com.au</description>
    <link>https://ecdonline.com.au</link>
    <item>
      <title>Funding boost for ultra-low-cost solar</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79619/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arena.gov.au/" target="_blank"&gt;ARENA&lt;/a&gt; has invested $11 million in new technology that has the potential to accelerate ultra-low-cost solar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipient of the funding is Australian solar technology company &lt;a href="https://www.sundrivesolar.com/" target="_blank"&gt;SunDrive Solar&lt;/a&gt;. Rather than using silver, the metal most commonly used when converting a bare silicon wafer into a finished solar cell, SunDrive has developed a cell metallisation technology that uses copper, a metal that is approximately 100 times cheaper and 1000 times more abundant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, silver accounts for approximately half the cost of converting a bare silicon wafer into a finished solar cell and solar manufacturing accounts for approximately 25% of the world’s annual industrial silver consumption. The use of copper instead could help the world to rapidly scale up solar manufacturing and support meeting net zero commitments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology also has environmental benefits as copper is easier to recycle and is less carbon intensive in the manufacturing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solar PV and wind are already recognised as the lowest-cost form of generation in Australia today; however, further cost reductions are required to optimise Australia’s transition to renewable electricity and to enable future industries such as renewable hydrogen and low-emissions metals. For this reason, ARENA has a strategic priority to enable ultra-low-cost solar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To make ultra-low-cost solar a reality, it is crucial that our scientists and researchers keep innovating and improving solar cells and module design,” said ARENA CEO Darren Miller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“SunDrive’s technology that replaces silver with copper is a potential game changer and highlights why now is the time to invest in technologies for our future economic success.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SunDrive is aiming to produce an advanced solar module at an installed price that is 20–30% cheaper than other high-efficiency solar modules on the market. The company has previously received $3 million in ARENA funding to demonstrate its copper metallisation technology to the prototype scale of 1.5 MW per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“With ARENA’s continued support, SunDrive, an Australian-founded company, has been able to compete with the world’s largest solar PV companies to produce the world’s most efficient commercial size solar cell,” said SunDrive Co-founder and CEO Vince Allen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARENA recently released a &lt;a href="https://arena.gov.au/news/the-incredible-potential-of-ultra-low-cost-solar-in-australia/" target="_blank"&gt;white paper&lt;/a&gt; on the potential of ultra-low-cost solar for Australia and the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image caption: The SunDrive cell.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/funding-boost-for-ultra-low-cost-solar-823879382</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/funding-boost-for-ultra-low-cost-solar-823879382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Govt grants to stimulate EV uptake in WA</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79620/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The WA Government has launched round two of its grants program to make EV chargers more affordable for businesses, not‑for-profits and LGAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched by Energy Minister Bill Johnston at the Cook government’s Charge Up Workplace Grants program at the EV Expo at Perth Convention and Exhibition Centre, round two includes $12.5 million to expand EV charging infrastructure throughout the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aimed at not-for-profits, small and medium businesses and local government authorities, the grants fund up to 50% of the cost of purchasing and installing an EV charger. The funding includes AC chargers and faster DC chargers ranging from 7 to 350 kW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grants are designed to maximise daytime EV charging, promote off-peak charging, support the conversion to EV fleets and, over time, stimulate a second-hand EV market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the first round, we assisted small and medium businesses, not-for-profits and local government authorities in installing EV chargers for their customers, clients and staff,” Johnston said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks to these grants, chargers are now operational in regional communities that support local tourism, small businesses and community service organisations.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About $2.4 million in grants has already been approved to install 403 chargers in 221 locations from Karratha to Albany, as well as around the Perth metropolitan area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications for round two close on 3 May 2024. For more information, visit: &lt;a href="https://www.wa.gov.au/organisation/energy-policy-wa/charge-workplace-ev-charging-grants" target="_blank"&gt;www.wa.gov.au/chargeup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/choochart choochaikupt&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/govt-grants-to-stimulate-ev-uptake-in-wa-861577481</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/govt-grants-to-stimulate-ev-uptake-in-wa-861577481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WBT YellowDuct: An Australian-Made Solution for Managing, Routing and Protecting Optical Fibre Cords</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79178/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced digital landscape, the demand for efficient and reliable data management and telecommunications infrastructure is at an all-time high. Managing and safeguarding optical fibre cords is a critical aspect of maintaining a seamless flow of data in various industries, including telecommunications exchanges, data centres, universities, hospitals, and more. That’s where WBT YellowDuct comes into play, offering an Australian-made solution that’s robust, versatile, and built to last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warren &amp;amp; Brown’s optical fibre ducting raceway, known as WBT YellowDuct, is a game-changer for those seeking a dependable system to manage, route and protect optical fibre cords within their facilities. This innovative solution is designed to ensure the utmost precision and efficiency, keeping your data centre or telecommunications infrastructure in optimal working condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warren &amp;amp; Brown’s YellowDuct system is more than just a simple ducting solution; it’s a comprehensive approach to optical fibre cable management. Here’s why it’s making waves in the industry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WBT YellowDuct is built to adapt and grow with your infrastructure. It’s the ideal choice for ensuring that your data centre remains future-proof. As technology advances, the flexibility of YellowDuct ensures that your cable management solution evolves in tandem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike some competitors in the market who use PVC, WBT YellowDuct is constructed with a special fire-retardant Low Smoke Zero Halogen (LSZH) material certified to UL94V-0 specifications. This feature is critical for safety, as LSZH materials significantly reduce toxic and corrosive gas emissions in case of a fire, minimising harm to personnel, buildings and transmission equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warren &amp;amp; Brown’s ducting raceway comprehensively covers all aspects of fibre cable management, including bend radius protection, cable access and routing, and physical protection. It’s a one-stop solution for safeguarding your optical fibre cords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YellowDuct is available in three distinct colours and seven sizes, making it easy to select the perfect fit for your facility. This diverse range includes solid wall and slotted wall options for exiting fibres. The most recent addition to the lineup is the 600 x 100 ducting raceway system, providing a maximum capacity of up to 7500 two-millimetre patch cords based on a 50% fill rate. And if your facility requires a customised solution, YellowDuct can be designed to meet your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation is a breeze with YellowDuct. Components can be joined together using two methods: slotted joiners or slotless joiners. Slotted joiners require a slotting tool only when duct length needs modification, while slotless joiners don’t require additional tools or slots, making installation quick and easy with just a screwdriver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YellowDuct components are manufactured from Noryl, a robust engineering plastic that is self-extinguishing and halogen-free. This feature ensures that in the event of a fire, gases emitted will not pose harm to personnel, buildings, or transmission equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warren &amp;amp; Brown’s commitment to quality is evident in their ISO9001 certification. YellowDuct products comply with stringent standards, including the UL2024A standard, EEU-ROHS requirements, and GR-63 Core Earthquake test compliance. Moreover, they come with a 10-year warranty, offering peace of mind to those who invest in this exceptional system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WBT YellowDuct is proudly manufactured in Australia, offering unrivalled local stock availability and an extensive product range to ensure your project stays on track, both in terms of time and budget. With local support and the backing of a globally recognised brand, you can trust in the reliability and performance of WBT YellowDuct for all your optical fibre cable management needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information and to discover how WBT YellowDuct can revolutionise your data centre or telecommunications infrastructure, visit: &lt;a href="https://wbnetworks.com.au/resources-ducting-raceway" target="_blank"&gt;https://wbnetworks.com.au/resources-ducting-raceway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to managing, routing, and protecting optical fibre cords, choose the Australian-made solution that sets the standard for quality and innovation!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/sponsored/wbt-yellowduct-an-australian-made-solution-for-managing-routing-and-protecting-optical-fibre-cords-213493967</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/sponsored/wbt-yellowduct-an-australian-made-solution-for-managing-routing-and-protecting-optical-fibre-cords-213493967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hammond Electronics UL94-V0 ABS IP54 1556 enclosures</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79261/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The flame-retardant UL94-V0 ABS IP54 1556 family of enclosures is inspired by the IP68 polycarbonate 1557 series. It features the same modern rounded corners and top face styling and introduces rectangular versions to complement the square formats derived from the 1557 series. IP54 sealed for general-purpose indoor use, the ABS material gives a lower price point than the polycarbonate used in the 1557, which is designed for installation outdoors and in aggressive environments. Self-tapping screws secure the lid to the base, for applications where repeated access is not required. There are multiple PCB mounting standoffs in both the lid and the base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four square sizes from 80 x 80 to 200 x 200 mm and three rectangular ones from 120 x 80 to 200 x 160 mm. All are available in black, RAL 7035 grey and white and there are two heights: 45 and 60 mm for the smallest size and 45 and 70 mm for the larger ones. The enclosure is suitable for desktops when fitted with the supplied feet; it can also be wall-mounted with four visible brackets or two hidden ones. Also available as an option are 2-mm-thick aluminium internal panels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/hot-product/hammond-electronics-ul94-v0-abs-ip54-1556-enclosures-1685410789</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/hot-product/hammond-electronics-ul94-v0-abs-ip54-1556-enclosures-1685410789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can you improve your data center's energy efficiency and reliability?</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79327/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With over seven million data centers around the world consuming roughly 2% of global energy demand, anything that can increase their energy efficiency will have a big impact. On average, cooling and air conditioning account for 40% of a data center’s energy consumption — making accurate heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC) measurements critical to optimizing energy use. So how do high-quality HVAC sensors save energy and improve reliability in data centers?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Increasing demand for data centers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demand for data centers is only set to increase thanks to processing-hungry applications like virtual reality, AI, and machine learning. In addition, there is a shift towards cloud computing as well as increased demand for edge data centers located near end users to reduce latency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the past decade, we have also seen the “hyperscale shift” toward large, business-critical data centers typically associated with big-data companies like Google and Amazon. While still a small percentage of the total, hyperscale data centers have increased their relative market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this means that energy consumption will increase as more data centers are brought online and current ones expand. According to estimates in a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2078-1547/6/1/117" target="_blank"&gt;study by Huawei Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the global energy consumption of IT will likely triple by 2030 compared to current levels, meaning there is a pressing need to increase data centers’ energy efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The need to become more energy efficient&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common metric used to measure the energy efficiency of data centers is Power Usage Effectiveness (PUE), which is defined as the ratio of the total energy used in the data center and the energy used by IT equipment only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the best-case scenario, PUE should be 1. This means that all energy is spent on IT equipment and the supporting infrastructure does not consume anything. In reality, the typical PUE in traditional data centers is around 2, and in hyper-scale sites around 1.2. In 2020, the global average PUE was about 1.6, which means that almost 40% of the energy used in data centers is consumed by non-IT systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The critical role of cooling and measurement&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cooling and air conditioning account for the majority of non-IT energy consumption in data centers, and cooling costs alone can easily represent 25% or more of total energy expense. This is because server racks generate a lot of excess heat which needs to be removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vaisala.com/en/expert-article/taking-heat-out-data-center" target="_blank"&gt;Taking the heat out of data center energy costs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cooling can be optimized with good design and, crucially, accurate HVAC measurements. If temperature readings are too high, it can lead to overcooling, and consequently, to excessive energy consumption; if the temperature readings are too low, it can lead to undercooling, which increases the risk of unplanned server downtime. Even a 1 °C measurement error can increase energy costs by millions of euros over a period of 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Data centers and sensors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With critical data worth billions of dollars processed and stored in a data center, power-hungry servers must always be maintained at an ideal temperature and humidity to prevent downtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing so requires several types of measurements to be made using different sensors in different locations, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;data halls and server rooms for measurement of the temperature of hot/cold aisles&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ventilation systems to measure duct temperature, humidity, and differential pressure&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;cooling systems to measure the immersion temperature and differential pressure&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-quality sensors are the key to efficiently controlling HVAC processes and ensuring stable indoor environments. The sensors that offer the best overall lifetime value are those that are accurate, provide stable long-term measurements, and are easy to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vaisala.com/en/blog/2023-01/sensor-requirements-data-centers" target="_blank"&gt;The sensor requirements of data centers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What to consider when choosing sensors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many factors to consider when choosing sensors for a data center, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is the solution flexible and does it allow for changes and expansion as the data center grows and changes in response to business needs?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Can the products be easily exchanged or upgraded when needed?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Are they quick and easy to install?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How easy are they to calibrate and maintain, and is support available from the instrument provider?&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instruments with exchangeable measurement probes or modules can be changed quickly without disturbing the measurement process. Traceable calibration certificates are important as they indicate a sensor was in perfect shape when it left the factory. It’s also an advantage if you’re able to do field-checking, calibrations, tuning, and adjustments easily on-site with tools provided by the instrument provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Investing in quality is a sensible choice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From both a reliability and cost perspective, high-quality HVAC sensors offer excellent value. The investment is modest in comparison with the benefits that accurate measurements can provide in the form of precise controls, improved energy efficiency, and as-designed indoor conditions. Want to learn more about how to reduce cooling energy costs through higher measurement accuracy? Download a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vaisala.com/en/lp/how-reduce-data-center-cooling-energy-consumption-insiders-guide" target="_blank"&gt;free insider’s guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to get the best tips on cutting data center cooling energy consumption with accurate measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vaisala.com/en/lp/how-reduce-data-center-cooling-energy-consumption-insiders-guide" target="_blank"&gt;GET THE FREE EGUIDE ON HOW TO CUT COOLING COSTS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/sponsored/how-can-you-improve-your-data-center-s-energy-efficiency-and-reliability--1243242384</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/sponsored/how-can-you-improve-your-data-center-s-energy-efficiency-and-reliability--1243242384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAPP orange tinned copper Switchboard Flex cables</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79387/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;LAPP Australia’s locally stocked range of orange tinned copper Switchboard Flex cables is designed to meet Australian standards for use in switchboard applications. The cables are suitable for switchboards and transformers, mains power distribution, burial in underground ducts or conduit, and other industrial applications. These low smoke zero halogen (LSZH) cables are designed for harsh Australian conditions. They are ultra-flexible with class 6 stranding, and a minimum bending radius of 5 times the outside diameter of the cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single-core double insulated (SDI) cables feature an operating temperature range of -25°C to 110°C and voltage rating of 600 V/1000 V. The orange outer sheath is made from R-E-110, a flexible rubber that provides UV and weather resistance, oil and chemical resistance, and flame-retardant properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conductor sizes range from 10–300 mm with outer diameters from 9–32.4 mm to suit a broad range of industrial applications, including mains power distribution and DC power feeds. Other products in the SDI range include earth tinned copper (green-yellow outer sheath, 110°C), standard bare copper (black outer sheath with bare copper, 90°C) and black tinned copper (black outer sheath with black copper, 110°C).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information: &lt;a href="https://lappaustralia.com.au/en/switchboard-flex" target="_blank"&gt;https://lappaustralia.com.au/en/switchboard-flex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/hot-product/lapp-orange-tinned-copper-switchboard-flex-cables-28784573</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/hot-product/lapp-orange-tinned-copper-switchboard-flex-cables-28784573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HiTHIUM introduces its first 5 MWh container with 46% greater energy density</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79423/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;HiTHIUM has announced a new 5 MWh container product using the standard 20-foot container structure. The more compact second generation (ESS 2.0), higher-capacity energy storage system will come pre-installed and ready to connect. It will be outfitted with 48 battery modules based on the manufacturer’s new 314Ah LFP cells, each module providing 104.5 kWh capacity and designed to meet the needs of large utility scale systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the more compact design, the 5 MWh container will provide an energy density of 117Wh/l, 46% higher than the 80Wh/l that can be seen in standard systems based on 280Ah cells. The product will also be technically compatible with most top inverter brands’ power control systems, or bidirectional inverters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new energy storage system, named the “HiTHIUM ∞Block,” comes with the company’s mature multi-level, liquid-cooling technology, which keeps cell temperature variation below 3° Celsius. Intelligent thermal management also enables the system to optimize battery power and reduce internal energy consumption. Further safety features include multi-level fault detection systems, cell monitoring, gas and smoke detection, and automated fire extinguishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HiTHIUM Head of Global Business Mizhi Zhang said: “This new 5 MWh container demonstrates that we can increase capacity and reduce LCOS, to make the energy transition genuinely affordable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Optimising cell chemistry and cooling technology for increased safety&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HiTHIUM has increased the intrinsic safety of LFP battery technology further and developed its own proprietary LFP. By means of a so-called lattice doping, the HiTHIUM team has achieved both a higher capacity and a lowered internal resistance of the cell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the new 5 MWh container based on 314Ah cells, the company delivers cabinets and containers based on its 300Ah cells, including a 4 MWh-capacity container, that also deploys the proprietary immersion liquid-cooling technology. HiTHIUM also offers the 300Ah and other LFP battery cells and liquid-cooled modules based on them to other battery storage manufacturers for use in their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the 300Ah cell HiTHIUM succeeded in reducing degradation in the first 1000 cycles to under 2%, versus the industry-typical 6%, achieved in part by modifying the anode with a technology for the active and sustained release of lithium ions. These 300Ah cells, unlike standard LFP cells, still retain their rated capacity after the first 1000 cycles. They are subsequently able to maintain this advantage, in terms of slowed degradation, over their entire lifetime. Batteries with HiTHIUM 300Ah cells can thus realise an 18% higher energy throughput during their lifetime, compared to commercially available LFP cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why LFP? Of the most commonly used lithium oxides, lithium iron phosphate is the most temperature-resistant, only becoming sensitive at approximately 220° C. Lithium-ion batteries can burn if damaged or heated to extreme temperatures, because of the sensitivity to excess temperatures of the lithium-mixed oxides used in the cell. There are lithium oxides for which so-called thermal runaway occurs at temperatures as low as ca. 180° C. Relative to other kinds, LFP cells have the greatest thermal safety reserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Inverter suppliers confirm BESS manufacturer HiTHIUM’s compatibility&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HiTHIUM has also demonstrated technical compatibility with major suppliers of power control systems (PCS) or bidirectional inverters. The PCSs are compatible with HiTHIUM’s products including its container solution systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a producer of cells, battery modules, up to full DC-side solutions, HiTHIUM teams up with PCS suppliers, working with a range of inverter-makers to confirm that the company’s battery products match well with the inverters’ important technical parameters, including DC input range and maximum short circuit current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HiTHIUM confirmed compatibility with brands including SMA, Gamesa, Delta Electronics, IngeTeam, Power Electronics, and Sineng Electric. The assessments look at PCS for both IEC and UL versions. Winfried Wahl, HiTHIUM Germany Senior Product Manager, explains: “The determination of compatibility allows customers and investors to pre-select matching PCS for their projects. Projects still of course need detailed design planning and to implement communication checks between energy management systems, BESS, and the PCS. This confirmation from major suppliers is nonetheless a crucial step, following our European market entry in June, toward delivering clear, transparent product information.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Maintaining agility even while implementing large-scale projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HiTHIUM served as the core supplier for China Southern Power Grid Company’s (CSG) first 100+ MWh-level, grid-side standalone energy storage project. Located in Meizhou City, Guangdong Province, the 140 MWh plant has an energy storage capacity of 140 MWh and deploys advanced LFP battery products from HiTHIUM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Projects like the one in Meizhou City are exactly why we built HiTHIUM’s technology and culture around customer-centricity. CSG and the province needed this project delivered quickly, safely, and with a very high quality of product,” explained Jason Wang, HiTHIUM General Manager and co-founder. “So we set up a special service team to coordinate the entire process, from manufacturing and shipping the batteries to ensuring timely project development and the professionalism of the process.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HiTHIUM also recently provided 198 MWh of battery products for a 200 MWh-capacity centralized, shared energy storage plant developed by China Resources Power Holdings. The power station is the first of this kind to operate commercially in Heze City, a metropolitan region with a population of nearly 8.3 million, and it also serves as a key energy storage project for Shandong Province, where it is located.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To meet continuing demand from large-scale energy storage projects, HiTHIUM is expanding its production capacity to 70 GWh by end of 2023. The manufacturer’s production lines are already some of the most advanced in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more, click &lt;a href="https://hithium.com/en/?utm_medium=display&amp;amp;utm_source=ecd&amp;amp;utm_campaign=web_entry_10_de&amp;amp;utm_content=enews&amp;amp;utm_term=231001" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/sponsored/hithium-introduces-its-first-5-mwh-container-with-46-greater-energy-density-926413582</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/sponsored/hithium-introduces-its-first-5-mwh-container-with-46-greater-energy-density-926413582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TestPro CV100 Multifunction Cable Certifier</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79253/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Approved by more than 35 cable manufacturers worldwide, the TestPro CV100 Multifunction Cable Certifier is purpose-built for today’s copper and fibre network infrastructure. Offering a large suite of test functions, the TestPro CV100 enables certification of cables to ISO/IEC 14763-3, AS/NZS 3080:2003 and other standards through hot swappable test adapters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It offers testing for single pair Ethernet, hybrid-powered fibre, wireless network connectivity (SSID, RSSI, Ping, Speedtest, Roaming) and network connectivity (Speedtest, SNR per link speed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CV100 platform is compatible with multiple plugin test adapters for different applications, including: copper test adapters up to CAT 8.1 and 3 GHz as standard (CAT 8.2 as an option); fibre OLTS test adapters (singlemode and multimode); OTDR test adapters; and multi-gigabit network test up to 10 Gb and PoE Test Adapter up to 90 W. It comes with project management software and regular free firmware updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features include full CAT6A certification in 6 s; network switch detail (VLANs list and usage, slot, port, device list, MACs, IPs); a locator for NEXT, RL and Shield; and MPTL and coaxial adapters. Made in Singapore with local calibration in Australia, it has a 5-year warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information: &lt;a href="https://telecomtest.com.au/product/cable-certifier-testpro-cv100-for-fiber-and-lan-cat5-5e-6-6a-8/" target="_blank"&gt;https://telecomtest.com.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/test-measurement/hot-product/testpro-cv100-multifunction-cable-certifier-747634600</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/test-measurement/hot-product/testpro-cv100-multifunction-cable-certifier-747634600</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New energy hub simulates Australia's grid</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79447/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.siemens.com/au/en.html" target="_blank"&gt;Siemens&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.swinburne.edu.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Swinburne University of Technology&lt;/a&gt; have launched a major &lt;a href="https://www.swinburne.edu.au/research/platforms-initiatives/siemens-swinburne-energy-transition-hub" target="_blank"&gt;Energy Transition Hub&lt;/a&gt; at the University’s Hawthorn campus in Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featuring some of the most advanced digital energy technology from Siemens along with the technical, R&amp;amp;D and teaching expertise of Swinburne, the $5.2 million Hub is a future energy grid laboratory accessible to students, teaching staff and industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The new Siemens Swinburne Energy Transition Hub will be working on new technologies to improve efficiency, supply, integration, storage, transport and use, as well as how we can improve existing technologies and frameworks,” said Deputy Vice-Chancellor, Research, Professor Karen Hapgood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We need change fast, and the Siemens–Swinburne team will focus on taking ideas to market — where they can make the most impact as quickly as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visitors to the Hub will be able to leverage digital twins of energy grids, map scenarios, research new findings, develop original hypotheses and test results. The digital twin of Australia’s energy grid will help commercial research teams run simulations of new, innovative solutions and software, focusing on the intermix and influx of various sources of energy into the grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, researchers, students and industry can use the opportunity to work on solutions for greener, more efficient future energy systems using Siemens Xcelerator, a new open digital business platform and marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/538104/web_image_article/Image-2-Team.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Siemens and Swinburne spokespeople with Minister D’Ambrosio. (L-R) Mr Jose Moreira (Siemens), Associate Professor Mehdi Seyedmahmoudian (Swinburne), Professor Karen Hapgood (Swinburne), Minister Lily D’Ambrosio, Mr Peter Halliday (Siemens), Professor Alex Stojcevski (Swinburne).&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;h9&gt;&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Collaboration between industry and academia is critical to driving better outcomes on key topics of national importance such as the energy transition. I’m proud of what the Siemens and Swinburne teams have achieved at the Energy Transition Hub, creating a best-of-its-kind for industry,” said Peter Halliday, CEO, Siemens Australia and New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The race to tackle climate change is real and of utmost importance. Australia’s contribution to global emissions is just over 1%. As industry and as a society, we should be focusing on reducing our emissions beyond the 1%, using digitalisation as the key lever to driving long-term sustainability. The Hub is a great example of how the best minds can collaborate to help shape the future,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Top image caption: Students using the Energy Transition Hub’s facilities. Images courtesy of Siemens.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/new-energy-hub-simulates-australia-s-grid-951056151</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/new-energy-hub-simulates-australia-s-grid-951056151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vic State Electricity Commission back in business</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79491/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Victorian Government has officially brought back its State Electricity Commission (SEC) as a government entity with a plan to lead the state’s renewable energy transition through a focus on supply, homes and training. Originally established in 1918, the SEC was privatised in the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched by Premier Jacinta Allan, the SEC’s Strategic Plan 2023–2035 sets out three clear priorities for the next 10 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Investing to accelerate the energy transition.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Supporting the switch to all-electric households.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Building a renewable energy workforce.&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, the SEC will invest $1 billion towards building 4.5 gigawatts of new power through renewable energy and storage projects — enough to power around 1.5 million homes. This investment will focus on increasing storage and onshore generation, and building industry confidence to attract further investment down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our initial $1 billion investment for the SEC will help boost private investment to fast-track and deliver projects that would not have been delivered at the same speed, or at all, without the SEC’s involvement,” said Treasurer Tim Pallas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SEC will also take over the Labor government’s Victorian Renewable Energy Target projects by 2025 — amounting to 1.2 gigawatts of renewable energy generation in addition to the 4.5 gigawatts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will help power public hospital and schools, police stations and government buildings with renewables, helping to achieve the target for all Victorian Government operations and facilities to be powered by 100% renewable electricity by 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that electrifying an older home can be a complicated process, with many moving parts, the SEC will establish a trusted ‘one-stop shop’ for Victorians, with pilot household solutions starting from next year. It is estimated that residents will make a saving of around $1400 a year by going electric; savings can increase to more than $2700 a year with solar installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the SEC will deliver the skills and training needed to secure Victoria’s pipeline of future energy workers. This involves supporting the creation of 59,000 jobs — including 6000 traineeships and apprentices — to help deliver the infrastructure and services needed to get the state to 95% renewable energy by 2035.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SEC will support workforce development and attraction through three avenues: as an employer; through attraction and training; and as an advocate for sector-wide workforce development. It will establish the SEC Centre of Training Excellence and engage with schools, TAFEs and industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SEC’s Strategic Plan was developed on recommendation from the SEC Expert Advisory Panel, which brought together some of Australia’s most prominent energy sector and business leaders. Each panel member brought specific expertise to guide the design of the new SEC and position it to accelerate Victoria’s energy transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“More than 100 years after it was first established, we’ve brought back the SEC to free Victoria from its reliance on fossil fuels and unlock the opportunities of our renewable energy transition,” said Interim CEO of the State Electricity Commission Chris Miller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the SEC and to view the strategy, visit: &lt;a href="https://www.secvictoria.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;secvictoria.com.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Paul Bradbury&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/vic-state-electricity-commission-back-in-business-1625390786</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/vic-state-electricity-commission-back-in-business-1625390786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern home seeks slick solar solution</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79446/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the northern outskirts of Auckland, there’s a property on which a local working farm sits beside a natural forested area. Located on the farm is a newly developed gated community with approximately 20 architecturally designed modern homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When searching for a home solar system, the owner of one of these residences opted for &lt;a href="https://taspacenergy.co.nz/" target="_blank"&gt;Taspac Energy&lt;/a&gt;, a wholesaler and distributor of solar energy solutions across all market segments in the New Zealand solar industry. The brief was to provide a solar mounting system for the two buildings onsite — a 150 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; primary residence and a 100 m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; garage/home office studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Challenges&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homeowner had chosen a standing seam metal roof because of its design appeal and flat uniform shape. It was important to him to have a low-profile, sleek, all-black solar solution that would not penetrate the roof or void any roof warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the property features an outdoor swimming pool, a spa bathroom and an EV charging station onsite, which is integrated into the whole solar PV system. The goal was for the solar system to supplement as much power as possible, as the property consumes 35,000 kWh per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The solution&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/537460/web_image_article/DJI-0049.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homeowner chose the &lt;a href="https://www.s-5.com/" target="_blank"&gt;S-5!&lt;/a&gt; PVKIT rail-less solar mounting solution (in black) combined with the S-5-R-465 Mini non-penetrating, standing seam clamp to complement the aesthetic look of the roof so the whole system would look slick and black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secondary building features a standing seam metal roof with a 12.6 kW solar array secured in place utilising the S-5! PVKIT direct-attach, rail-less solar solution. The rooftop solar system consists of 32 405-watt black PV modules connected to a 10 kW solar inverter coupled with a 19.2 kWh battery storage system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The S-5! system provides a simple, secure method to ‘lay &amp;amp; play’ PV modules with tested, engineered, direct attachment onto the seams of the metal roof. Also, using the S-5! clamps meant the homeowner could maintain warranties due to the non-invasive, penetration-free attachment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The outcome&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homeowner was able to supplement the property’s power generation by 45%, reducing his dependency on utilities. The PVKIT system eliminated the need for a traditional rail system and provided an aesthetically pleasing, cost-effective PV-mounting solution — saving the customer time and money on installation and materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We were naturally drawn to the quality of S-5! products and the fact that there are no known warranty claims or failures on any of the products they have ever produced,” said James Hanff, Grid Connected Project Manager, Taspac Energy Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Their rail-less solution is super-compact and easy to transport, great quality, super-fast and user-friendly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Project stats&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Solar installer: Avid Solar&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;S-5! distributor: Taspac Energy Ltd.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Module manufacturer: 32 405-watt REC Alpha Pure Modules&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Inverter manufacturer: Fronius Gen 24Plus Hybrid Inverter&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Battery storage: BYD Battery-Box Premium HVM Battery Storage System&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Project size: 12.6 kW&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Roof profile: standing seam metal roof&lt;br&gt;
	 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Images courtesy of S-5!&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/case-study/modern-home-seeks-slick-solar-solution-1622501561</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/case-study/modern-home-seeks-slick-solar-solution-1622501561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exposing the vulnerabilities of smart homes</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79401/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Smart homes are becoming increasingly interconnected, comprising an array of consumer-oriented Internet of Things (IoT) devices ranging from smartphones and smart TVs to virtual assistants and CCTV cameras. These devices have cameras, microphones and other ways of sensing what is happening in our most private spaces — our homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Led by &lt;a href="https://networks.imdea.org/" target="_blank"&gt;IMDEA Networks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.northeastern.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;Northeastern University&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with NYU Tandon School of Engineering, Universidad Carlos III de Madrid (UC3M), IMDEA Software, the University of Calgary and the International Computer Science Institute, the research team looked into the intricacies of local network interactions between 93 IoT devices and mobile apps. Their study, titled ‘In the Room Where It Happens: Characterizing Local Communication and Threats in Smart Homes’, was presented at the ACM Internet Measurement Conference (ACM IMC’23) in Montreal, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When we think of what happens between the walls of our homes, we think of it as a trusted, private place. In reality, we find that smart devices in our homes are piercing that veil of trust and privacy — in ways that allow nearly any company to learn what devices are in your home, to know when you are home, and learn where your home is,” said David Choffnes, Associate Professor of Computer Science and Executive Director of the Cybersecurity and Privacy Institute at Northeastern University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These behaviours are generally not disclosed to consumers, and there is a need for better protections in the home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study’s findings illuminated new threats associated with the inadvertent exposure of sensitive data by IoT devices within local networks using standard protocols such as UPnP or mDNS. These threats include the exposure of unique device names, universally unique identifiers (UUIDs) and even household geolocation data, all of which can be harvested by companies involved in surveillance capitalism without user awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Vijay Prakash, a PhD student from NYU Tandon who co-authored the paper, the team found evidence of IoT devices inadvertently exposing at least one piece of PII (personally identifiable information), such as a unique hardware address (MAC), UUID or unique device name, in thousands of real-world smart homes. Any single PII is useful for identifying a household, but combining three of them together makes a house very unique and easily identifiable, Prakash said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For comparison, if a person is fingerprinted using the simplest browser fingerprinting technique, they are as unique as one in 1500 people. If a smart home with all three types of identifiers is fingerprinted, it is as unique as one in 1.12 million smart homes,” Prakash said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These local network protocols can be employed as side channels to access data that is supposedly protected by several mobile app permissions, such as household locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A side channel is a sneaky way of indirectly accessing sensitive data. For example, Android app developers are supposed to request and obtain users’ consent to access data like geolocation. However, we have shown that certain spyware apps and advertising companies do abuse local network protocols to silently access such sensitive information without any user awareness. All they have to do is kindly ask for it [from] other IoT devices deployed in the local network using standard protocols like UPnP,” said Narseo Vallina-Rodriguez, Associate Research Professor of IMDEA Networks and co-founder of AppCensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our study shows that the local network protocols used by IoT devices are not sufficiently protected and expose sensitive information about the home and the use we make of the devices. This information is being collected in an opaque way and makes it easier to create profiles of our habits or socioeconomic level,” added Juan Tapiador, Professor at UC3M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact of the research extends far beyond academia. The team’s findings underscore the imperative for manufacturers, software developers, IoT and mobile platform operators, and policymakers to take action to enhance the privacy and security guarantees of smart home devices and households. The research team responsibly disclosed these issues to vulnerable IoT device vendors and to Google’s Android Security Team, already triggering security improvements in some of these products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/yucelyilmaz&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/article/exposing-the-vulnerabilities-of-smart-homes-619733071</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/article/exposing-the-vulnerabilities-of-smart-homes-619733071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lift companies charged over death of apprentice electrician</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79378/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esv.vic.gov.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Energy Safe Victoria&lt;/a&gt; has charged two lift companies and their directors under the &lt;em&gt;Electricity Safety Act 1998&lt;/em&gt; for offences relating to the death of a fourth-year apprentice electrician. At the time of his death in March 2021, the apprentice was working unsupervised on a car lift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alleged offences include charges relating to failing to provide effective supervision for the apprentice electrician and working on energised electrical equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is alleged the 21-year-old died after coming into contact with an energised piece of electrical equipment in a West Melbourne apartment block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The matters are listed for mention at the Melbourne Magistrates Court on 16 November 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/artisteer&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/lift-companies-charged-over-death-of-apprentice-electrician-744044618</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/lift-companies-charged-over-death-of-apprentice-electrician-744044618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EnergyAustralia signs wind farm offtake agreement</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79286/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Renewable energy developer &lt;a href="https://genexpower.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Genex Power Limited&lt;/a&gt; has entered into a 10-year power purchase agreement with &lt;a href="https://www.energyaustralia.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;EnergyAustralia&lt;/a&gt; for the 258 MW Kidston Stage 3 Wind Project (K3W), through Genex’s wholly owned subsidiary K3W Project Co. Pty Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This follows the first offtake Genex signed with EnergyAustralia, for the 250 MW Kidston Pumped Storage Hydro project in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two projects form part of Genex’s flagship &lt;a href="https://genexpower.com.au/250mw-kidston-pumped-storage-hydro-project/" target="_blank"&gt;Kidston Clean Energy Hub&lt;/a&gt;, located in north Queensland, which will integrate large-scale solar generation with pumped storage hydro. The Kidston Clean Energy Hub comprises the operating 50 MW stage 1 Solar Project (KS1) and the 250 MW Kidston Pumped Storage Hydro Project (K2-Hydro), with potential for further multi-stage wind and solar projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K3W is being developed by Genex in a 50:50 partnership with Electric Power Development Co., Ltd (J-POWER).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agreement with EnergyAustralia secures the offtake of 30% of the K3W project’s output of wind energy and large-scale generation certificates at a fixed price, over a 10-year term from commencement of operations. (The fixed price is subject to annual escalation in accordance with movements in the consumer price index.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The execution of this power purchase agreement with EnergyAustralia represents a significant milestone for the development of the 258 MW Kidston Stage 3 Wind Project, the third stage of the Kidston Clean Energy Hub,” said Genex CEO Craig Francis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Securing 30% of the offtake capacity of the project with such a high-quality partner in EnergyAustralia signifies a material step in mitigating project risk.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EnergyAustralia Managing Director Mark Collette said the energy retailer and generator was pleased to expand its successful partnership with Genex by supporting the Kidston Stage 3 Wind Project, which would bring it a step closer to its goal of up to 3 GW of renewable energy committed or in operation by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Both Kidston Wind and the Kidston Pumped Storage Hydro Project are important steps in delivering EnergyAustralia’s purpose to lead and accelerate the clean energy transformation for all,” Collette said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Totojang&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/energyaustralia-signs-wind-farm-offtake-agreement-1187832243</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/energyaustralia-signs-wind-farm-offtake-agreement-1187832243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telstra becomes early adopter of hydrogen energy</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79287/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;As part of a co-funded pilot project with the Victorian Government, &lt;a href="https://www.telstra.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Telstra&lt;/a&gt; will install backup hydrogen generators at five sites in outer-regional Victoria, which has a history of storm-related power blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Australian ‘green hydrogen’ company &lt;a href="https://energys.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Energys&lt;/a&gt; has presented the first of five Hydrogen Fuel Cell Generators manufactured for Telstra as part of this alternative energy backup project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The generators are designed as a drop-in replacement for traditional diesel electric generators, which will gradually be phased out as the world strives to meet emissions targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While hydrogen fuel cells have been used in niche applications since the mid-20th century, the abundance of fossil fuels has limited their wider commercial adoption. With rising fuel prices and the need to cut emissions, many forward-thinking companies are working to include hydrogen in their future energy roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energys’s fuel cell generator delivers 10 kilowatts of AC power using hydrogen gas as a fuel source. The hydrogen is passed through the fuel cell, which undergoes an electrochemical reaction, producing electricity. The only by-product of this reaction is pure water vapour, which can be released harmlessly into the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designed and manufactured in Victoria, the Hydrogen Fuel Cell Generator is the result of seven years of research and development. It has been designed specifically for large-scale manufacture using Energys’s proprietary engine design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re supporting the state’s emerging renewable hydrogen sector to play a key part in our transition to 95% renewable energy by 2035,” said Minister for Climate Action and Minister for Energy and Resources Lily D’Ambrosio MP, who attended the unveiling of the first Energys fuel cell generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This innovative project uses renewable energy to keep the power running during an emergency, helping to maintain vital telecommunications, which is critical as we encounter more frequent extreme weather events,” D’Ambrosio said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image caption: Lily D’Ambrosio MP (centre) attends the unveiling of the first Hydrogen Fuel Cell Generator designed by Energys for Telstra. Image: Supplied&lt;/h9&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/telstra-becomes-early-adopter-of-hydrogen-energy-34900539</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/telstra-becomes-early-adopter-of-hydrogen-energy-34900539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transforming home security through AI</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79257/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the first time in over a decade, home break-ins are on the rise, according to data from the Australian Bureau of Statistics (ABS).&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In 2022, 2% of Australian homes — equating to 194,100 households — experienced a break-in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While community programs and laws will always have a role in keeping homes safe, new technology can provide an important extra layer of security. Artificial intelligence (AI), in particular, can make home security smarter, according to telecommunications company &lt;a href="https://uniden.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Uniden&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike old systems, AI security can learn what’s normal for a home. For example, AI notifications can focus specifically on a pet, human or car in the driveway. This tailored approach can drastically reduce false alarms, making it more likely that only relevant alerts reach homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uniden has identified some key features of AI-equipped devices and how they can help enhance home security:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Intelligent surveillance and sensitivity settings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI-powered cameras can detect motion and understand its context, with users able to adjust sensitivity settings, focus on specific areas or rely on thermo sense technology to identify different types of movement. These settings can significantly reduce the number of false alarms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3K resolution for refined detail&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An AI-powered camera with an ultra-3K lens resolution offers the ability to zoom in and capture high-quality footage in intricate detail, enabling a clear view of what’s happening on a property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;AI-enhanced dual lens for a comprehensive view&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to dual lens hardware, modern security cameras can seamlessly merge two videos into one expansive image, offering a 170-degree-wide field of view. This technology captures a more extensive view than traditional security cameras permit. Additionally, the enhanced visuals can trigger AI-powered notifications for specific detections like pets, humans and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Spotlight and intelligent colour night vision&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameras equipped with a powerful 440 lumens spotlight activate when the camera detects a person or vehicle, illuminating the area and adding colour to night vision footage up to 30 metres away. This AI-powered feature acts as a deterrent to intruders while ensuring that any alerts received are worth checking immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Two-way communication with privacy masking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-way communication helps a user monitor their property in 3K quality from anywhere in the world, allowing them to interact with visitors or oversee deliveries when away from home. Additionally, the privacy marking setting offers the option to black out areas a homeowner doesn’t want recorded. This allows surveillance to be focused where it’s most needed, such as the front and back doors, where most people enter and exit the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href="https://uniden.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;www.uniden.com.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.abs.gov.au/media-centre/media-releases/break-ins-increase-after-record-low" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.abs.gov.au/media-centre/media-releases/break-ins-increase-after-record-low&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/onurdongel&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/article/transforming-home-security-through-ai-1154920811</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/article/transforming-home-security-through-ai-1154920811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urgent recall of dangerous solar batteries</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79260/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;LG has issued an urgent recall for LG-branded batteries stored in some Australian residential solar storage systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recall includes 13 specific LG battery models at risk of overheating, catching fire and causing damage to property, serious injury or death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These defective batteries may be installed in LG-branded solar systems including RESU or in non-LG systems including SolaX Power Station, Opal Storage and Eguana Evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Product Safety Australia &lt;a href="https://www.productsafety.gov.au/recalls/lg-energy-solution-australia-pty-ltd-formerly-lg-chem-australia-pty-ltd-%E2%80%94-lg-ess-home-energy-storage-system-batteries" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; provides a full list of the affected LG battery models, as well as systems the battery may be installed in and how to check if one of the recalled batteries is installed in your residential solar system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those with a product listed for recall should immediately switch the battery off and contact LG Energy Solution by calling 1300 677 273 or emailing &lt;a href="mailto:productau@lgensol.com"&gt;productau@lgensol.com&lt;/a&gt; for advice and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LG will organise a remote or onsite visit by a technician to shut down and replace the batteries at no charge. Consumers may be able to alternatively request a refund for the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LG will also compensate customers if their power bill increases during the time their battery is shut down and a new model is installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NSW Fair Trading Commissioner Natasha Mann said that the defective batteries have been sold across Australia by several solar system companies since 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you have a solar storage system installed, you may have one of these potentially dangerous products and not know it,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please take a minute to inspect the batteries as soon as possible. If you are affected by the recall, don’t panic, turn off the battery and contact LG straight away.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/serazetdinov&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/urgent-recall-of-dangerous-solar-batteries-1568637849</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/urgent-recall-of-dangerous-solar-batteries-1568637849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uniden App Cam SOLO PANO Kit</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src=""&gt; &lt;p&gt;Uniden’s App Cam SOLO Pano Kit is an intelligent security system offering a range of AI features designed for Australian conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weatherproof device has a 440 lumens spotlight, a 170-degree-wide field of view and a 3K lens resolution to capture high-quality footage when most needed. With this detection technology, the App Cam SOLO Pano Kit alerts users through instant-push notifications via the Uniden SOLO app, thus reducing the number of false alarms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uniden offers free seven-day cloud storage, which rolls over for the life of the product. This cloud-based storage saves motion-triggered recordings, so users receive relevant footage without the clutter, making it simpler to find and review key events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system’s wire-free over Wi-Fi capability is designed so that both homeowners and renters can easily install it without worrying about ongoing subscription costs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/product/uniden-app-cam-solo-pano-kit-725988117</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/automation-security-control/product/uniden-app-cam-solo-pano-kit-725988117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrician pleads guilty over explosion risk</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79228/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;An electrician from Western Australia’s South West region has pleaded guilty to two charges under WA’s electricity licensing regulations and ordered to pay $11,000 in fines and costs for a dangerous installation that could have caused a hydrogen explosion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2021, the electrician attended a property in Scott River East, near Augusta and Nannup, to install inverter chargers in a standalone power system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system involved storing solar energy in a bank of vented lead–acid batteries, which produce potentially explosive hydrogen gas when they are recharging. The electrician installed the inverter chargers, which can be an ignition source for this gas, near the exposed lead–acid battery bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An investigation by WA safety regulator &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.wa.gov.au/building-and-energy" target="_blank"&gt;Building and Energy&lt;/a&gt; found that the electrician’s installation of the inverter charger did not comply with electrical wiring rules that require protection against ignition when electrical equipment is installed in areas where explosive gases may be present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The electrician breached the Electricity (Licensing) Regulations 1991 by not adhering to the wiring rules and, additionally, by submitting an official compliance notice when the installation work was in fact incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WA’s Director of Energy Safety, Saj Abdoolakhan, said the dangerous installation could have resulted in serious injuries and property damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In this case, hydrogen would have been produced regularly whenever the vented lead–acid batteries were charged by energy from the solar panels,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is pure luck that the chargers did not ignite the gas from the nearby exposed batteries before the danger was identified by a Building and Energy electrical inspector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 22 September 2023, Magistrate Andrew Maughan ordered the electrician to pay a global fine of $8000 and $2982.30 in costs. The electrician was granted a spent conviction due to factors such as the guilty plea and no previous electrical offences in a lengthy career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maughan urged tradespeople to accept the real potential for injury from hazards, adding that the incorrect notice charge was also a serious matter due to the diligence expected in self-regulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abdoolakhan also stressed the importance of licensed electrical contractors and electrical workers taking responsibility for their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They have to make sure the work they do complies with all the relevant technical safety requirements. They must also submit accurate notices that reflect compulsory checking, testing and compliance,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/wesvandinter&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/electrician-pleads-guilty-over-explosion-risk-1175553981</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/electrician-pleads-guilty-over-explosion-risk-1175553981</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual power plants for WA schools</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive"  src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront.net/data/79123/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Seven schools in regional Western Australia will receive solar panels and commercial batteries as part of &lt;a href="https://www.synergy.net.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Synergy&lt;/a&gt;’s Schools Virtual Power Plant (VPP) Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schools will have solar systems and a commercial-sized battery installed and operational in the 2024 school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A VPP is a network of energy resources such as rooftop solar panels and batteries that are combined to generate, store and distribute electricity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The VPPs will enable the schools to store the energy generated from their solar systems and better manage energy use, while also helping improve grid stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Virtual Power Plant project is a terrific program that is supporting schools in lowering their energy bills, while also stabilising the broader energy system,” said Education Minister Dr Tony Buti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The project offers WA students the chance to learn more about how energy is produced and used — equipping them with STEM skills and knowledge, which is a really important part of their education.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seven regional schools to join the 17-school pilot across Western Australia are variously located in Kalbarri, Geraldton and Kalgoorlie. The regional expansion of the Schools VPP project is funded through the Schools Clean Energy Technology Fund, part of a total $8.8 million state government investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geraldton MLA Lara Dalton said it was great that three Geraldton schools would be able to experience the many benefits of renewable energy technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Virtual Power Plants at Champion Bay Senior High School, Geraldton Senior High School and Waggrakine Primary School will help reduce their power bills and improve power quality in the community,” Dalton said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Halfpoint&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/virtual-power-plants-for-wa-schools-1350964856</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/virtual-power-plants-for-wa-schools-1350964856</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
