<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ECD (Electrical+Comms+Data) RSS Feed</title>
    <description>https://ecdonline.com.au</description>
    <link>https://ecdonline.com.au</link>
    <item>
      <title>Lapp ETHERLINE cables and EPIC DATA 90 RJ45 connector</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71637/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;The Lapp Group’s ETHERLINE product range includes Cat5, Cat6 and Cat7 industrial Ethernet cables and connectivity products. Available from Treotham Automation, the ETHERLINE range of cables provides reliable network communications in demanding industrial and communication environments where difficult EMI conditions are prevalent. ETHERLINE is available with PVC or PUR outer sheath which meets the highest service life requirements, even under harsh climatic conditions. ETHERLINE offers premium screening against electromagnetic interference and is suited for use in drag chains and moving machinery parts in dry or damp rooms or plant engineering and machinery manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treeeeeeotham also provides the EPIC DATA 90 RJ45 connector which was designed to complement ETHERLINE cables. The connector is made up of two parts, with the rear part being able to be fitted in four positions. Installation engineers are increasingly demanding angled connectors for Ethernet cables, so the EPIC DATA 90 RJ45 connector offers the versatility to rotate or change cable outlets in 90-degree increments easily in the field. It is designed to ensure reliable network cabling even in restricted spaces, avoiding strain on the bending radius of data network cables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treotham Automation has thousands of locally stocked products available for next-day delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href="https://treotham.com.au/flexible-cables/ethernet-cables/flexible-use/etherline-cat5e-flex" target="_blank"&gt;https://treotham.com.au/flexible-cables/ethernet-cables/flexible-use/etherline-cat5e-flex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/hot-product/lapp-etherline-cables-and-epic-data-90-rj45-connector-1645818915</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/hot-product/lapp-etherline-cables-and-epic-data-90-rj45-connector-1645818915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WBT Ducting Raceway: an Australian-made solution for managing, routing and protecting optical fibre cords</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71599/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Warren &amp;amp; Brown’s optical fibre ducting raceway is an Australian-made solution for managing, routing and protecting optical fibre cords between termination equipment, patch panels and splicing cabinets or frames in telecommunications exchanges, data centres, universities, hospitals, or anywhere optical fibre cabling is present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ducting range has been designed as a robust and versatile solution that supports seamless growth, ensuring that data centres are future-proof. Warren &amp;amp; Brown’s ducting range is made using a special fibre-retardant Low Smoke Zero Halogen (LSZH) material certified to UL94V-0 specifications, while some other brands on the market are still using PVC. In the case of a fire, LSZH materials significantly reduce the amount of toxic and corrosive gas emissions, minimising harm to personnel, buildings and transmission equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warren &amp;amp; Brown ducting raceway ensures all the critical points of the fibre cable management are met: bend radius protection, cable access and routing, and physical protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ducting system is currently available in three colours and seven sizes in a solid wall or slotted wall for exiting fibres. It is most important to select a size that allows for expansion and future additions to the ducting system. The most recent addition is the 600 x 100 ducting raceway system, providing maximum capacity of up to 7500 two-millimetre patch cords, based on a 50% fill rate. The ducting raceway can easily be customised and designed for your facility’s specific requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components can be joined together using two methods: slotted joiners or spotless joiners. Slotted joiners require the use of a slotting tool only when the duct length has been modified; however, duct lengths and ducting components are supplied pre-slotted so they can be installed quickly and easily by clicking into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To complete the installation where no modifications have been made, only a basic screwdriver is required. Slotless joiners require no additional tooling or for slots to be made on the side of the duct, requiring only a screwdriver for installation of raceway system ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique design of the ducting system protects the optical fibre patch cords from damage and ensures that the bend radius of the cable is not compromised. All components in the WBT system are manufactured from Noryl, a very strong engineering plastic, which is self-extinguishing and halogen free (for 100, 220 and 330 mm ducting the rating is UL94-0, for 30 and 50 mm ducting it is UL94V-1), which means in the case of a fire, the gases emitted will not cause harm to personnel, buildings, or transmission equipment, unlike some other brands of ducting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WBT fibre optic ducting raceway products are manufactured to the highest quality standards (ISO9001), complying with the stringent requirements ULA2024A &amp;amp; RoHS (Restriction of Hazardous Substances Directive), and carry a 10-year warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WBT Ducting Raceway items conform to the following standards and requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ISO 9001 Certified Quality Management System by BSI&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Fire retardant plastic, Halogen Free&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;UL2024A standard&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;EE-ROHS requirements&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;GR-63 Core Earthquake test compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/sponsored/wbt-ducting-raceway-an-australian-made-solution-for-managing-routing-and-protecting-optical-fibre-cords-1012283030</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/sponsored/wbt-ducting-raceway-an-australian-made-solution-for-managing-routing-and-protecting-optical-fibre-cords-1012283030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transmission benefits for NSW landowners</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71619/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.energynetworks.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Energy Networks Australia&lt;/a&gt; has welcomed the NSW Government’s announcement that landowners who host new significant transmission infrastructure will be eligible for strategic benefit payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy Networks Australia CEO Andrew Dillon said the payments would help get transmission infrastructure built on time to enable the transition to net zero energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The NSW Government is taking major strides in solving the challenges of building transmission infrastructure including how networks engage with communities and landowners and implementing social licence best practice. This may form a blueprint for other jurisdictions,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Australia is working towards a net zero energy grid but is impeded by a lack of transmission infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our existing network regulations focus on keeping payments to landowners as low as possible. The current regulatory approach is a handbrake on getting projects built, and challenging and divisive for affected communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Strategic benefit payments are a major step to addressing this problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dillon said it was pleasing to see the NSW Government had earmarked not only projects within the NSW Electricity Infrastructure Roadmap, but also those in the Australian Energy Market Operator’s &lt;a href="https://aemo.com.au/en/energy-systems/major-publications/integrated-system-plan-isp" target="_blank"&gt;Integrated System Plan&lt;/a&gt; (ISP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By including projects for the ISP, it will mean a more interconnected energy grid for the whole of Australia,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The need for network investment is now critical; the cost of delaying these projects is significant. Networks need to install more than 10,000 kilometres of new transmission lines to ensure we can connect the renewable generation our system will need to reach net zero by 2050.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/zetter&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/transmission-benefits-for-nsw-landowners-906119237</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/transmission-benefits-for-nsw-landowners-906119237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Test' Solar &amp;amp; (amp here) now here is encoded&amp;gt; &amp;amp; savings through bird-inspired algorithm TEST El Niño</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71633/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Researchers at &lt;a href="https://www.swinburne.edu.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Swinburne University&lt;/a&gt; have created a bird-inspired algorithm that could dramatically increase the efficiency of the more than three million solar panels on Australian roofs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solar panel efficiency can be impacted up to 92% by partial shading, where birds, dust or surrounding structures block out part of the sun. The new algorithm allows the shaded parts of the panel to be bypassed, saving solar owners money and generating a greater volume of renewable energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Associate Professor Mehdi Seyedmahmoudian, from Swinburne’s &lt;a href="https://www.swinburne.edu.au/about/our-structure/organisational-structure/schools-departments/school-science-computing-engineering-technologies/" target="_blank"&gt;School of Science, Computing and Engineering Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, said many solar owners are unaware of the large impact that just a single bird or shaded panel can have. “People often spend a lot of money on solar panels to increase efficiency, without knowing that these small changes on the rooftop, which are out of their control, can actually drop the solar panels’ efficiency dramatically,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seyedmahmoudian and his New Energy Technologies Research Group revealed that 52% of partial-shading conditions are created by birds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our thinking was that if the problem is created by nature, then we need to implement nature to solve it,” Seyedmahmoudian said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Obviously we cannot control the birds, so we studied their movement to create a nature-inspired artificial intelligence. Now when you have birds over a panel, that section can be bypassed and you can get the highest efficiency possible from the rest of your solar panels.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the system uses existing hardware and integrates the nature-inspired algorithm into the intelligent system, the technology doesn’t come at a huge cost. The smart software can also detect damaged or malfunctioning panels and divert unused power in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People were focusing on infrastructure technology rather than the intelligence of the system. You cannot control the environment, so this is a very cost-effective way to improve the efficiency,” Seyedmahmoudian said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seyedmahmoudian is now working with his research group so that their solution can be installed directly into existing household set-ups. “We are developing our own inverters within our research group, and also looking forward to exploring opportunities to work and share our knowledge with existing inverter companies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the research team, the most important step is creating a pathway to implement and integrate the system at people’s homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want to be able to go to somebody’s home and say, ‘I’m going to give you this box, you don’t need any new hardware, I’m just going to install this inverter and as a result your solar system will dramatically improve’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Frank Cornelissen&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/solar-savings-through-bird-inspired-algorithm-1647208995</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/solar-savings-through-bird-inspired-algorithm-1647208995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rockwell Automation to acquire CUBIC</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71467/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rockwellautomation.com/en-au/company.html" target="_blank"&gt;Rockwell Automation, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, a company dedicated to industrial automation and digital transformation, has signed a definitive agreement to acquire &lt;a href="https://www.cubic.eu/" target="_blank"&gt;CUBIC&lt;/a&gt;, a company that specialises in modular systems for the construction of electrical panels. CUBIC, founded in 1973, serves fast-growing industries such as renewable energy, data centres and infrastructure. It is headquartered in Bronderslev, Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CUBIC’s flexible modular systems combined with Rockwell’s intelligent devices and industry expertise should benefit customers by offering faster time to market, enabling broader plant-wide applications for intelligent motor control and generating smart data to increase sustainability and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CUBIC’s established partner model will allow Rockwell to build an expanded Partner Network for intelligent motor control offerings in Asia, Europe and Latin America. The company will bring new customers and partners in hybrid and process industries. Additionally, CUBIC will broaden Rockwell’s market access in renewable energy and data centre solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“CUBIC’s innovative motor control solutions strengthen our portfolio of leading intelligent motor control technologies,” said Bob Buttermore, VP and GM of Rockwell’s Power Control Business. “We are pleased to welcome a talented team with specialised expertise in structural design, power systems and global standards.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Joining Rockwell will enable us to expand our relationships and accelerate our global growth,” said Jacob Moller Knudsen, CEO of CUBIC. “This is a perfect match that will allow us to offer our customers the best solutions going forward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At close, CUBIC will report to Rockwell’s Power Control Business in the Intelligent Devices operating segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CUBIC is expected to report more than $75 million in sales in fiscal year 2022, which ended 30 September. The transaction is subject to customary regulatory approval and is expected to close by the end of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Maxiphoto&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/rockwell-automation-to-acquire-cubic-361312823</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/rockwell-automation-to-acquire-cubic-361312823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Praise for transmission investment</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71473/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.energynetworks.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Energy Networks Australia&lt;/a&gt; has welcomed the significant transmission investment announcements from the federal government’s &lt;a href="https://www.energy.gov.au/news-media/news/rewiring-nation-supports-its-first-two-transmission-projects" target="_blank"&gt;Rewiring the Nation&lt;/a&gt; plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new funding will enable both the Marinus Link between Victoria and Tasmania and the Victoria–New South Wales interconnector KerangLink to proceed, unlocking vital renewable energy to aid in the transition towards net zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy Networks Australia CEO Andrew Dillon said the investment will mean more secure and reliable renewable energy for the national energy market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Australia is working towards a net zero energy grid but is hampered by a lack of transmission infrastructure. These new links are key steps towards a 21st-century renewable energy grid,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Network investment is critical to enable the most affordable transition to a net zero energy system. Every dollar spent on transmission will return more than twice this in benefits to customers. It will enable cheap, renewable electricity to flow to where it is needed, making firming easier and lowering wholesale prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Networks need to install more than 10,000 kilometres of new transmission lines to ensure we can connect the renewable generation our system will need to reach net zero by 2050. While private sector investors are prepared to underpin much of this investment, leadership from government will encourage confidence and investment from the private sector.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dillon said a recent &lt;a href="https://www.energynetworks.com.au/resources/reports/2022-reports-and-publications/market-sounding-report-on-transmission/" target="_blank"&gt;market-sounding report&lt;/a&gt; commissioned by the &lt;a href="https://www.cleanenergycouncil.org.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Clean Energy Council&lt;/a&gt; and Energy Networks Australia had already highlighted the critical need for governments to work to solve transmission challenges to enable Australia’s energy transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The stakeholder feedback from the report emphasised the crucial role that Rewiring the Nation could play in funding significant transmission projects like Marinus Link and KerangLink. It is pleasing to see the federal government has prioritised these projects and acted swiftly to get them moving.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/mikulas1&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/praise-for-transmission-investment-1409078512</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/news/praise-for-transmission-investment-1409078512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The problem with charging cars at home at night</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71476/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;If the common charging of electric vehicles at home in the evening or overnight shifts to daytime at work as more cars go electric, then that would restrain extra costs for electricity systems, according to a new &lt;a href="https://www.stanford.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;Stanford University&lt;/a&gt; study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, the research team published a &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0306261921016214" target="_blank"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on a model they created for charging demand that can be applied to an array of populations and other factors. In the new study, published 22 September in &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/nenergy/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature Energy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, they applied their model to the whole of the Western United States and examined the stress the region’s electric grid will come under by 2035 from growing EV ownership. In a little over a decade, they found, rapid EV growth alone could increase peak electricity demand by up to 25%, assuming a continued dominance of residential, night-time charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To limit the high costs of all that new capacity for generating and storing electricity, the researchers say, drivers should move to daytime charging at work or public charging stations, which would also reduce greenhouse gas emissions. This finding has policy and investment implications for the region and its utilities, especially since California moved in late August to ban sales of gasoline-powered cars and light trucks starting in 2035.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We encourage policymakers to consider utility rates that encourage day charging and incentivise investment in charging infrastructure to shift drivers from home to work for charging,” said the study’s co-senior author, &lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/ram-rajagopal" target="_blank"&gt;Ram Rajagopal&lt;/a&gt;, an associate professor of civil and environmental engineering at Stanford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February, cumulative sales of EVs in California reached one million, accounting for about 6% of cars and light trucks. The state has targeted five million EVs on the road by 2030. When the penetration hits 30 to 40% of cars on the road, the grid will experience significant stress without major investments and changes in charging habits, Rajagopal said. Building that infrastructure requires significant lead time and cannot be done overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We considered the entire Western US region, because California depends heavily on electricity imports from the other Western states. EV charging plus all other electricity uses have consequences for the whole Western region given the interconnected nature of our electric grid,” said Siobhan Powell, lead author of the March study and the new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We were able to show that with less home charging and more daytime charging, the Western US would need less generating capacity and storage, and it would not waste as much solar and wind power,” said Powell, mechanical engineering PhD ’22.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And it’s not just California and Western states. All states may need to rethink electricity pricing structures as their EV charging needs increase and their grid changes,” added Powell, who recently took a postdoctoral research position at ETH Zurich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once 50% of cars on the road are powered by electricity in the Western US — of which about half the population lives in California — more than 5.4 gigawatts of energy storage would be needed if charging habits follow their current course. That’s the capacity equivalent of 5 large nuclear power reactors. A big shift to charging at work instead of home would reduce the storage needed for EVs to 4.2 gigawatts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Changing incentives&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current time-of-use rates encourage consumers to switch electricity use to night-time whenever possible, like running the dishwasher and charging EVs. This rate structure reflects the time before significant solar and wind power supplies when demand threatened to exceed supply during the day, especially late afternoons in the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, California has excess electricity during late mornings and early afternoons, thanks mainly to its solar capacity. If most EVs were to charge during these times, then the cheap power would be used instead of wasted. Alternatively, if most EVs continue to charge at night, then the state will need to build more generators — likely powered by natural gas — or expensive energy storage on a large scale. Electricity going first to a huge battery and then to an EV battery loses power from the extra stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the local level, if a third of homes in a neighbourhood have EVs and most of the owners continue to set charging to start at 11 pm or whenever electricity rates drop, the local grid could become unstable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The findings from this paper have two profound implications: the first is that the price signals are not aligned with what would be best for the grid — and for ratepayers. The second is that it calls for considering investments in a charging infrastructure for where people work,” said &lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/ines-azevedo" target="_blank"&gt;Ines Azevedo&lt;/a&gt;, the new paper’s other co-senior author and associate professor of energy science and engineering in the &lt;a href="https://sustainability.stanford.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability&lt;/a&gt;, which opened on 1 September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We need to move quickly toward decarbonising the transportation sector, which accounts for the bulk of emissions in California,” Azevedo continued. “This work provides insight on how to get there. Let’s ensure that we pursue policies and investment strategies that allow us to do so in a way that is sustainable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with electricity pricing design is charging commercial and industrial customers big fees based on their peak electricity use. This can disincentivise employers from installing chargers, especially once half or more of their employees have EVs. The research team compared several scenarios of charging infrastructure availability, along with several different residential time-of-use rates and commercial demand charges. Some rate changes made the situation at the grid level worse, while others improved it. Nevertheless, a scenario of having charging infrastructure that encourages more daytime charging and less home charging provided the biggest benefits, the study found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rajagopal and Azevedo are also co-directors of the &lt;a href="https://energy.stanford.edu/bitsandwatts" target="_blank"&gt;Bits &amp;amp; Watts Initiative&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford’s &lt;a href="https://energy.stanford.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;Precourt Institute for Energy&lt;/a&gt;. Other co-authors of this study are Gustavo Cezar, PhD student and a staff engineer at Stanford’s SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory; and Liang Min, Managing Director of the Bits &amp;amp; Watts Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by the California Energy Commission, the National Science Foundation and the Bits &amp;amp; Watts Initiative with support from Volkswagen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Fahroni&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/article/the-problem-with-charging-cars-at-home-at-night-804242896</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/article/the-problem-with-charging-cars-at-home-at-night-804242896</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing big data in property valuation</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71482/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the &lt;a href="https://www.unisa.edu.au/" target="_blank"&gt;University of South Australia&lt;/a&gt; (UniSA) have developed a machine learning technique which they say makes property valuation more transparent, reliable and practical, with the ability to accurately model the impact of urban development decisions on property prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technique was created and validated using over 30 years of historical sale information in metro Adelaide and uses purpose-developed machine learning algorithms to process huge amounts of data about housing, urban structure and amenities, making it possible to quantify the effects of urban planning policies on housing value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lead researcher on the project, UniSA geospatial data analyst and urban planning expert Dr Ali Soltani, said the technique has implications for the property, urban planning and infrastructure sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our modelling technique and findings may help real estate investors, builders, property owners, house appraisers and other stakeholders gain a more realistic view of the value of property and the factors that affect that,” Soltani said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This research has implications for policymakers by providing insights into the potential impacts of urban planning — such as infill regeneration, master-planned communities, gentrification and population displacement — and infrastructure provision policies on the housing market and subsequent local and regional economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By capturing the complicated influence of infrastructure elements such as road and public transportation networks, commercial centres and natural landscapes on home value, our model is especially valuable for enhancing the accuracy of current land value predictions and lowering the risks associated with traditional property valuation methodologies, which are largely dependent on human experience and limited data.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soltani said the model — developed in conjunction with Professor Chris Pettit from UNSW’s &lt;a href="https://cityfutures.ada.unsw.edu.au/" target="_blank"&gt;City Futures Research Centre&lt;/a&gt; — may also be extended to include other economic features at both the macro and micro levels, such as interest rates, employment rates and the influence of COVID-19, by harnessing the benefits of big data technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This model has the potential to be used as a decision-support platform for a variety of stakeholders, including home buyers and sellers, banks and financial agents, investors, the government, and insurance or loan agents,” Soltani said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our technique makes it simpler for stakeholders and the general public to apply the findings of sophisticated models on historical or real-time data from multiple sources, which have previously been almost black-box and expert-oriented.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A summary of this research has been recently &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0264275122003808?via%3Dihub" target="_blank"&gt;published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Cities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Elsevier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/CHUNYIP WONG&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/news/harnessing-big-data-in-property-valuation-663348735</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/news/harnessing-big-data-in-property-valuation-663348735</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Cash for standards' causes alarm</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71337/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Australia’s electrical industry has raised the alarm over a ‘cash for access’ proposal for electrical standards, warning of safety risks and increased black market access if small businesses are priced out of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An industry forum convened by &lt;a href="https://masterelectricians.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Master Electricians Australia&lt;/a&gt; condemned the proposed new pricing scheme for access to standards, saying business owners were being viewed as cash cows by Standards Australia, which already boasts $361 million in net assets and $60 million in annual revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Master Electricians Australia General Manager of Policy and Advocacy Jason O’Dwyer said Standards Australia planned to increase its fees to the electrical contracting industry by $30 million per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no place for this cash-for-access approach to pricing a document that is so vital to the quality of electrical work and the safety of all Australians,” O’Dwyer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s why Master Electricians convened an industry roundtable to highlight our concerns that the additional costs will either be passed on to consumers or, even worse, will just be too much for some businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This could result in increased use of out-of-date or illegal copies of the Electrical Standards, meaning businesses may not always be working in line with the latest technical and safety best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These are serious concerns, and the standards are vitally important documents for our industry. They shouldn’t be available only to those with the biggest bank accounts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O’Dwyer said the pricing model would drive up the cost of accessing standards for all other industries such as plumbing and building and would also affect universities, TAFEs, RTOs and other teaching institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industry forum called on Standards Australia to implement a “reasonable and manageable subscription” that could be collected from electrical contractors as part of their annual licence fee, as currently happens in New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Standards Australia is a not-for-profit organisation, which supposedly exists to develop standards. However, considering industry invests a significant amount of money, expertise and intellectual property into that process, it’s time that Standards Australia stopped treating us as a cash cow,” O’Dwyer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industry roundtable was attended by all major representative groups in the electrical industry, including Master Electricians Australia; the Electrical Trades Union of Australia; the National Fire Industry Association, Australia; Master Plumbers Australia and New Zealand; and the Association of Consulting Architects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All these groups are long-term partners and supporters of Standards Australia, and we don’t want to attack an organisation that plays such an important role in our industry,” O’Dwyer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But friends tell friends when they are walking on a dangerous path, and that’s what we are doing here as an industry. We can only hope Standards Australia will listen to the warning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposed changes will impact all industry associations including NECA and the ETU. Currently all Master Electricians have access to 21 Australian Standards at no cost. This will remain in place for the 2022–23 financial year. The MEA said it hoped that at the conclusion of this period, Standards would have implemented a reasonable and manageable subscription, providing access to standards as part of the electrical contractors annual licence fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/AndreyPopov&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/-cash-for-standards-causes-alarm-915369216</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/-cash-for-standards-causes-alarm-915369216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qld's $23m renewable energy training facility</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71316/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;The Queensland Government has launched a state-of-the-art new training facility for renewable energy, with the aim of giving workers the skills they will need for the thousands of jobs to be created under its Energy and Jobs Plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk officially opened Electro Group’s Renewable Energy Training Facility (RETF) at Pinkenba, where Cabinet also met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our investment of $17 million towards this $23 million training centre of excellence will help create a skilled future workforce to provide cheaper, cleaner and secure energy for Queenslanders,” Palaszczuk said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Queensland Energy and Jobs Plan will create around 100,000 new jobs, so facilities like this are critical in developing the skills to build new clean energy infrastructure and industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As part of our plan, we will build Australia’s largest energy SuperGrid, delivering clean, reliable and affordable energy to power Queensland homes and industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Renewable Energy Training Facility will provide world’s best practice in electrical, solar renewable energy and telecommunications training, creating a future-ready workforce and supporting our students to reach their full potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a significant training centre not only for the region but for the state, in partnership with the Electrical Trades Union and Master Electricians Australia.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The investment was part of the Palaszczuk government’s &lt;a href="https://www.covid19.qld.gov.au/government-actions/our-economic-recovery-strategy" target="_blank"&gt;Queensland Economic Recovery Strategy: Unite and Recover for Queensland Jobs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RETF is owned and operated by Electro Group Training (&lt;a href="https://www.egt.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;EGT&lt;/a&gt;), which will offer qualifications in renewable energy, train apprentices, and assist licensed electricians in upgrading their skills to install, operate and manage solar and other renewable energy equipment safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minister for Energy, Renewables and Hydrogen Mick de Brenni said Queensland’s energy transformation presents the state’s greatest jobs opportunity in a generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Queensland SuperGrid and our plan to use local companies, via onshore component manufacturing wherever possible, will generate an expected 64,000 direct and indirect jobs in its construction and even more in its operation,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our plan invests in skills, training and support for both our existing energy sector workforce and creating the new jobs and careers of tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is complemented by the $10.6 million Hydrogen and Renewable Energy Training Facility at Bohle TAFE in Townsville, as part of the $100 million Equipping TAFE for our Future initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SuperGrid is all of the elements in the electricity system, including poles, wires, solar, wind and storage; its aim is to provide Queenslanders with renewable power for generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Thurtell&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/qld-s-23m-renewable-energy-training-facility-1164106511</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/qld-s-23m-renewable-energy-training-facility-1164106511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon to deploy heavy-duty electric trucks</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71317/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Volvo Trucks has announced it will be delivering fully electric heavy-duty trucks to Amazon in Germany by the end of the year. The 20 Volvo FH Electric trucks are expected to drive more than 1 million road kilometres annually, fuelled with electricity instead of diesel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heavy goods vehicles and other commercial vehicles currently make up around 36% of Germany’s domestic transport emissions&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; — making road transport decarbonisation an important factor in addressing net zero goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Big actors in the transport business play a key role in leading the industry’s efforts to lower its carbon footprint. Therefore, I’m glad that Amazon is working with us to help reduce their emissions in longer and heavier transport assignments,” said Jessica Sandström, Senior Vice President of Product Management at Volvo Trucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volvo Trucks started the series production of heavy-duty electric trucks in September this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Globally we now have six electric truck models ready to order and in series production to meet the increasing demand for decarbonising goods transports. This is an encouraging step forward for reducing climate change impacts,” Sandström said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The electric versions of its most important product range — the heavy-duty Volvo FH, Volvo FM and Volvo FMX trucks — will play a vital role in reaching Volvo Trucks’ global target that by 2030 half of all new trucks sold will be battery or fuel cell electric. These electric heavy-duty trucks can operate at a total weight of 44 tonnes and the three models mentioned represent around two-thirds of the company’s sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon will use the trucks to replace its diesel counterparts, with the new fleet playing a key role in electrification initiatives through the company’s transportation chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Amazon is committed to decarbonising its fleet, and the middle mile has been a notoriously hard-to-abate sector,” said Andreas Marschner, Vice President Transportation Services Europe at Amazon. “That’s why welcoming these electric heavy goods vehicles from Volvo into our fleet is such a critical milestone. We’re operating one of the fastest-growing commercial transportation electrification programs, and we’ll continue to invest and innovate to decarbonise and deliver packages to customers with zero emissions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Volvo FH Electric has a battery capacity of 540 kWh, with 490 kW of continuous output power. Its range is up to 300 km, but it can cover up to 500 km during a normal workday if a top-up charge is added, eg, during a lunch break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other vehicles in Volvo’s electric truck range include the Volvo FL and FE Electric, manufactured in Europe from 2019 for city distribution and refuse handling, and the Volvo VNR Electric for North America, which began production in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Reference&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1. Bundesministerium für Umwelt und Verkehr, &lt;a href="https://www.bmuv.de/fileadmin/Daten_BMU/Pools/Broschueren/klimaschutz_zahlen_2021_bf.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Klimaschutz in Zahlen — Fakten, Trends und Impulse deutscher Klimapolitik, Ausgabe 2021 (bmuv.de)&lt;/a&gt;, Page 36&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image caption: The Volvo FH Electric. Image courtesy of Volvo.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/amazon-to-deploy-heavy-duty-electric-trucks-1135523125</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/amazon-to-deploy-heavy-duty-electric-trucks-1135523125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Moke returns: now all-electric</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71329/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mokeinternational.com/" target="_blank"&gt;MOKE International&lt;/a&gt; is returning the Moke Californian to America after 40 years with the more powerful and highway-legal Electric MOKE Californian — a zero-emissions re-imagining of the original 1964 Mini Moke. MOKE International owns the original 1964 British Motor Corporation Moke trademarks and is recognised in over 100 jurisdictions as the owner of the Moke brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Electric MOKE Californian is handcrafted in the United Kingdom to the same specifications and standards as the Electric MOKE that recently went on sale in Europe, but its name is a US market-specific tribute to the 1977 Moke Californian — an upgraded version of the Mini Moke that was sold in America and ceased production in 1982.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company says this is the first time a genuine version of the original Mini Moke has gone on sale in the US in more than four decades, and the first time a highway-legal version of the original Mini Moke has been available in America, with a top speed of 50 mph (80 kph). Fully charged, the Electric MOKE Californian offers a range of 80 miles (120 km) — enough to cruise Route 101 down to Malibu Beach from Santa Barbara. A full charge takes four hours on a US Type 1 charger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a momentous time for MOKE International,” said Isobel Dando, CEO MOKE International. “It’s great to be able to offer the US market a genuine MOKE car for the first time in 40 years. The original Moke Californian represented an incredibly important chapter in the company’s rich history; we are proud that the MOKE lives on and can be enjoyed in the electric era.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mini Moke was born in the heartland of Britain’s automotive industry, created by the ‘father of the Mini’, Sir Alec Issigonis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With prototypes built by the British Motor Corporation in 1959, developed under the codename ‘The Buckboard’, the Mini Moke was originally intended to be a lightweight military vehicle that could be parachuted into warzones and help troops traverse rough ground quickly. Marketed domestically as a utility wagon for farmers and workers, it quickly found adherents across the globe, especially in the South of France and Australia, where its rugged nature and open-top design made it a popular beach shuttle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admirers including The Beatles, The Beach Boys and Brigitte Bardot — seen driving the Mini Moke in glamourous seaside locations like the French Riviera and the Caribbean — cemented its status as an icon of the Swinging Sixties. While there were many variants of the original Mini Moke made before production ceased in 1993, the Moke Californian represented a departure from the Mini Moke’s utilitarian look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still built in the UK, at a facility operated by Fablink Group in Northamptonshire, the new Electric MOKE Californian embodies the same ‘freedom and fresh air’ qualities as the original, MOKE International says — but now it will play a part in keeping some of the world’s most beautiful locations clean through zero-emissions technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image courtesy of MOKE International.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/mini-moke-returns-now-all-electric-1047205791</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/mini-moke-returns-now-all-electric-1047205791</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrician fined $4K following shock risk</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71292/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;An electrician has been fined $4000 after leaving several live cables exposed at a family home in East Perth, putting residents at risk of electric shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man, who holds electrical worker and electrical contractor licences, pleaded guilty at Perth Magistrates Court to breaching WA’s electricity licensing regulations by carrying out non-compliant work. He is not named because the court granted a spent conviction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to information presented in court by &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.wa.gov.au/building-and-energy" target="_blank"&gt;Building and Energy&lt;/a&gt;, the electrician was contracted in July 2020 to carry out electrical installation work in the bathroom and laundry. This included installing several 240 V cables, which were left hanging from the ceiling and walls for later connection to lights and socket outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A subsequent inspection revealed the cables were left energised at a potentially lethal voltage level, with the ‘live’ unterminated ends only covered in tape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a breach of the regulations, which require energised and accessible components to be left with adequate protection against direct contact with live parts, such as robust insulation and appropriate enclosures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WA’s Director of Energy Safety, Saj Abdoolakhan, said it was unacceptable for a licensed electrician to leave electrical equipment in a hazardous condition. “The work in this case presented a real electric shock risk to anyone who came into contact with the wiring, which was easily accessible in a residential property and in areas prone to dampness,” Abdoolakhan said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is incredibly fortunate that nobody was hurt. This case should remind all licensed electrical workers and contractors of their obligations to always ensure their work is left in a safe condition.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Ocskaymark&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/electrician-fined-4k-following-shock-risk-1397609542</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/electrician-fined-4k-following-shock-risk-1397609542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NECA welcomes crackdown on 'solar cowboys'</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71213/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;The National Electrical and Communications Association (&lt;a href="https://www.neca.asn.au/" target="_blank"&gt;NECA&lt;/a&gt;) has welcomed SafeWork NSW’s announcement that rooftop solar installers in NSW can expect a visit from inspectors as part of a six-month operation to ensure safe work practices are being undertaken within the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SafeWork NSW Executive Director Compliance &amp;amp; Dispute Resolution Matthew Press said, “Solar retailers and installers have responsibilities under work health and safety laws to ensure workers are not at risk of falls from heights or contact with electricity, the two biggest safety risks the industry faces.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NECA Technical Director Paul Brownlee said, “Net zero energy targets must come with zero safety issues. Solar installation is a lucrative business. But, while most electricians are completing high-quality, safe installations, dodgy installers continue to plague our industry, damaging the reputation of hardworking sparkies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is not good enough, and the cowboys must be weeded out. Not only are unsafe installers putting their own lives at risk, but they’re also risking public lives by making homes potential fire traps or, even worse, death traps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dodgy solar installers should experience more heat than just that from the sun, so it’s pleasing to hear that SafeWork NSW and NSW Fair Trading are clamping down on those doing the wrong thing. The SafeWork NSW website has some great &lt;a href="https://www.safework.nsw.gov.au/hazards-a-z/solar-panel-installations" target="_blank"&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; regarding safe solar panel installations, and if you are still unsure, please reach out to NECA on 1300 361 099.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SafeWork NSW reported that of the 286 inspections completed last year, 69% of sites were only using harnesses or did not have fall protection at all. Of the sites using harnesses, 32% did not have appropriate anchor points in place and 50% were not clipped on to anything. A further 26% of sites did not have their ladder fixed at the top, nor did the ladder extend one metre past the landing space. 27% of sites did not place a lock on the main electrical switch or the meter box and 14% did not adequately address the risk of overhead powerlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The announcement follows &lt;a href="https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/electricians-disqualified-from-nsw-building-industry-486948552" target="_blank"&gt;recent news&lt;/a&gt; that NSW Fair Trading has revoked the contractor licences of seven electricians after they were found to have signed and submitted compliance certificates (CCEWs) for solar panel installations despite not having carried out, supervised or inspected the installations themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NSW Fair Trading Commissioner Natasha Mann stated that NSW Fair Trading would not hesitate to act against any electrical contractors trying to cut corners and bend the rules. “In light of the fact that electric shocks are the second-biggest cause of death in the New South Wales construction industry, we also want to ensure solar installation work sites are safe places. It is the solar panel installers, those properly certifying the work, who are responsible for ensuring the safety of those on premises and ensuring safe work methods are in place,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Felbaba Volodymyr&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/neca-welcomes-crackdown-on-solar-cowboys--665845214</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/neca-welcomes-crackdown-on-solar-cowboys--665845214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$3m in energy funding for Qld community groups</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71193/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Community groups in Queensland are being offered a significant financial incentive to participate in the state’s renewable energy transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environment Minister Meaghan Scanlon has announced that $3 million will be on offer for community-based organisations to help them install batteries, solar panels and other energy-efficient systems that will also enable them reduce their power bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Palaszczuk government has announced the most ambitious action on climate change and renewables in our state’s history, and Queensland community groups are eager to do their bit too,” Scanlon said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Queensland’s $62 billion energy and jobs plan will see emissions from energy cut by 90% by 2035. More than 700,000 households and small businesses have installed rooftop solar, and now the cornerstones of our communities can take part in the action.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scanlon’s announcement follows the government’s recent awarding of funding for renewables and energy-efficient devices to close to 40 community groups across the state. These included the Cairns BMX Club, which received $30,000 to purchase and install solar panels and a battery at its clubhouse, and Communify Queensland Ltd, which received $35,400 to replace light fixtures in the Newmarket community space and to purchase a new energy-efficient freezer and heat pump to reduce energy costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our community groups do such great work with the services they provide, and through this funding they’ll be able to install renewable energy systems such as solar panels or small-scale wind generators, purchase energy-efficient hot water systems or whitegoods, or replace lighting with energy-efficient alternatives,” Scanlon said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funding will open soon, with details on how to apply to be published on the Department of Environment and Science (DES) &lt;a href="https://www.des.qld.gov.au/" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on how the Queensland Government is investing in renewables and climate action, visit &lt;a href="https://www.des.qld.gov.au/climateaction" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.des.qld.gov.au/climateaction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Eddisonphotos&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/-3m-in-energy-funding-for-qld-community-groups-553397994</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/news/-3m-in-energy-funding-for-qld-community-groups-553397994</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed rule change aims to avoid blackouts</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71202/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Electricity consumers would receive additional protection from future major supply disruptions under a proposed change to the National Electricity Rules recommended by the Australian Energy Market Commission (&lt;a href="https://www.aemc.gov.au/" target="_blank"&gt;AEMC&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change is set out in a Directions Paper for stakeholder consultation, following a Rule change request by Alinta Energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent analysis conducted by the AEMC’s expert Reliability Panel shows that rising global fuel prices are disrupting the operation of Australia’s power generation fleet during emergencies, threatening the safe, stable and secure operation of the electricity system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analysis follows concerns raised about the level of the Administered Price Cap (APC) and whether it was high enough to manage recent extreme market volatility, which led to the suspension of the National Electricity Market (NEM) in June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the June energy crisis, a number of states faced major electricity shortfalls. It was caused by a ‘perfect storm’ of colder than average winter weather conditions that raised electricity demand; high global fuel prices; scheduled generator maintenance and unplanned outages; and low renewable power output from wind generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of the crisis, AEMO needed to issue close to 500 directions to generators to ensure security of supply and avoid widespread load shedding or, in the most extreme circumstances, blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After examining these issues, the AEMC is proposing an increase in the level of the APC from $300/MWh to $600/MWh, which should cover the short-run marginal costs of most generators in a range of credible scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The APC has only been applied three times in the 24 years since the NEM commenced, underscoring its purpose as a last-resort safety net during times of extreme and unpredictable market volatility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AEMC also considers the increased APC will reduce reliance on the compensation process to a limited number of generators required to operate during emergency situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The higher APC will also improve incentives for storage to play a part in emergency situations, further supporting the transition to net zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AEMC Chair Anna Collyer said, “To protect consumers from extreme market conditions in the future we have decided to propose a prudent change to the market settings, to increase the APC to a level that will reduce the risk of costly and damaging blackouts, more effectively secure our electricity supply and keep the system stable as we transition to more renewable energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The APC is a last-resort safety net that stabilises the electricity system by capping wholesale electricity prices during rare emergency situations. The APC has not been updated in 14 years and it is no longer at a level where it provides the right incentives to facilitate more supply in emergency situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If this change had applied in June, it would have unlocked significantly more electricity generation — enough to power more than 2 million homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Importantly, this change would have no impact on wholesale prices during normal market conditions, but it would have a substantial benefit in protecting us from damaging blackouts and securing our reliable electricity supply during emergencies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy Consumers Australia (ECA) CEO Lynne Gallagher said, “We are supporting this proposal because it provides important protections for consumers from price and supply shocks from volatile market conditions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposed increase in the APC would apply until no later than 1 July 2025, after which the APC level would revert to longer-term settings that have been recommended by the expert Reliability Panel and will be considered by the AEMC through the normal rule-change process. Submissions on the AEMC’s Direction Paper will close on Thursday, 13 October 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href="https://www.aemc.gov.au/rule-changes/amending-administered-price-cap" target="_blank"&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt; for more information and contact details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Evgen_Prozhyrko&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/proposed-rule-change-aims-to-avoid-blackouts-1190311398</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/business-and-management/news/proposed-rule-change-aims-to-avoid-blackouts-1190311398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earthquake impact measured "building by building"</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71208/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure sensing and monitoring company &lt;a href="https://fibersense.com/" target="_blank"&gt;FiberSense&lt;/a&gt; has shared striking high-resolution results in its detection of the magnitude 5.8 Cook Strait earthquake that occurred 70 km northwest of Wellington, New Zealand, on 22 September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Founder and CEO of FiberSense, Mark Englund, said, “Our DigitalSeismic sensing service that we have operating on fibre-optic telecoms cables in Wellington detected a range of activity from the earthquake centred on the Cook Strait [on 22 September]. We cross-referenced our measurements with the records of the official earthquake sensors and the results were remarkable — for the first time ever we’ve calibrated the impact of quakes down to a building-by-building analysis level.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers working to understand the impact, scale and dangers that earthquakes have on communities have, to date, been informed by the data collected by individual seismic readers scattered around the globe. In the quake-prone islands of New Zealand, this can mean just a few dozen seismic meters, often hundreds of kilometres apart, are relied on to capture data for the whole country. They measure not just the onset and duration of ground motion, but also critically important information like the maximum ground acceleration and directionality of shaking. Taken together, this data informs the public sector’s responses to natural disasters and underpins preparations to proceed with a plan of action when the inevitable next event occurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, FiberSense said the current quality of earthquake data will be “turbocharged” by using information detected across the ubiquitous fibre-optic cables that link up cities, connect communities and traverse the globe. The FiberSense team has invented and patented a new class of sensor system over optical fibre cable infrastructure called Vibration Detection and Ranging (VID+R). This technology acts as a series of ‘virtual seismic sensors’ set every few metres along a fibre cable. These distributed sensors can then detect the force and speed of the earthquake as the damaging waves move through city blocks and even individual buildings. This detailed information about the event is available in the moments immediately after the earthquake strikes as the data is aggregated automatically in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Immediately after the earthquake ... we first confirmed that the main data points from the official readings like magnitude and wave movement across ground closely matched with our readings. This established that our fibre-optic-based quake detection is as reliable as current methods that depend on monitoring stations scattered across New Zealand. The most compelling finding is that because the fibre-based method constantly records the activity as the event wave moves across the earth, our DigitalSeismic service captured the peak ground acceleration with around 1000x greater fidelity compared to what conventional seismic networks achieved,” Englund said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;a href="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/487055/web_image_article/image006.jpg" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/487055/web_image_article/image006.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fibre-optic telecoms cables are the hidden web of communication within a city,” said FiberSense VP of Research &amp;amp; Development Dr Nate Lindsey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“FiberSense’s DigitalSeismic service uses this web to take the pulse of a city, block by block, building by building. When an earthquake strikes, we use advances in distributed sensing to make measurements of how much the ground shook at positions every few metres along the optical fibre, improving on the traditional seismometers which are separated by kilometres, at best. A further key benefit from our approach is that DigitalSeismic concentrates ground-shaking information where it matters most — in and around the populated areas where the fibre is commonly located. This contrasts with conventional seismic networks which have traditionally been located far from noisy city activity. Targeting populated areas adds important data-driven insight right where people are most impacted, making DigitalSeismic technology a real game changer for how we respond to seismic hazards,” Lindsey said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe this capability will be an invaluable tool for first responders, utilities, critical infrastructure owners and seismologists, as well as government authorities in assessing the damage from earthquakes,” Englund added. “Whilst we can’t prevent natural disasters occurring, we can inform the way we plan for and respond to these inevitable events. It is critical that the quality of the data we base our recovery plans on should be as complete and well informed as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FiberSense is engaged with seismologists at Victoria University of Wellington and the University of Auckland through a grant from &lt;a href="https://www.eqc.govt.nz/" target="_blank"&gt;Earthquake Commission&lt;/a&gt; (EQC) to study the earthquake recordings that FiberSense is supplying to the community. Through this science partnership, the company said it hoped to build a bridge to new opportunities in earthquake early warning and seismic hazard analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image credit: iStock.com/Adrian Wojcik&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/news/earthquake-impact-measured-building-by-building--1295757379</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/data-networking-communications/news/earthquake-impact-measured-building-by-building--1295757379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing renewables on a large scale</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71189/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Europe’s plans, &lt;a href="https://www.dw.com/en/von-der-leyen-we-must-diversify-both-our-suppliers-and-our-energy-sources/av-60840910" target="_blank"&gt;as outlined by von der Leyen&lt;/a&gt;, will include procuring liquefied natural gas (LNG) from alternative “reliable suppliers”, plus a drive towards renewable energy sources and hydrogen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternative energy sources like wind, wave, marine, hydro, biomass and solar are becoming more widely used. According to the &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/" target="_blank"&gt;International Energy Agency&lt;/a&gt; (IEA), 29% of electricity generated in 2020 was from renewable sources, a 2% increase on the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This highlights that grid operators and managers must be prepared for a further rise in renewables. But, although renewable energy is beneficial for the environment, it poses unique energy management challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;More sources, more problems&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the low or medium voltages used to run renewable sources like wind and solar, they can be unpredictable. Because these energy sources depend on the sun shining periodically, or the presence of wind, they feed energy to the grid more intermittently. This can lead to disruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventional remote monitoring systems are based on a standard template, making it harder for them to analyse fluctuating data. Any alterations to these operating systems or drives are not only time-consuming but can also fall behind the demands of renewable sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address these unique challenges, remote monitoring systems must therefore be reliable and flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Chain of cables&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/486210/web_image_article/OVA230-Image-two.jpg" style="display: block; height: 244px; margin: auto; width: 400px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Remote telemetry units (RTUs) collect and manage data, making it available to other systems for processing and analysing, including on tablets and smartphones. Image credit: Ovarro&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RTUs offer an effective hardware solution. They have been used in energy grids for years to capture, store and analyse data collected from physical assets in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, Distrigas, the leading gas provider in Belgium, &lt;a href="https://ovarro.com/en/middle-east/case-studies/tbox-helps-automate-gas-distribution-metering/" target="_blank"&gt;uses Ovarro’s TBox LT2 RTUs&lt;/a&gt; to provide important data on gas volumes at 550 outstations throughout its network. Each TBox connects to the existing meter, to a turbine, and a pressure and temperature transducer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RTUs will also be invaluable in smart grids. Smart grids rely on data collected by monitoring equipment to predict problems or identify them quickly before they become more severe. Effective use of RTUs can also help grid operators take preventive or remedial action against these incidents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An electricity grid functions like a chain of cables, where a failure in one link can render the entire chain ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure reliable running and improve security, Ovarro offers remote monitoring and supervisory control and data acquisition (SCADA) systems designed for distribution grids, such as the &lt;a href="https://ovarro.com/en/europe/solutions/monitoring--control-devices/rtus/datawatt/dsg-series/" target="_blank"&gt;Datawatt Smart Grid (DSG) series&lt;/a&gt; for the water, energy and industrial markets. The DSG series is flexible, with a range of protocols that can be implemented in real time including IEC104, COAP and Modbus. Other protocols are available on request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="img-responsive" src="https://d2emomln4apc0h.cloudfront.net/assets/486208/web_image_article/OVA230-Image-three.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Ovarro’s Datawatt Smart Grid (DSG) series of RTUs can help monitor unpredictable low-voltage renewable energy sources.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Go deep into renewables&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DSG RTUs collect and manage data, before making it available to other systems for analysis. Ovarro can also assemble bespoke cabinets with a combination of its own products and third-party hardware. This offers a complete and easy-to-install solution, and an improvement over traditional systems that are difficult to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to data makes grids smart. Therefore, RTUs and SCADA systems are essential for effective modern smart grids, to collect and analyse the large amounts of process data needed for improved decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the EU comes to rely more heavily on renewable energy sources, optimised distribution management will become essential. Automation offers one solution — with RTUs like the DSG series being able to collect, interpret and act on data produced by low- and medium-voltage renewable energy sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These technologies can support the EU on its journey to net zero and help Europe, in the words of von der Leyen, “go deep into the renewables”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Top image credit: iStock.com/aydinmutlu&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/article/managing-renewables-on-a-large-scale-958554489</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/article/managing-renewables-on-a-large-scale-958554489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILME RKAX range of HNM connectors</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71138/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Treotham is expanding the market for rectangular connectors with the new ILME RKAX size ‘21.21’ metal housings (bulkhead and surface mounted) and hoods with a CLASS single locking lever. The new connectors come together with a wide range of connector inserts for 5, 10, 16 and 40 A, as well as the redesigned RQF/M 05, with integrated HNM (high number of mating cycles) screw-type PE terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treotham’s new combined connectors, RXC 4/2 and RXC 4/8, extend from 500 to 10,000 mating cycles thanks to the HNM treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new RX7M2D P series of 70 A crimp contacts is now expanded by adding a variant of male contacts with an insulating cap on their tip. This determines the finger-proof safety feature (IPXXB or IP20 in combination with the MIXO CX 02 7M module).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ILME HNM range is a good solution for applications with frequent disconnection use, such as test benches, charging systems or removable tooling equipment activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/microsite-product/ilme-rkax-range-of-hnm-connectors-1207484663</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/electrical-distribution/microsite-product/ilme-rkax-range-of-hnm-connectors-1207484663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Sydney battery facility could transform industry</title>
      <description>&lt;img class="img-responsive" style="display: block; margin: auto" src="https://d1v1e13ebw3o15.cloudfront..net/data/71047/pool_and_spa_logo/..jpg"&lt;p&gt;Global renewable energy storage company &lt;a href="https://gelion.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Gelion&lt;/a&gt; (founded in 2015 by Professor Thomas Maschmeyer as a spin-out from the University of Sydney) has commenced industrial production of its gel-based zinc bromide battery, with the launch of a manufacturing facility in Western Sydney capable of producing two megawatt hours of batteries annually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gelion’s non-lithium battery lasts for six to 12 hours, and will be critical, the company said, in replacing fossil fuel-produced energy on the grid by providing new storage options for a higher percentage of renewables. In the future, Gelion could scale its facilities to gigafactory level and create thousands of direct and indirect jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gelion partnered with &lt;a href="https://www.batteryenergy.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Battery Energy&lt;/a&gt; at its lead-acid manufacturing site in Fairfield to accelerate speed to market, with the battery designed to fit standard lead acid racks, and its manufacturing line utilising 70% of existing lead-acid battery processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scaling the Gelion manufacturing capacity will require many similar skills to those used in other legacy industrial processes, including coal-fired power stations, meaning Gelion could absorb, retrain and grow thousands of fossil fuel-reliant or otherwise diminishing jobs as Australia’s energy transition occurs. This marriage between established and new technology shows Australia could scale sovereign domestic manufacturing capacity extremely efficiently by leveraging existing processes and supply chains, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global battery market &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/en/news-release/2022/06/22/2466800/28124/en/Global-Battery-Market-Report-2022-Market-to-Reach-173-7-Billion-by-2026-China-Dominates-Li-ion-Battery-Production-US-and-Europe-Make-Efforts-to-Gain-Strong-Position.html?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_hsmi=227812459&amp;amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-9FfEVpu4OJa9EzjGx_s7P3nU1Dm0H2k2ToWjyvsp8qcHrb_A72V6NY6SSI_G0cE124DCmpLGVq_-YJ20EN8jN0hQPSSQ&amp;amp;utm_content=227812459&amp;amp;utm_source=hs_email" target="_blank"&gt;is expected to reach $265 billion by 2026&lt;/a&gt; but there are currently significant challenges with unsustainable, unreliable or risky global supply chains, including a dependence on finite rare-earth materials and a &lt;a href="https://www.afr.com/companies/mining/lithium-insider-sees-decade-long-shortage-20220925-p5bkrh" target="_blank"&gt;predicted global lithium shortage&lt;/a&gt;. Gelion’s gel-based zinc bromide battery has the potential to solve these issues by being more cost-effective, non-reliant on rare earths, sustainably produced, recyclable and safe in high temperatures, as well as providing long-duration storage with lower maintenance costs and being scalable on a predominantly Australian supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tests performed on the first batch of Gelion batteries have shown their performance meets customer requirements, and the batteries will be supplied to the &lt;a href="https://www.acciona.com/projects/sierra-brava-floating-photovoltaic-plant/?_adin=11551547647" target="_blank"&gt;Acciona Energia&lt;/a&gt; solar plant in Narrava, Spain, to potentially become part of Acciona’s supplier portfolio as a renewable energy storage provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gelion stated that the Acciona Energia deal was one of many in its pipeline, with the company in advanced discussions with multiple global customers in the energy, resources, mining, and oil and gas sectors for trials and offtakes. Gelion and Battery Energy are also experiencing significant interest from Australian customers and industry looking to decarbonise and improve energy security, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are delighted to be launching production of our breakthrough battery, proving it can be produced at scale with existing lead-acid battery manufacturing processes,” Hannah McCaughey, CEO of Gelion, said. “Our game-changing technology will now be deployed to Acciona to support its development of renewable battery systems. This milestone is a significant step forward in Gelion’s growth strategy and also strengthens our position in the rapidly expanding energy storage market.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Western Sydney facility officially launched on 30 September 2022 at a ceremony attended by Chris Bowen, Federal Minister for Climate Change and Energy, and Ed Husic, Federal Minister for Industry and Science. Husic will play a key role in implementing Australia’s first &lt;a href="https://www.alp.org.au/policies/australian-made-batteries" target="_blank"&gt;National Battery Strategy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bowen said, “This is a great day for Gelion, starting the first industrial production line for their new Endure Battery, right here in Fairfield, the industrial heartland of Sydney. This is what Australian innovation is all about: cutting-edge technology and new manufacturing opportunities, which means more well-paying local jobs and upskilling in the workforce.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s fantastic to see Australian scientific know-how turned into battery manufacturing capability right here in Western Sydney,” Husic said. “Through the National Battery Strategy, the Albanese government wants to see the creation of a thriving energy storage industry supporting renewable technologies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h9&gt;Image caption: Chris Bowen and Ed Husic with Professor Thomas Maschmeyer and Gelion CEO Hannah McCaughey at the launch of the new facility. Image courtesy of Gelion.&lt;/h9&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/article/new-sydney-battery-facility-could-transform-industry-747983292</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ecdonline.com.au/content/efficiency-renewables/article/new-sydney-battery-facility-could-transform-industry-747983292</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
